Chapter 597: Drifting Cloud Sect

Seeing that Han Li remained silent, Fairy Violet Spirit smiled and asked, “Brother Han, how do you feel about marrying her? Little Sister Mei Ning’s beautiful appearance should more than qualify her enough to become your concubine. Surely you wouldn’t refuse such a pleasant matter that has come knocking on your door?”

Han Li unconsciously frowned and turned to look at the charming, bright appearance of Mei Ning.

Mei Ning held her head low and a faint blush was revealed from her snow-white neck, making for a rather touching scene. It seemed she had tacitly agreed with Violet Spirit’s proposal.

Han Li slowly spoke with a calm expression, “Based on her appearances alone, she wouldn’t qualify as a mere concubine of a high grade cultivator; even being a Dao companion wouldn’t be out of the question. However, I am different from common cultivators. I have dedicated myself to the pursuit of immortality and cannot easily involve myself with the affairs of men and women. Furthermore, I am a lone wanderer and often encounter perilous situations. How could I possibly take in a concubine? If Fellow Daoist Mei were to follow me, it wouldn’t be a good thing for her at all; it would only lead her down a path of unprecedented hardship!”

Mei Ning’s body faintly trembled upon hearing him and her blush hastily faded away. She only raised her head to reveal a paled face.

As if greatly discontent with Han Li’s refusal of the beautiful woman, Violet Spirit annoyedly said, “But in the end, Brother Han is still rejecting her. Needless to say, with your late Core Formation cultivation, who could possibly pose a threat to you apart from Nascent Soul eccentrics? Perhaps Fellow Daoist may soon succeed in condensing a Nascent Soul. After that, the entire world would be free to roam as you choose. How would you be unable to protect Little Sister Mei Ning?”

Han Li flatly said, “Fellow Daoist Violet Spirit should already be aware. Although I believe myself to be a level higher than similar grade cultivators, I’ve always provoked enmity from foes far stronger than I. Until I reach Nascent Soul stage and possess enough power to defend myself, I cannot possibly consider taking in a concubine. When the time comes that I am incapable of defending her, she will only face a bitter reality.”

Violet Spirit creased her brow, knowing that Han Li had spoken truthfully. Moreover, she faintly felt that Han Li was somewhat displeased. She could only sigh and avoid further mentioning the topic.

Mei Ning eventually recovered her calm and bit her lips while staring at Han Li and asking, “Since Brother Han didn’t reject this little woman based on her lacking appeal, would you be willing to accept me after you enter Nascent Soul stage?”

Han Li looked at the woman and calmly said, “Nascent Soul stage? I don’t have any certainty that I will be able to condense a Nascent Soul. Furthermore, even if I am able to reach the Nascent Soul stage, I have no idea about how many years it will take. Would Fellow Daoist Mei be willing to wait over a hundred years for an uncertain chance that I would able to condense a Nascent Soul?”

“I...” When Mei Ning heard this, her expression grew unclear and she was incapable of responding. As a Foundation Establishment cultivator, even thirty years was too long, let alone a hundred. Although Han Li made for a very good choice for pair cultivation, she didn’t have the time to wait for an uncertain result.

After all, the cultivation world was a truly cruel place. Although she had only spent a short amount of time together with Han Li and had a favorable impression of him, it was impossible for her to have fallen so completely in love with him that she’d ignore the consequences.

Seeing her hesitation, Han Li could only inwardly sigh and placed two bottles onto the table before pushing them towards her.

Han Li unhurriedly said, “These are a few cultivation progression pills that I concocted from demon cores. Instead of seeking a man to pair cultivate with, it may be better to diligently cultivate by yourself. Perhaps you’ll even form a golden core like Fellow Daoist Violet Spirit.”

Since these medicine pills were for Foundation Establishment cultivators, they no longer had any value to Han Li, but since the woman had passed on her Transient Spirit Qi to him, he may as well use this opportunity to repay the favor without much effort. As such, he would no longer need to dwell on the matter.

“Medicine pills concocted from demon cores?” Mei Ning appeared moved and unconsciously reached for one. After opening the bottle’s lid, a fragrant odor instantly filled the room. “These are top grade medicine pills!”

Mei Ning then stared at Han Li in confusion. She was at a complete loss for words. Han Li had treated her with such amorous disregard in the Umbra Realm, but he then refused to take her in as a concubine. Even more baffling, he had then taken out precious medicine pills for her.

Fairy Violet Spirit glanced at the medicine pills with a trace of astonishment but she immediately chuckled, “Hehe! Brother Han is truly magnanimous. Since Fellow Daoist Han has said as much, Little Sister should accept them. Perhaps with a few more medicine pills, you will truly be able to enter Core Formation. If that were to occur, us sisters should join hands so that we may travel unfettered.”

Mei Ning glanced at Han Li with a complicated expression and whispered a word of thanks before taking the small medicine bottles into her storage pouch.

Han Li faintly smiled in response and turned towards the window, glancing down at the small city’s streets.

It was bustling with activity, reminding Han Li of a familiar scene that he had long forgotten. His smile then turned into a faint sigh.

Seeing that Han Li wore such an expression, Violet Spirit and Mei Ning couldn’t help but glance at each other in confusion.

...

The Nan Province was located in the western portion of the State of Xi. The land there was quite complicated, containing many hills and jungles with the occasional swamp miasma occasionally wandering the land. As a result, there were only a few main roads connecting the several villages in the area, and few ever tread into the wilderness. As for the mountain ranges, they were home to particularly vicious beasts, detering anyone from visiting them.

This had caused the area to be abundant with rare medicinal herbs and beasts, much to the joy of the country’s cultivators. This had led to a majority of the country’s cultivators to be located in this province. A few of the more powerful cultivator sects even monopolized a few of the areas with the more abundant Spiritual Qi.

As for the mountain range in the province known as the Dreamcloud Mountains, it was an area famed in the Heavenly South for its sacred spirit veins. In the profound spirit veins of the mountain grew the legendary Spirit Well Tree, the final type of the three divine woods.

The local powers held this tree in even greater esteem than the Heaven Lightning Bamboo and Soul Nurturing Wood because of a spirit milk that was produced by the tree every two hundred years known as “wine nectar”. Although the liquid couldn’t be directly used, it could be refined into many types of exceptionally powerful spiritual medicines. Among these was a legendary sacred medicine known as the Spirit Tempering Pill.

The Spirit Tempering Pill was also known as the Soul Pacifying Pill. Not only could it increase one’s cultivation a certain amount, it could also harden one’s heart and calm one’s soul, alleviating a cultivator of any inner demons that may haunt them.

Condensing a Nascent Soul was quite unlike forming a core. Apart from requiring a certain degree of luck and depth of cultivation, condensing a Nascent Soul also subjected oneself to the disturbances of illusions and inner demons. After all, transforming one’s core into a Nascent Soul was a fearsome test of mental endurance and willpower.

The heaven-defying treasure of the Dreamcloud Mountains’ spirit veins with the addition of the extraordinary concentration of spiritual Qi that it contained had attracted countless sects with the desire to establish their base their. As a result of endless battles and subterfuge, the territory was currently being held by an alliance of three sects: The Ancient Sword Sect, the Drifting Cloud Sect, and the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion.

With the three strongest forces in the State of Xi combining power, other sects could only extinguish any hopes of seizing the spirit veins and watch helplessly.

Sitting down on the steps of one of the peaks of the Dreamcloud Mountains, Han Li was pondering over information that had to do with the mountains and was examining the nearby environment.

There were a few young men and women silently walking on the mountain paths, each with an expression of excitement. When Han Li saw this, he faintly smiled. As the great Drifting Cloud Sect was about to recruit a new batch of new disciples in the coming days, these Qi Condensation youths were brimming with anticipation.

Having spent half a month in this place, it was only natural that he knew of this. Their famed pill concoction technique was one of various reasons he chose to infiltrate the sect. However, he wasn’t going to enter as a Core Formation cultivator, but an ordinary Qi Condensation cultivator.

Unless a mid Nascent Soul cultivator were to closely examine him, none would be able to see through the miraculous effects of the nameless Qi restraining incantation. It was only because of this that he dared to follow through with his plan.

When he suddenly recalled what happened before he had parted with Violet Spirit and Mei Ning, he bitterly chuckled.

According to his original plans, he had found a place to establish a cave residence and consumed a few medicine pills in order to reach the peak of Core Formation stage. While the Transient Spirit Qi had progressed his cultivation somewhat, it wasn’t enough to genuinely advance him into False Nascent Stage.

However, something unexpected occurred that had completely overturned his plans.

When he took a medicine pill, he astonishedly discovered that the medicine pill had completely lost effect for him. Regardless of whether it was the grade six demon beast pills or the grade seven demon beasts, they all had no effect on him. He was left at a complete loss.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

ED: Barbant

Chapter 599: Entering the Sect (1)

Of the three sects controlling the sacred spirit veins, the most optimal choice for Han Li wasn’t the Drifting Cloud Sect but the Hundred Possibilities Sect that was well known for its tool refinement.

In addition to his original goals of finding a cultivation area, the Hundred Possibilities Sect disciples were particularly adept at refining all sorts of magic tools. Rumor has it that the sect even possessed refinement methods for peak grade magic treasures.

These treasures caused Han Li’s heart to stir. However, it was a pity that the sect recruited disciples in the same manner as the State of Yue’s Seven Sects used to: they prioritized recruitment from cultivation clans and only rarely accepted outsiders as disciples.

Furthermore, a union of the five most powerful cultivator clans within the sect had monopolized the sect’s allocated section of the Dreamcloud Mountain’s spirit veins in the west. Both of these factors had caused Han Li to relinquish any thoughts of joining this sect with slight regret.

As for the Ancient Sword Sect, as its name implies, it is extremely adept at sword controlling techniques. All of their magic tools and magic treasures were various types of differently sized swords. As for the sect protecting arts, the True Absolute Sword Arts, it was incredibly incisive and was widely known throughout the country.

The Ancient Sword Sect didn’t exclusively take in disciples from cultivator clans, it also took in young vagrant cultivators. However, the sect required one to be extremely suited to their sword arts. If one’s aptitude didn’t match the sect’s cultivation techniques, they weren’t taken in. This was why they had the fewest disciples of the three sects despite how often they were recruiting.

On the other hand, by relying on their domineering attacks, the disciples of the Ancient Sword Sect prevailed over opponents of similar cultivation, leading the sect to be the most powerful of the three. As a matter of course, they held the main spirit vein of Dreamcloud Mountain.

The final sect was the Drifting Cloud Sect. Instead of being renowned for its weapon refinement like the Hundred Possibilities Sect, the Drifting Cloud Sect was famed for its pill concoction.

The legendary Spirit Tempering Pill was something that only a few of the sect’s elders were capable of concocting. So despite the sect’s inferior strength in comparison to the other two, it managed to acquire the east portion of the mountain’s spirit vein. Additionally, the Drifting Cloud Sect recruited the most disciples and possessed the least demanding requirements.

On a whole, the sect only had two conditions for accepting disciples: Primarily, it required that that one possessed decent spiritual roots and a capacity to be nurtured. Lacking that, they were also more than willing to accept any disciples that had poor aptitudes so long as their cultivation had already reached a high enough layer.

After all, the Drifting Cloud Sect pursued a disorganized assortment of various disciplines outside of its renowned pill concoction technique. These fledgling disciplines required large quantities of low level cultivators in order to progress.

As for vagrant Qi Condensation cultivators with poor aptitudes, they clearly understood that they had no future prospects after joining the sect and would eternally be low grade disciples. Regardless, they joined with thoughts similar to Han Li’s; It was quite convenient to take shelter in the great power of the Drifting Cloud Sect. It was for this reason that vagrant cultivators flocked to the sect in large numbers.

With the lax acceptance policies and the enticement of the legendary Spirit Tempering Pill, the sect seemed to be the optimal choice for Han Li to infiltrate.

With some lingering uncertainty, Han Li made a few additional inquiries and learned that the sect would soon be taking in more disciples, immediately dispelling any of his reservations. Without revealing any of his plans, he immediately took off and parted with the two women after making a few preparations.

As recruitment day drew near, many Qi Condensation cultivators began to gather on the road. When Han Li saw this from the top of his mountain, he calmly joined them.

On his walk along the path, he unhurriedly walked for about two hours without reaching the end. This wasn’t because the mountain was large but because the stone roads were being affected by a few shallow illusion techniques. They probably wished to use this to grind down the number of cultivators that wished to enter the sect.

Given the lax entrance conditions of the Drifting Cloud Sect, they may as well cull the cultivators that were too impatient to walk along the path.

The several cultivators that walked in front of Han Li had discovered something amiss, and immediately gathered together and started whispering to each other. They seemed to have guessed what was going on and continued to walk forward without hesitation.

The group of cultivators seemed to be acquaintances. Despite having been ignored, Han Li continued on his way without paying them any heed.

After yet another hour walking along the stone path, they eventually reached some blue stairs. The group of cultivators happily quickened their pace as they climbed up the stairs. Still indifferent, Han Li calmy climbed the steps and examined the scene at the top.

There was a huge, pure white platform that was over four hundred meters wide, and the only other structure present was a small unremarkable pavilion on the other side. There were several tens of different groups of variously clothed cultivators around it, but no one dared to step inside the pavilion. As for Han Li and the group in front of him, they wordlessly joined groups already there and sat down among them.

Han Li inwardly sneered at the scene in front of him. While Qi Condensation vagrant cultivators were unable to see anything, Han Li was able to see through the illusion formation with his spiritual sense.

The small stone pavilion before them was actually a huge white jade tower. A sign hung from the tower had three large golden words, “Illusory Cloud Hall”. Three people stood underneath the huge sign and were looking down at the unknowing Qi Condensation cultivators below, talking amongst themselves as they gestured.

They relied solely on the spell formation for concealment and made no other effort to hide themselves.

Of the three, two were early Foundation Establishment cultivators while one was a mid Foundation Establishment cultivator. It seemed the three of them were in charge of receiving the newcomers.

Han Li wordlessly walked amongst the nearby crowd and sat down at the edge with his head down. Although he closed his eyes, his spiritual sense completely enveloped the three Foundation Establishment cultivators and he easily eavesdropped on their conversation.

A pale faced youth that appeared to be in his late twenties pointed down at the crowd and spoke with a tone of dissatisfaction, “Senior Martial Brother Qiu! Although the deadline hasn’t yet been reached, there aren’t many vagrant cultivators that have caught our eye. Most of the cultivators here wouldn’t even pass the qualifications, and are clearly only at the seventh layer of Qi Condensation. Do they think that the Drifting Cloud Sect takes everyone?”

“There is nothing we can do. Three years ago, our sect accepted a large batch of disciples because they were suitable. And because Senior Martial Uncle Jin was short on manpower, there was an exception made to accept two eighth layer Qi Condensation cultivators at the time. This produced a misconception that it is easier to enter our sect, which is why there are so many vagrant cultivators that have come to try their luck.” The man called Senior Martial Brother Qiu was a white-robed mid Foundation Establishment cultivator in his forties with a stern, squarish face and bright eyes.

A vigorous youth with a heroic air chuckled and added, “Of course, we aren’t going to be so lenient this time around. After all, the recently accepted low grade disciples have been on the shoddier side with regards to their spiritual roots and cultivation. It seems an elder took notice of this and has already warned the sect master. As such, we will follow the sect master's word to accept nothing but quality.”

The pale-faced youth glanced down at the vagrant cultivators and disdainfully said, “Accept nothing but quality! If that’s the case, then it would be fine if we choose ten disciples and have the rest of them leave.”

Senior Martial Brother Qiu glanced at the pale-faced youth and calmly said, “Junior Martial Brother Liu shouldn’t underestimate these vagrant cultivators. There may truly be a few unfounded geniuses among them. Junior Martial Brother Sun Huo was once a vagrant cultivator too, but he managed to reach Foundation Establishment with a mere five years of hard work. Although he was given a suitable cultivation technique and a Foundation Establishment Pill for his quickly acquired merits, this can also be considered part of his aptitude.”

When the pale-faced youth heard him, he quickly thought of something and dryly coughed. He then quickly smiled as if he felt some fear towards Senior Martial Brother Qiu and said, “Senior Martial Brother is correct. I’ve spoken wrongly!”

Senior Martial Brother Qiu was about to say more to the youth, but Han Li wasn’t interested, so he recalled his spiritual sense and began to meditate.

As of current, he had restrained his Qi to the point where other cultivators only perceived him to be a tenth layer Qi Condensation cultivator. He should have no trouble entering the sect!

About half a day later, there were many more cultivators in the crowd that had climbed up the stone steps. By the time the sun set, there were nearly a hundred Qi Condensation cultivators sitting on the stage. A majority of the cultivators there were youths, but there was also a middle-aged man with a particularly profound cultivation.

At that moment, an expanse of red light suddenly burst forth from the stone pavilion and it disappeared to reveal a hundred meter tall tower along with the three silhouettes standing above.

Senior Martial Brother Qiu swept his gaze across the crowd with a stern expression and calmly said, “We welcome all of you Fellow Daoists to our Drifting Cloud Sect. My Martial Brothers and I will be in charge of evaluating you disciples. I hope you Fellow Daoists will clearly listen to what I will say next. Don’t miss it.”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 600: Entering the Sect (2)

Upon seeing the sudden changes of their surroundings and hearing Senior Martial Brother Qiu's words, the cultivators on the platform were momentarily shocked and then hurriedly stood up, wearing respectful and attentive expressions. All of the cultivators there knew that if they were to enter the great Drifting Cloud Sect, they absolutely couldn't afford to leave a bad impression with the three men standing on the tower.

Senior Martial Brother Qiu revealed a satisfied expression upon seeing the vagrant cultivators being so tactful.

Senior Martial Brother Qiu slowly said with a solemn expression, "You Fellow Daoists should all know the criteria by which we accept disciples. That being the case, I won't go into detail. Let's have our Fellow Daoists who possess tri-attribute, dual-attribute, or special spiritual roots walk forward.”

The crowd stirred at this and after a short moment, only four people walked forward, three men and a woman.

Senior Martial Brother Qiu swept his gaze over those four and calmly said, “You four will follow Junior Martial Brother Liu who will be in charge of evaluating your cultivation aptitudes.”

At that moment, the pale faced youth stepped forward and wordlessly waved his arm. A white streak of light then flew out from his sleeve and circled in the air before turning into a huge embroidered scarf that gently floated about a meter off the ground.

The pale-faced youth appeared atop the scarf magic tool in a blur and expressionlessly said, "Climb on. I'll bring you four to another place and examine your aptitudes there. Those that are unsuitable will naturally be sent back."

When the four heard this, they glanced at each other with slight hesitation before climbing onto the scarf. The pale-faced youth then clutched his hands in an incantation gesture and caused the scarf to glow with white light before it set off through the sky in a streak of white light.

After sending off the pale-faced youth, Senior Martial Brother Qiu glanced down at those who remained and continued, "Those with cultivations at the tenth layer and higher, step forward and follow Junior Martial Brother Yu. So long as anyone doesn't have too much a problem with their identities, they will be able to enter the sect. As for you remaining Fellow Daoists, if you wish to enter the sect, then you are required to pass a test before you will be taken in. If you fail, I can only ask you all to diligently cultivate for several more years and come back once you've improved.” Once that was said, an uproar occurred amongst the crowd. Apart from a few peculiar individuals, a majority of them revealed a disappointed expression.

It seemed the standards of this selection would be far more strict and caused a few cultivators hoping for a fluke to grow greatly dispirited. Although he did say they could participate in a test to still join the sect, everyone knew that they were words spoken out of politeness.

After all, with the number of people present there would be no way for the Drifting Cloud Sect to give all of them a chance.

Needless to say, these tests would be extremely difficult to pass if one's cultivation was beneath the tenth layer. Only cultivators at the ninth layer of Qi condensation would have even the slightest chance of success. In the past, only a sparse few cultivators at the ninth layer were able to pass these tests.

Although those people all had poor aptitudes, they were able to succeed through a show of exceptional perseverance. As a result, despite their lacking future prospects, the Drifting Cloud Sect would be willing to accept them as they would be able to contribute towards their various fledgling disciplines.

Underneath the envious gazes of the rest of the crowd, Han Li and six other cultivators walked forward.

Senior Martial Brother Qiu swept his gaze across them and nodded his head.

When the valiant youth surnamed Yu saw this, he released a flying magic tool without any delay. A huge bronze alms bowl appeared before them.

Without needing any words from the youth, Han Li and the group of cultivators obediently climbed onto the magic tool. The copper alms bowl then flew off deep into the Dreamcloud Mountains in a streak of light.

As for the remaining vagrant cultivators that didn't qualify, Han Li was completely ignorant as to whether any of them would enter the sect, nor did he care enough to find out.

At that moment, he was absorbed in examining the six others that were enveloped in the alms bowl's yellow light alongside him. There were four men and two women. Apart from a refined yellow-clothed woman that appeared about twenty years old, the others all appeared to be in their thirties.

There was even a fifty year old cultivator. Although he possessed the deepest cultivation of the group at the twelfth layer of the Qi Condensation, Han Li could only shake his head and inwardly sigh.

If they didn't have much luck, cultivators with poor aptitudes had to spend an immense amount of time cultivating if they wished to reach the tenth layer or higher, resulting in Han Li and the yellow-clothed woman to have the youngest appearances in the group.

If it weren't for the mysterious bottle that Han Li had encountered, he feared he would've spent most of his life cultivating like the twelfth layer cultivator only to reach the sixth layer. Entering a large cultivation sect would've been out of the question.

When Han Li began to ponder about the past, he entered a rare state of absent-mindedness.

Soon after, he regained clarity of mind and looked at the others. While they didn't appear to be particularly notable, they had faces full of excitement.

But when Han Li's gaze fell onto large fully-bearded man, he narrowed his eyes for a moment, but soon his expression returned to normal.

This wasn't because of anything unusual about the man's appearance, but because there was a trace of indescribable cold Yin Qi in him. This Yin Qi was very well hidden and if it weren't for Han Li's extraordinary spiritual sense, he would've completely missed it This definitely wasn't a cultivation art that belonged to the five elements. From the fluctuations of his spiritual Qi, he clearly possessed some unusual magic techniques.

However, the large man's tenth layer cultivation wasn't even the slightest bit false, causing Han Li to ponder over it with great curiosity.

As Han Li was lost in thought, a huge expanse of endless fog appeared before the huge alms bowl. This white fog was extremely dense and roiled as sounds of thunder faintly echoed out.

Han Li's heart stirred and he sent out his spiritual sense. However, something blocked it when he attempted to reach about thirty meters into the mist.

Han Li inwardly trembled, knowing that the white mist was an uncommon restriction. It was likely one of the Drifting Cloud Sect's formidable sect protecting restrictions. He didn't dare to further rashly test it and hastily recalled his spiritual sense.

The group of vagrant cultivators all revealed an expression of awe when they saw the endless mist. Although they'd never come across a spell formation before, the astonishing restriction before them had greatly broadened their perspectives.

At that moment, the youth surnamed Yu formed a hand incantation and had his flying magic tool slowly come a stop. Then he grasped his storage pouch and took out an azure formation flag.

After muttering something, the flag in his hand began to glow with a piercing radiance that gradually grew.

"Open!" After the youth finished his incantation, he glared at the fog and pointed the formation flag at it. A bowl-thick azure beam of light shot out from the tip of the flag straight into the mist, leading to an astonishing scene.

The other areas of the fog roiled as before, but the portion of the fog in front of them became extremely calm. Then following a series of clear chimes, the white Qi parted before them, revealing a ten-meter-wide passage.

After this occured, the youth surnamed Yu carried the group through the passage without delay. In the blink of an eye, they disappeared from sight.

Not long after, the passage closed and waves of thunder sounded out once more.

After the time it took to finish a cup of tea, the group eventually passed through the mist and emerged before within a hidden land.

Before they could even clearly see past the fog, they felt dense spiritual Qi rush against them. Han Li couldn't help but take in a deep breath and feel a trace of joy well up inside him as he looked forward.

There was a huge expanse of earth with verdant greenery, fragrant aromas, birdsong, and several mountains that spanned over three kilometers tall reaching out as far as the eye could see. Surrounding these mountains were buildings of various sizes including palace halls and pavilions of countless number along with many variously clothed cultivators rushing about in a hurry.

After seeing their surprise and excitement, the youth surnamed Yu silently smiled. He then pointed to the nearest mountain peak and said, "Take a good look. These are the Six Marvelous Peaks of the Drifting Cloud Sect's monastery. If you truly enter our sect, this will be your home. But first, we will head to Dayspring Mountain's Initiation Residence. You'll explain a bit about your past and then we will test your cultivation."

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 601: Entering the Sect (3)

Han Li and the other Qi Condensation cultivators weren't surprised by the information regarding the tests, and were brought to Dayspring mountain by the valiant youth surnamed Yu.

They met many cultivators along the way with most of them being at Qi Condensation. When they saw their guide, they respectfully saluted him. It appeared the youth had quite the reputation in the Drifting Cloud Sect.

They only came across one other Foundation Establishment cultivator, a yellow-robed man with a thin face and sharp ears. He flew up from Dayspring Mountain, but when he caught sight of the youth surnamed Yu, he smiled and called out to him, "Junior Martial Brother Yu, are these six newly arrived disciples? It seems there weren't that many this time around!" While he acted quite familiar with the youth, the others were able to see that he held hidden motives.

The handsome youth unconsciously frowned upon seeing the yellow-robed cultivator. Regardless, he calmly replied, “So it turned out to be Senior Martial Brother Yan! These people still need to be examined with truth techniques and be introduced to the sect master before they become official disciples. They are still only candidates."

The yellow-robed cultivator chuckled and said, “So its like that. However, Junior Martial Brother should know that my talisman refinement division still needs disciples. Do you think you could send two of these cultivators to me?"

At that moment, his eyes focused on the group behind the young man.

Han Li's expression was calm, but he felt quite disgusted from the gaze. From the way he looked at them and the tone he used, he certainly wanted to work them to the bone.

When the other cultivators heard him, their expressions slightly changed. It seemed they also didn't have a favorable impression of him.

"Senior Martial Brother Yan, that is not something I can decide. You should know that the allocation of disciples is decided by the sect master. If Senior Martial Brother feels that he doesn't have enough disciples for his talisman refinement division, you may bring it up with the Sect Master. Since Senior Martial Brother Miao is still waiting for me at the acceptance residence, I can't keep you company any longer." The youth surnamed Yu seemed to understand the yellow-robed cultivator's deceitful nature and immediately refused his request. After uttering an excuse, he stomped on his magic tool and brought the group of cultivators down to the pavilion below.

The yellow-robed cultivator thought to further hold him back, but after hearing the youth mention Senior Martial Brother Miao, he revealed slight hesitation and allowed him to go.

After watching the youth and company enter the pavilion from a distance away, his expression fluctuated. After lowering his head in thought for a moment, he coldly snorted and flew off to a different mountain in a streak of yellow light.

At that moment, the group had already arrived on the first floor of the pavilion and were meeting with an unfamiliar man.

He was a shriveled youth glancing through a bamboo scroll with keen interest as he sat in a sandlewood armchair. The man only appeared to be thirty years of age, but his cultivation had already reached the late Foundation Establishment stage. Although he had only reached late Foundation Establishment and hadn't yet consolidated his cultivation, he truly was a rarely seen talent. Having reached so far at his current age, he had great hopes of rising to the Core Formation stage. Could it be because of this man's name that the annoying yellow-robed cultivator didn't dare to trouble Junior Martial Brother Yu any further?

When the other cultivators witnessed the shriveled youth's cultivation, they glanced at each other with expressions of shock.

At that moment, this person had already folded up the bamboo scroll and glanced at the youth. He said with a soft voice, "Junior Martial Brother Yu, I've put you through a bit of trouble. Did Junior Martial Brother Yan block you just now?"

“Since Senior Martial Brother already knows of it, there should be no need to ask. However, did that person come again to bother Senior Martial Sister Peiling?" The valiant-looking youth asked with disgust.

"That person? Even if Junior Martial Brother Yan is somewhat excessive, he is still a fellow disciple of our Drifting Cloud Sect. Your words are inappropriate. Please take note of it in the future, else if the master notices, punishment is unavoidable." The sickly youth's words may have been meant to rebuke him, but his tone was completely flat, lacking even the slightest anger.

But all the same, the Junior Martial Brother Yu's heart trembled and he hastily said, "Senior Martial Brother is correct. This younger disciple will certainly pay attention to it in the future." Seeing that the youth admitted his error, Senior Martial Brother Miao nodded his head and smiled. He then turned his gaze to Han Li and the others as he began to examine each of them.

He seemed to be looking at them quite thoroughly, slowly examining them from head to toe. This had aroused quite a bit of anxiousness among those present. Possibly due to a misconception, Han Li felt that his gaze momentarily paused on the large fully bearded man before quickly turning to another person. Although it was impossible for Han Li's true cultivation to be seen through by him, Han Li felt slightly uneasy.

After a short moment, Senior Martial Brother Miao withdrew his gaze and calmly patted at his waist and took out a talisman that sparkled with silver light.

"It’s good that only about seven have come as I had expected. Otherwise, I wouldn't have enough True Heart talismans for all of you. Junior Martial Brother Yu, take these talismans and place them on their body. After they take effect, bring them to my study." Senior Martial Brother Miao spoke with a serene tone and handed the talismans to the youth. He then stood up from his chair and walked to the second floor without paying them any further attention.

However, when the shriveled youth slowly turned the corner, he suddenly bent down and began to rapidly cough. It sounded quite painful, but soon after, he managed to stand up and head towards the stairway underneath the bewildered gazes of everyone there.

A trace of astonishment flickered in Han Li's eyes but it quickly disappeared.

Junior Martial Brother Yu revealed a trace of anxiousness and sighed before turning towards Han Li and the others. "These are True Heart talismans. I'm sure you know what they do, so I'll save my breath. If you harbor any sinister designs or conspiracies, it would be best for you to take the initiative to leave. Otherwise, if you're discovered, don't blame our Drifting Cloud Sect for being ruthless."

With that said, a cold glint flickered from the youth's eyes as he glanced at the seven before him. Although his tone was quite fearsome, nobody took the initiative to leave.

As a result, the youth nodded with a relaxed expression and tossed the silver talismans towards the seven with a wave of his arm. They all placed beneath each of their right shoulders. The youth then casually sat down without any regard for the other seven and closed his eyes.

The others glanced at each other in dismay. Although they all had their own thoughts in mind, none of them dared to tear off the truth talisman. They could only wait.

At that moment, Han Li tilted his head and glanced at the silver talisman near his shoulder. For a very brief moment, he smirked. Not long after, the talisman began to shine with silver light before it soon faded away.

When the youth felt something happen, he opened his eyes and glanced at Han Li before emotionlessly saying, "Go to the second floor. Senior Martial Brother Miao is waiting for you!"

When Han Li heard that, he glanced at the talisman and wordlessly climbed up the stairs.

The second floor was quite empty with nothing apart from two prayer mats. The shriveled youth was sitting cross-legged on top one of them. When he saw that Han Li had arrived, he pointed to the other prayer mat and smiled, "Please sit down! There is no need to be nervous. It will be over quickly. The interrogation technique isn't anything like a soul bewitchment technique. It only determines whether or not your answers are truthful. Although it doesn't hold completely certainty, it will be correct most of the time. As such, I will ask you ten questions. If three or more are judged to be false, you will not be accepted into the sect. Do you understand?"

Han Li nodded his head and sincerely said, "Junior understands." He then sat down on the prayer mat in front of the youth. Regardless, Han Li inwardly sneered. As if the True Heart Technique could ever reveal his true intentions!

"Alright, let's start. Where were you born..." Seeing that the talisman on Han Li's shoulder was flashing with silver light, he began to ask questions.

...

Han Li and the others flew off from the pavilion and headed straight towards the largest mountain. All of the cultivators had passed the shriveled youth's cultivation without problem. As such, once the Drifting Cloud Sect Master recognized them and had recorded their names, they would become official disciples of the sect.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 602: Gold Forged Constitution

The main peak of the Six Marvelous Peaks was also the largest, standing at over ten kilometers. Many other mountains surrounded it like stars surrounding the moon with Dayspring Mountain being among them. The top half of this mountain was also enveloped in a faint purple fog, concealing everything in a mysterious haze.

Conversely, the bottom half of the mountain was bustling with activity. There were countless buildings of all sizes that covered the mountain spanning from crude stone rooms to expansive hundred meter tall palace halls, and there were a mess of countless scattered limestone roads throughout.

Among these roads were stalls of all sorts with people selling and buying various goods. Many Drifting Cloud Sect disciples were included among them as they haggled over the various items with the stall owners.

When Han Li and the other cultivators saw this, they were left dumbstruck.

The youth surnamed Yu was already accustomed to the sight and paid it no attention as he moved his flying magic tool forward. They shot about kilometer into the air and flew into a stone hall.

The stone hall was made of huge slabs of limestone that reached about a hundred meters tall. Each side of the hall was connected to smaller side rooms that were only about twenty meters wide. There were very few cultivators that entered and left the halls.

Cultivator Yu then landed the alms bowl in front of the hall and had all of them get off. Afterwards, he formed an incantation gesture and had the alms bowl quickly shrink before he put it away into his storage pouch.

"Wait here for a moment, I have to report to the Sect Master first. I'll call for you afterwards." The youth then walked into the hall with large strides.

The many Qi Condensation door keepers clearly recognized Cultivator Yu and merely saluted him with respect as they watched him walk into the hall.

After the youth disappeared from sight, the guards curiously glanced at Han Li and the others. They seemed to have already guessed who they were.

A while later, a streak of white light towards the palace hall before fading away. The light was revealed to be a huge embroidered scarf carrying the pale-faced youth surnamed Liu along with the four other young cultivators that had left before them.

The pale-faced youth gazed at Han Li's group of seven and revealed a trace of surprise. But soon after, he landed his flying magic tool nearby and proudly entered the stone hall, leaving the four young cultivators behind.

In the next moment, Han Li's group and the group of four young gifted cultivators glanced at one another.

For some unknown reason, the atmosphere appeared somewhat amiss despite the fact that both groups were going to enter the sect at the same time. There seemed to be a trace of hostility between them. But as they were about to enter the Drifting Cloud Sect, the two sides could only keep silent and behave themselves.

After the time it took to finish a meal, cultivator Yu finally walked out from the hall. When he appeared, he immediately beckoned to Han Li's group and then turned towards the four gifted youths, "You four will be coming in with us. The Sect Master wishes to accept you all as disciples at the same time." With that said, the youth turned around and reentered the hall.

The two groups didn't dare to delay and hastily followed after him.

Following the youth, they passed through a short corridor before entering a hundred meter wide hall. There were eight cultivators sitting in chairs, whispering about something as they each wore different expressions.

After the disciples were brought inside, the seated cultivators immediately ceased talking and began to examine Han Li's group.

At that moment, Han Li appeared sincere as he displayed deference to them. But at the same time, he had released his spiritual sense and inspected the appearances and cultivations of the seated cultivators.

There was a late Foundation Establishment cultivator, two mid Foundation Establishment cultivators, and the rest were only at early Foundation Establishment. Senior Martial Brother Qiu and the pale-faced cultivator were sitting amongst them.

The blue-robed late Foundation Establishment cultivator waved his hand at the youth and smiled, “We've troubled Junior Martial Brother Yu! Please, take a seat." This person was the Drifting Cloud Sect Master, Wei Yiming.

He had an ordinary appearance with two small eyes. However, each of his movements gave off an exceptionally imposing presence; it appeared he wasn't a simple character.

“Many thanks Senior Martial Brother!" The youth cupped his hands and directly sat down in the chair at the side.

At that moment, the seated cultivators finished examining Han Li's group and had finally moved on to the four talented youths. Each of the youths' gazes revealed a trace of fervent excitement and their bodies straightened upon being examined.

As Han Li took all of this in with a trace of surprise, he heard the sect master speak.

After examining the new disciples, the sect master glanced at the other seated cultivators and slowly said, "Yes! These disciples are suitable enough to enter the sect. They are suitable. After all, we haven't taken in a batch of disciples since several years ago. Junior Martial Brothers, how do you wish for the disciples to be allocated?"

"Naturally, we wholeheartedly agree that the final decision will lie with Senior Marital Brother Wei." An old man with grey hair twirled his short beard and spoke with an exceptionally respectful tone. His voice then changed as he smoothly said, "My Hidden Sword Mountain has no need for any external affair disciples. However, for inner sect disciples, my own Hidden Sword Mountain only recruited two disciples the last time around and is lacking in manpower. My mountain should have a disciple this time around. I have no need for the other disciples, except for the disciple with the Gold Forged constitution.”

After the old man said this, he pointed to the tall and sturdy youth. When the youth heard him, he couldn’t help but reveal surprise.

A deathly-pale middle-aged man was unable to stay sitting upon hearing the old man, and bluntly retorted, “Humph! You might’ve received fewer disciples the last time around, but you also received a disciple with dual-attribute spiritual roots. Needless to say, our Fire Cloud Mountain must be the ones to claim the disciple with the abnormal constitution.”

When the grey-haired old man heard this, he chuckled and shook his head, “Your Fire Cloud Mountain mainly relies on fire attribute cultivation arts, but cultivators possessing the Gold Forged Constitution possess metal attribute spiritual roots. Junior Martial Brother Yang, your position is lacking.”

“Even if your hidden sword mountain possess metal attribute cultivation techniques, our Fire Cloud Mountain’s Senior Martial Uncle Li’s Metal Tempering Arts are renowned throughout the entire State of Xi. Why can’t this disciple cultivate his techniques?” The middle-aged man didn’t reveal the slightest intention of backing down.

“You...”

The sect master frowned and interrupted, “Enough, I’ve already heard your thoughts. There is no need to further speak of them.”

Senior Martial Brother Liu smiled and mediated, “That’s right. Senior Martial Brothers’ dispute will have no end. It’s better to have Sect Master decide. After all, regardless of which mountain receives him, he will still be a disciple of our Drifting Cloud Sect in the end. There is no reason to fight.”

The old man and the deathly-pale middle-aged man glanced at each other, but the old man rushed to say, “Junior Martial Brother Qiu’s words holds reason. Our Hidden Sword Mountain will hold no complaint if the Sect Master makes the decision.”

When the middle-aged man heard this, he hesitated for a moment before agreeing.

The sect master’s expression relaxed and after a moment of thought, he turned to Han Li’s group and calmly said, “These disciples are particularly special so we should handle them last. Let’s distribute these other disciples. After all, our six mountains of the Drifting Cloud Sect have never turned away good help. Let’s first distribute these seven external affair disciples.”

Two hours later, Han Li and the fully bearded man stood on a huge alms bowl and were being brought back to Dayspring Mountain by Cultivator Yu.

They’d already changed into the attire of blue robes for low grade disciples and had been distributed to Dayspring Mountain.

Cultivator Yu brought the two out of the stone hall once the distribution was finished without the slightest complaint.

As for the tall and sturdy youth that was in high demand, he was unexpectedly assigned to Illusion Stone Mountain. Although the grey-haired old man and the middle-aged man were both dispirited, they could only concede the matter. But fortunately, they were each given an inner sect disciple and ended up with something for their troubles.

“Although you’ve only entered the sect as external affair disciples, it is quite fortunate for you to be distributed to our Dayspring Mountain. Because our Martial Ancestor is gentle and kind-hearted, we won’t treat you too harshly. You only have to finish your assignments within the given time. The rest of your time you will be free to do as you wish.”

“If you have the opportunity to acquire great merits, perhaps the Martial Ancestor will even bestow a Foundation Establishment Pill to you. After all, external affair and inner sect disciples receive the same treatment in name. However, the inner sect disciple’s main assignments are to cultivate. Because of your poor aptitudes, you are assigned to other various tasks such as medicine and talisman refinement. The attainments of the many Martial Uncles in these fields are quite profound.” Because Han Li and the fully-bearded man were already disciples of Dayspring Mountain, Cultivator Yun spoke to the two with a much more gentle tone as he gave them an explanation of sect matters.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 603: Affiliation

“Many thanks for Martial Uncle Yu’s guidance!” Although Han Li found it somewhat awkward, he wore a respectful expression as he uttered his thanks.

As for the fully bearded man, he merely grinned, appearing as if he weren’t one for words.

Already knowing that there was something amiss about his past, Han Li felt dumbfounded. The large man’s acting skills had already reached perfection. Could it be he truly didn’t know about the oddities of his own body?

While that Senior Martial Brother Miao also noticed something odd, Han Li was certain that a late Foundation Establishment cultivator wouldn’t be able to see through the person’s cold Qi. There was certain to be something amiss; it was quite thought provoking.

Cultivator Yu seemed pleased by the two’s reactions and spoke a few words more before bringing them to a pavilion located at the center of Dayspring Mountain.

They landed on a limestone platform where two young teenagers were chatting about something. When they saw Cultivator Yu appear, they immediately stopped talking and approached them.

The doll-faced girl chuckled and asked, “Well if it isn’t Martial Uncle Yu! Did you come to visit Martial Ancestor?” Knowing the strictness of seniority in the cultivation world, Han Li felt shocked at the girl’s casual attitude.

Cultivator Yu smiled and said, “That’s right. These two are external affair disciples that our mountain received from this selection. I am here to report to Martial Ancestor and see which Senior Martial Brothers to give them to.” It appeared he was quite familiar with the girl.

The girl then turned her gaze to Han Li and the large man. She sweetly smiled and said, “So they’re newly arrived Junior Martial Brothers. If you have an opportunity in the future, please don’t forget to pay me and Junior Martial Brother Xin a visit and tell me a bit about the mortal world. I’m looking forward to it.”

The dark-skinned teenager at her side meekly muttered, “If Senior Martial Sister wishes to hear them, don’t drag me in. I would prefer to cultivate.”

“You can cultivate anytime you want, but having new disciples enter Dayspring Mountain from the mortal world is something that is hard to come by. Naturally, we should listen to a few interesting tales from the outside!” Although the she was quite young and dainty, she chided the boy with a bold attitude, leaving him at a loss for words.

Cultivator Yu revealed a wry smile and shook his head before bringing Han Li and the large man into the courtyard.

As they walked, Cultivator Yu warned, “Keep note of those two. Junior Martial Sister Ma and Junior Martial Brother Xin may appear young and hold the same seniority as you, but they are the Martial Ancestor’s descendants from the mortal world. Although they haven’t yet been accepted as official disciples, it is a matter that will occur sooner or later. Do not offend them no matter what; nobody will protect you from the Martial Ancestor.”

When Han Li heard this, he nodded his head with a forced smile. As for the large man, he rubbed the back of his head and silently smiled.

When Cultivator Yu saw their reactions, he smiled and consoled them, “Junior Martial Brother Xin is a sincere person. He won’t do anything inappropriate. Although Junior Martial Sister Ma has always been somewhat mischievous, she doesn’t bear any malice. There is no need to be too worried about them; you just have to pay a bit more attention to them.”

Of course, Han Li and the large man repeatedly nodded their heads in response.

After that was said, the three had already passed through three courtyards before appearing in front of a secluded side wing.

As soon as the three appeared at the side wing, they faintly heard a man’s voice. “Is that you, Jun’er?”

When Yu Jun heard this, he immediately stopped in place and solemnly replied, “Disciple pays his respects to master!”

“Your Third Martial Brother and your Fifth Martial Sister also happen to be here. Go ahead and bring the two behind you inside.” From the liveliness of the voice, the owner seemed to be in a good mood.

“Yes!” Yu Jun didn’t dare to delay and called to Han Li and large man before hastily entering the half closed door of the side room.

Apart from several pots of various unknown plants, the elegant and refined hall only had a black wood table along with a set of chairs. A middle-aged man in scholar robes sat at the side. He had an incredibly old fashioned appearance with a long, thin mustache and a beard that reached to his chest, giving him a sagelike appearance with otherworldly poise.

To his side stood an old man and a young woman.

With a wrinkle-filled face and pure white hair, the old man was by all means someone that appeared to have nearly reached his end. He was silently smiling. As for the woman, she appeared to be in her late twenties and possessed a fair, elegant appearance. She was currently expressionless.

Yu Jun hastily stepped forward and saluted them in a kneel, “I pay my respects to Master! Greetings, Third Senior Martial Brother, Fifth Senior Martial Sister!”

“Please stand up. There are no outsiders here, no need to be so formal. So these two must be the newly accepted disciples of our Dayspring Mountain!” The middle-aged man waved his arm and had Yu Jun stand up. Afterwards, he examined Han Li and the large man with interest.

When Han Li saw that this person was a mid Core Formation cultivator, he felt somewhat gloomy, but he could only force a smile and call out to him as, “Martial Ancestor.” The large man had done the same.

This Martial Ancestor possessed neither the capability of spotting the peculiarity of the large man’s body nor seeing through Han Li’s true cultivation.

As such, he asked for their names and casually said, “Good, good, good...” He then turned to the old man and young woman at his side and mildly instructed them, “Since you two are here, I won’t have to bother any others. As an expert in talisman refinement and a pill concoction adept, you should be lacking people. Take in these two newly arrived disciples for the time being. Naturally, pick a cultivation art for them along the way. Even if they are external affair disciples, if their cultivation is too poor, they’ll be a target of ridicule by their fellow sect members from the other mountains.”

The white-faced old man replied with a wide smile, “Yes, Master! Junior Martial Sister and I will take a person each.”

The beautiful woman in her twenties hesitated for a moment before nodding her head.

After a moment of thought, the old man proposed, “Since Junior Martial Sister also agrees, how about I take Martial Nephew Du over to my talisman refinement division? I am in need of sturdy helpers, so that will leave Martial Nephew Han to you!”

The woman agreed with an unchanged expression, not bothering to glance at Han Li.

When the middle-aged man saw this, he nodded his head and spoke to Han Li and the large man, “You two are dismissed, wait outside for a moment. I still have matters to discuss with your seniors.”

Han Li and the large man glanced at each other before sincerely acknowledging him. They then headed out of the room and stood about ten meters away from the room as they obediently waited.

Soon after, the large man glanced to the cloudless far away sky and remained still. It was unknown what he was thinking about. As for Han Li, he wore a lazy expression as he eavesdropped on the conversation inside. With his immense spiritual sense, Han Li was able to listen without a problem. Although his expression was unchanged, several odd movements escaped from his eyes.

After the time it took to finish a meal, the door to the side room finally opened, and the three disciples left the room one after the other.

The old man wordlessly raised his hand and released a slender magic tool. After he said his farewells to the woman and Yu Jun, he took to the skies with the large man in tow.

At that moment, the woman walked over to Han Li and coldly swept her gaze over him. She emotionlessly said, “Let’s go. You’ll be coming back with me to my cave residence.”

A faint smirk momentarily appeared on Han Li’s face before he nodded with a indifferent expression.

With a pulse of red light, an expanse of red mist enveloped the both of them.

Four hours later, Han Li had appeared at a strange medicine garden that was over three hundred meters wide.

The verdant medicine garden had many types of medicinal herbs and a thatched cottage with three rooms. When Han Li saw the nameless small mountain nearby, he stroked his chin and revealed a faint smile.

Previously, the cold and elegant mid Foundation Establishment woman had used a red ribbon to bring the two to her cave residence. This “Martial Aunt” Mu Peiling had asked him if he was willing to look after the medicinal garden or if he was willing learn the art of pill refinement.

This had stunned Han Li. After all, so long as a cultivator was right of mind, they would agree to learn without a doubt.

But before the woman waited for Han Li’s reply, she coldly explained that looking after the medicine garden was rather simple. So long as he handed over a fixed amount of medicinal ingredients, he could spent a majority of his time in cultivation. Although external affair disciples also had an opportunity to touch upon the profound path of medicinal pills, the cost of pursuing that path was to refine a certain amount of pills every month, greatly reducing their cultivation time. As a result, each of them had their own advantages.

Without even the slightest deliberation, Han Li instantly chose his old task of looking after the medicine garden. This was a task that may as well have been created for him; it would allow him to cultivate without fear or obstruction.

He had originally thought that he would have to escape from various menial jobs in order to cultivate. But as it turned out, this extremely suitable medicine garden task was brought before him by fortunate chance!

The cold, elegant woman didn’t reveal the slightest surprise at Han Li’s choice.

Since he was brought here, Mu Peiling brought away the original keeper of the medicinal garden and left behind a jade slip that recorded a water attribute cultivation art, the Profound Ice Arts.

This medicine garden had now become Han Li’s domain.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 605: Bloodshadow Evasion

Mei Peiling had continuously treated Han Li with a neutral indifference during her visits, as he prefered. It would be best for him to have this woman forget that this medicinal garden even existed. If she stopped paying him any visits, it would be very convenient for his cultivation.

After yet another month passed, Han Li had finally grasped a near complete understanding of the Spirit Constraining Formation and immediately placed one down around the mountain in accordance to his understanding.

As a result, the faint spiritual Qi fluctuations of the spell formations had completely vanished. From the outside, the small mountain appeared completely ordinary, much to Han Li’s satisfaction.

In the next three months, Han Li had both fully refined the Weeping Soul Pearl to completion and expelled the Wind Spirit Energy in its entirety, far quicker than he had originally expected. But what surprised Han Li the most was how he didn’t feel any illness or headaches upon connecting his spiritual sense to the Weeping Soul Pearl when he completely refined it. It seemed that the Weeping Soul Beast’s unexpected evolution had also caused the deathly Weeping Soul Pearl to also undergo a strange transformation. Han Li was overjoyed by the discovery.

As for the harmful Wind Spirit Energy, although it had been difficult and exhausting to expel it from his body, once he had expelled a majority of it, it had become far easier to deal with. Not only was the harmful energy less painful to handle, but he was able to expel it from his body in much less time. The last several strands of energy had been extremely easy to rid himself of.

After carefully examining his body several times to find no abnormalities, Han Li eventually felt relief.

With the most vital matters already taken care of, Han Li focused his attention to cultivation and the medicine pill refined from the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng.

He pondered for several days on the matter of cultivation before deciding to simultaneously cultivate the fourth layer of the Great Development Technique and the Azure Essence Sword Arts. According to his previous experiences with forming a golden core, a powerful spiritual sense seemed to greatly benefit in breaking through bottlenecks. Even if the fourth layer of the Great Development Technique was extremely difficult, Han Li planned on giving it a try.

Even if spiritual sense didn’t provide a particularly large benefit in condensing a Nascent Soul, it would at least prove greatly beneficial when confronting an enemy.

While this path may somewhat increase the time it would take to reach the false Nascent stage, Han Li didn’t believe the choice was incorrect as he would only lose a bit of time at the worst.

As for the matter of refining the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng, Han Li couldn’t afford to be negligent. While the other materials were easily replaced, the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng, the grade eight Demon Echo Grass and the Agate Horn were nowhere to be found in the Heavenly South. If he were to fail in the pill refinement process, Han Li would be left without any alternative.

As a result, Han Li began to study the formula for the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng in between his cultivation. He often refined a few various pills in accordance to the techniques described in the formula in order to improve his own pill concoction techniques.

Time began to slowly pass by as he repeatedly cultivated and refined pills.

During this period, Han Li had also taken the time to learn demon script in preparations to comprehend the old hide book and the copper plate in his possession so that he could finally learn what they contained. By making use of his eidetic memory, Han Li was able to easily grasp the ancient demon characters and began to look through the details of the hide book.

The old hide book contained a demon art known as the “Nine Gale Transformations”. After taking a look at it, Han Li discovered that the technique was specialized for bird-type demonic beasts. It contained a series of spell arts, body techniques, and two secret techniques.

The spell arts and body techniques were out of the question. Unless a powerful demon were to cultivate it, one would find their body bursting halfway as they cultivated it.

As for the two secret techniques, one of them was the nameless concealment technique that he had been using this entire time, the Hidden Wind Technique. However, the nameless concealment technique was slightly altered from the original in order to become more suitable for human cultivators. It currently held no value to Han Li apart for reference.

However, the other secret technique that was described was of much interest to Han Li, the Bloodshadow Evasion Technique.

As the name implies, Bloodshadow Evasion was a strange movement technique that draws support from one’s blood essence and allowed one to flee over fifty kilometers in an instant.

Secret techniques that drew support from one’s blood essence in order display great abilities were something that most Devil Dao cultivators were capable of. However, this Bloodshadow Evasion was quite different from the secret techniques of humans.

First of all, one is incapable of controlling the distance traveled with this technique. When this technique was activated, one would instantly turn into a crimson blur as they shot over fifty kilometers away.

Secondly, this secret technique required a large, fixed amount of blood essence. Once the technique was activated, the blood essence for this technique would immediately ignite. However, if one lacked enough blood essence to use the technique, the technique would cause one’s body to rupture halfway through and turn into a cloud of gore. It was a truly dangerous technique.

Lastly, activating this technique required a pair of wings. Because Bloodshadow Evasion was too fast, without any wings to maintain balance and a particular body lightening technique, the technique could cause one to crash into the earth after traveling only a short distance, or return back to where one started. In brief, a clean escape would be an impossibility without them.

Han Li carefully read through the secret technique several times. No matter how he saw it, he felt that it was very suitable for him to cultivate.

While other humans might not have wings, Han Li had the Thunderstorm Wings. The treasure’s spirit wings were no different from true wings.

If the Bloodshadow Evasion was truly as amazing as described, then it was an optimal technique for escaping. After all, the Thunderstorm Wings could only use lightning evasion to travel over a small area. It would only be able to flicker incessantly and would be incapable of making a clean escape.

After committing the cultivation method of Bloodshadow Evasion to his memory, he started to look through the copper plate.

The copper plate didn’t have a name for its techniques and its descriptions made little sense. Han Li also found the strange cultivation postures unfathomable. After glancing at the techniques it recorded, Han Li was left particularly confused.

After all of this, Han Li faintly recalled what the flood dragon had said. This Divine Provenance Plate seemed to be damaged beyond use. It was no wonder why he couldn’t make sense of the plate.

After realizing this, Han Li grew greatly dispirited and could only put the plate away.

From that day on, Han Li added the Bloodshadow Evasion to his cultivation routine in addition to the Great Development Technique and the Azure Essence Sword Arts.

Although he later felt that he had grasped the technique, he didn’t dare to rashly test it. A great decrease in blood essence wasn’t something that could be joked about.

This continued as half a year unknowingly passed.

One day, Han Li sat inside a quiet room as he cultivated the Great Development Technique when he suddenly opened his eyes. A strange expression flickered over his face as his body immediately glowed with azure light before he immediately shot out from his cave residence to the medicinal garden.

A short moment later, Han Li was standing in front of the medicine garden’s cottage with all of his puppets placed away.

He glanced to the southeast and pensively thought for a moment before taking a seat inside the cottage. He then steeped a cup of tea and assumed a relaxed position.

A short moment later, an extremely polite voice came from outside the medicine garden’s restrictions, “Excuse me, could you tell me if Senior Martial Sister Yuan is here? I am the Hidden Sword Mountain’s Kui Huan.” The young man’s voice seemed to contain a trace of urgency.

‘Senior Martial Sister Yuan? Was that the name of the original caretaker of the medicine garden?’

Han Li’s face remained calm as the new arrival shouted several more times. Han Li then downed his cup and slowly replied, “Senior Martial Brother, there is no need to shout. Senior Martial Yuan left this place half a year ago. This medicine garden is now being cared for by me. If you wish to find her, then you should pay a visit to Martial Aunt Mu’s cave residence.”

“What? The medicine garden changed caretakers?” The young man was astonished. From his tone, it seemed he wasn’t trying to find someone, but had come to the medicine garden for something else.

The man chuckled and amiably said, “Since Senior Martial Sister Yuan isn’t here, then Junior Martial Brother will do. Would Junior Martial Brother release the restrictions so that I may have a chat with you?”

Han Li rubbed his chin. From how elegantly spoken his words were, Han Li had no grounds to refuse him!

After some thought, Han Li walked out from the cottage and took out a yellow command talisman. With a flash of radiance, the mist surrounding the medicine garden began to slowly dissipate.

This revealed a yellow-robed young man that stood in the southeast of the restriction.

The man had thin eyes, thick eyebrows and a large, straight nose. His head was also slightly smaller than normal. Although his appearance couldn’t be said to be ugly, it was somewhat comical.

His cultivation was only at the ninth layer of Qi Condensation, somewhat inferior to Han Li’s displayed cultivation. It was unknown how this person was able to enter the Drifting Cloud Sect.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 606: Snowcloud Fox

As Han Li was examining the young man’s appearance, the young man chuckled and walked into the medicine garden. He enthusiastically said, “So Junior Martial Brother is a disciple of Dayspring Mountain. Your face is quite unfamiliar. Could you be a new disciple? In that case, I could genuinely be considered your Senior Martial Brother.”

“My surname is Han. I entered the sect earlier this year. Senior Martial Brother must be a brilliant disciple of Hidden Sword Mountain!” Han Li withdrew his gaze and smiled.

“So it’s Junior Martial Brother Han. I am Hidden Sword Mountain’s Kui Huan. I take care of a nearby spirit beast field along with several other Senior Martial brothers. Junior Martial Brother should pay a visit if he finds an opportunity. Although my cultivation isn’t very high, I’ve been at the sect for eight years and know many of the matters in the Drifting Cloud Sect along with the various disciples of the six mountains. If there is anything you feel unsure of, please don’t hesitate to ask me.” The man had spoken elegantly the entire way through.

Han Li faintly smiled. The eloquent man reminded him of Little Abacus from all those years ago at the Seven Mysteries Sect. He was also eloquent, smooth at establishing relations, and proclaimed himself to be greatly knowledgeable. They were clearly the same kind of person.

While Han Li did find this humorous, he didn’t mean any ill will towards him. He crossed his arms and blinked, asking, “Many thanks for your kindness. However, may I ask if Brother Kui has any urgent matters for coming here?”

Kui Huan revealed slight embarrassment and hesitated for a moment. He then rubbed the back of his head and said, “It can’t be said to be an important matter. I merely came to ask Senior Martial Sister Yuan for some help. I just didn’t think that the caretaker of the garden for six years would suddenly leave. This has left me in a bit of a difficult situation.”

“You want help?” Han Li frowned and revealed a trace of doubt.

“It isn’t anything much. Surely Junior Martial Brother knows that since us external affair disciples have inferior aptitudes, we aren’t particularly valued. The sect’s’ magic tools and medicine pills naturally won’t fall into our hands. A year’s worth of hard earned spirit stones isn’t even enough to buy a few cultivation progression medicine pills. As such, I along with many other martial brothers go to the nearby Greentrack Marsh and capture a few small rare animals to sell at the market. These Snowcloud Foxes aren’t demon beasts, but their petite physique, adorable appearance, and human-like intelligence makes them in high demand with female disciples of the sect. That is why my martial brothers and I struggle to capture a lot of them.

“Not long ago, we discovered a strange Snowcloud Fox that had a faint trace of spiritual Qi on it as if it had transformed into a low grade demon beast. This was naturally a cause for joy. If we could capture it alive, it would net over a hundred spirit stones, a rarely seen sum. Unfortunately, we were far too impatient and didn’t think things through, allowing the fox to escape. Now, the demon beast has already fled deep into the marsh and is difficult to spot. Although we’ve searched through a majority of the marsh and have occasionally spotted it, it wouldn’t allow us to come any closer. It would simply flee deeper inside.” With that said, Kui Huan revealed a trace of regret.

When he saw that Han Li wore a pensive expression, he paused for a moment before continuing, “We later left a few people to watch over it for a time and discovered that this strange Snowcloud Fox is fond of eating Huangjing [1] , especially Huangjing that is over ten years old. We reckon that if we wished to lure the beast, we would need Huangjing that is at least fifty years old before it would fall into our trap. Junior Martial Brother should know that any medicinal herb that is several tens of years old isn’t something that can be bought with a few spirit stones. It would require more than a couple dozen!

“While we did have a few savings, we already pooled them together earlier to buy cultivation medicine. We don’t have any spirit stones leftover. Helpless, I could only think of Senior Martial Sister Yuan’s medicine garden. It seems there should be two or three stalks of Huangjing that are at that age. That’s why I paid a visit, but I didn’t expect that she would be swapped with Junior Martial Brother Han. D-do you think you could spare a stalk of Huangjing for us to use?” When Kui Huan asked his question, his voice grew softer and he somewhat stammered.

It seemed he also knew that his request was somewhat excessive.

After that was said, Han Li’s face remained unfathomable. After a short moment of silence, he said, “I do have two stalks of Huangjing that are over fifty years old which are according to your specifications.

“While it stands to reason that since this is the first time Senior Martial Brother Kui has come to seek help, I shouldn’t refuse you as your Junior Martial Brother. However, Senior Martial Brother Kui should realize I do not have the authority to give out the spirit herbs in this garden. If it were lacking something or if it were to disappear, I wouldn’t have anything to say when Martial Aunt asks for them. I fear I would be punished. That is why I cannot help you.”

Han Li’s words were quite calm, but the yellow-robed man couldn’t help but reveal disappointment.

“Junior Martial Brother, please be at ease. I am only going to borrow this spirit herb for several days. When the time comes, I will be certain to return it to you with thanks. We will also be extremely careful as we transport the spiritual herb so that there will be no mistakes. Of course, us Senior Martial Brothers won’t have you lend the spirit herb for nothing. After this succeeds, we’ll be certain to give you a few spirit stones. We won’t have you suffer a loss.”

“I am sorry! This matter is quite important. I cannot allow you to use this medicinal herb. However, if you are lacking in spirit stones, I do have some saved up. I can lend a few to Senior Martial Brother so you can buy a herb instead.” After giving a staunch refusal, Han Li proposed an alternative with a smile.

The yellow-robed man’s unsightly expression quickly brightened, “Is Junior Martial Brother serious? If you can lend us spirit stones, it is natural that I won’t need the spiritual herbs of your garden. However, a medicinal herb of that age will cost at least thirty spirit stones. Does Junior Martial Brother truly have that much?” His delighted expression soon revealed a trace of doubt. After all, this was by no means a small amount to a Qi Condensation cultivator.

Han Li slowly said, “These spirit stones were saved up before I joined the sect and I’ve yet to use them. I’ll lend them to Senior Martial Brother for now! If these spirit stones could be turned into more, I wouldn’t want to miss such a rare opportunity.”

“Hehe, so it turned out that Junior Martial Brother Han is an expert in conducting business. Please don’t worry about it, Junior Martial Brother. With the Huangjing, that Snowcloud Fox is practically ours.” Kui Huan couldn’t help but grin upon finding Han Li had spoken truthfully.

Han Li smiled and grabbed his storage pouch. He then handed over thirty various colored spirit stones to the young man without any reservations.

Kui Huan received the spirit stones with delight and pledged that they would succeed without problem. With only a bit of idle conversation afterwards, he took his leave with his mind occupied.

As Han Li glanced at the departing young man, his smile faded away and he shook his head. He naturally didn’t place the pledge to bring back the spirit stones in any regard. He merely didn’t wish to offend anyone after having just arrived at the Drifting Cloud Sect.

Han Li planned on staying at the Drifting Cloud Sect for quite a while. Being acquainted with a well-connected individual such as Kui Huan could prove to be very useful.

With that thought, Han Li reactivated the medicine garden’s restrictions and returned back to the the small stone mountain to continue his cultivation.

...

Three days later, Han Li was silently standing in front of an embarrassed Kui Huan.

He wasn’t there to return the spirit stones, but rather to request Han Li’s help to capture the Snowcloud Fox.

Han Li pursed his lips and doubtfully asked, “You don’t have enough people to capture a low grade demon beast?”

Kui Huan chuckled and said, “Junior Martial Brother doesn’t know how sly this Snowcloud Fox is, nor does he know how fast it is. Even common flying magic tools are unable to chase it down. We were originally going to have an inner sect Senior Martial Brother lend us a set of Obscure Track Formation tools to deal with the fox, but this Senior Martial Brother was unexpectedly assigned to a task yesterday and is no longer present in the sect. As such, we are lacking a member to use the formation. It would cost us quite a few more spirit stones in order to replace him as there aren’t any others that would be willing. That’s why I came to request Junior Martial Brother to assist us. Naturally, we will give Junior Martial Brother a larger share of the spirit stones when we succeed.”

When Han Li heard this, he stroked his chin and pondered for a moment. Had Kui Huan come to request his assistance any other time, he would’ve bluntly refused; there would’ve been no way he would wasted his time over such a trivial affair. But a few days before as he was cultivating the fourth layer of the Great Development Technique in seclusion, he felt his nerves grow restless and had no luck regaining his tranquil temperament ever since.

It seemed this was a sign that he had reached a bottleneck for the Great Development Technique. As such, this may prove to be a good opportunity as bottlenecks are broken through by chance encounters. Perhaps going out would do something for it.

Having thought that, Han Li nodded and said, “Since Senior Martial Brother Kui has spoken as such, I will assist you. I am quite curious where this Greentrack Marsh is.” Han Li then lazily smiled.

[1]. In English, this herb is known as Polygonatum sibiricum or as Solomon's Seal.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 608: The Fox's Appearance

Han Li was the last to descend into the valley. Seeing that everyone around him had started to take the miasma treatment pills, he couldn’t help but smile. With his body’s essence having been purified, any miasma entering his body was cleansed with a single breath.

At that moment, the group was flying straight towards the center of the valley.

“That demon fox is extremely clever, and we will only get one chance to capture it. As such, we must find a wide area so that it cannot escape from the formation. There is a flat field free of mud not far ahead of us. We won’t have to fear it running away by digging into the mud.” From Senior Martial Brother Wang’s plans, it seemed he had deliberated much about this matter.

Having followed Senior Martial Brother Wang this long, the others in the group naturally raised no objections. As for Han Li, he merely smiled and remained silent.

A short moment later, the five arrived in a lush, flat field with short shrubbery sparsely scattered about.

Without waiting for Senior Martial Brother Wang’s instruction, Kui Huan and the others landed on the field and examined their nearby surroundings.

Following a quick discussion, Kui Huan walked to the center of the field and dug open a small hole. He then carefully took out the Huangjing that he bought from the market and shallowly buried it in the hole so that it slightly emerged from the ground. Afterwards, he sprinkled a bit more dirt on top to make it look a bit more natural. A faint medicinal aroma immediately began to spread out.

“Good, that will do. The Snowcloud Fox has a very keen sense of smell. Even if the Huangjing is three feet buried, the Snowcloud Fox will surely smell its aged medicinal scent.” Kui Huang stood up and dusted off his hands with satisfaction. He then recalled something and took out a white formation flag. “Ah right, Junior Martial Brother, take this. It’s an Obscure Track Formation flag.”

Han Li nodded his head and calmly received the small flag. At that moment, Senior Martial Brother Wang began to brief the party.

He solemnly said, “In a moment, everyone will take up a position on higher ground. When the demon fox appears, we’ll all use the formation flags at the same time and envelope the field in an illusion formation. I am confident that since the Snowcloud Fox only recently turned into a demon beast, it will not be able to flee from the formation.”

All the others nodded their heads in agreement before taking off on their flying magic tools. They all motionlessly floated about a hundred-fifty meters in the air with formation flags in their hands. They each used shallow invisibility magic techniques to conceal themselves as they waited.

Since this involved such a large amount of spirit stones, Kui Huan and the others each appeared rather nervous as they unblinkingly stared down below. Even Senior Martial Brother Wang wore a grave expression as he deeply stared.

In contrast, Han Li was the most calm amongst them. He was holding the white formation flag in a single hand as he swept his gaze around. In fact, Han Li had already enveloped the area of a kilometer around them with his spiritual sense. He would be the first to know if any winds blew or any bush shook.

The area became deathly silent as two hours passed by. Kui Huan’s neck began to ache as he stood on his magic tool from continuously watching down below. His face revealed faint impatience. He glanced at Senior Martial Brother Wang and thought to say something to him, but after some hesitation, he shut his mouth upon further thought. There was nothing to complain about even if they had to wait a while longer. This was all in order to capture the demon fox.

After yet another hour passed by, most of the group began to feel anxious. As for Han Li, his expression began to stir as he stared at a patch of nearby shrubbery.

At that moment, Kui Huan couldn’t help but stir. He licked his lips and was about to say something when he heard Han Li’s cold voice through a voice transmission, “Be careful, the demon fox has already arrived. It is hiding in a bush to the west. Don’t scare it away.”

The other three also heard Han Li’s voice transmission.

In response, all of them glanced at the west bushes in alarm only to discover that nothing strange could be seen. They couldn’t help but be skeptical of Han Li’s words, but their relaxed attitudes became vigilant once more.

After the time it took to finish a meal, surprise was clear in their eyes as a foot-long, snow-white beast slowly walked out from a bush. It turned its head around with each step and its whiskers occasionally twitched in hopeful anticipation. It was incredibly adorable.

Upon seeing this, the other four grew vigilant and nervously grasped the formation flags in their hands.

The white fox didn’t glance up at the five. After seeing that there was nothing strange in its surroundings, it grew slightly more courageous and it began to silently walk in the direction of the Huangjing.

However, when it arrived about thirty meters away from the Huangjing, it suddenly stopped and its small pink nose suddenly sniffed the air. A trace of doubt flickered in its eyes as if it had discovered something.

This scene had caused Senior Martial Wang to lose his calm and he loudly shouted, “Now!” His formation flag dropped to the ground in a streak of yellow light. When Han Li and the others heard this, they threw down the formation flags without hesitation and each uttered several incantations.

Five different lights began to shine from the flags as soon as they touched the ground. A large expanse of yellow mist then enveloped the field, sealing it from every direction. The Five Elements Obscure Track Formation had taken effect.

When the Snowcloud Fox saw this, it naturally knew that it was trapped. It immediately released several panicked howls and turned into a white blur as it shot into the yellow mist in an attempt to escape.

The group of cultivators appeared somewhat relieved upon seeing this, but they didn’t relax just yet. The illusion formation merely changed the direction of the white fox so that it turned in circles and stayed within the formation. The cultivators naturally wished to exhaust the beast first before they set to capturing it.

The group of people beamingly smiled as if this operation was a success. After the small fox ran around inside the yellow mist, it suddenly blurred several times before collapsing to the ground. It no longer stood up.

When the others saw this, they couldn’t help but feel frightened and looked at each other in dismay.

Senior Martial Brother Wang’s face grew sullen and he calmly said, “Do not release the restriction. We will continue to maintain it. Junior Martial Brother Ma, go down and see what is happening. The Obscure Track Formation is only able to trap, it does not cause harm. From the fox’s sly nature, it is most likely pretending to be dead.”

The others were greatly relieved upon hearing him and the youth surnamed Ma wordlessly descended.

Han Li faintly smirked at the scene and glanced down with a mysterious smile.

The short and stout Senior Martial Brother Ma was rather fast. After a short moment, he had entered the yellow mist and was several steps away from the fox.

He carefully grabbed the white fox tail and boldly shook it several times. The white fox was unresponsive as if it were truly dead.

As a result, the youth surnamed Ma felt slightly panicked and immediately pressed his ear against the beast’s chest.

Soon after, Senior Martial Brother Ma flusteredly shouted from within the mist, “Senior Martial Brother, quickly come down, the demon fox’s body is ice-cold. Perhaps its heart has stopped from fright!”

“Impossible!” Senior Martial Brother Wang couldn’t help but change his expression.

Kui Huan nervously said, “Senior Martial Brother, let’s release the spell formation and take another look. Our spiritual power cannot sustain the restriction for much longer.”

The cultivator surnamed Xi remained silent but a trace of worry appeared in his eyes. The demon beast wouldn’t be worth much if it were dead.

After a moment of hesitation Senior Marital Brother Wang nodded his head and said, “Fine! We’ll release the spell formation since Junior Martial Brother Ma has already grabbed onto the spirit beast.”

When Han Li heard this, he calmly rubbed his chin, but he didn’t display the slightest opposition.

Suddenly, the cultivators began to mutter some words and point to the ground, causing four of the flags to shoot back into their hands as streaks of light.

In the instant the yellow mist dissipated, a short and stout youth placed his finger on the small beast’s nose as if he were testing something.

The three dropped down with sullen expressions. However, Han Li remained standing in his original position as he glanced at the white fox down below. His face revealed an odd expression.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 609: The Chase

Before Senior Martial Wang and the other two descended, the youth surnamed Ma had already placed his finger on the white fox’s nose and angrily cursed, “Damn! This thing isn’t breathing! Don’t tell me that it died for nothing.”

With that said, he raised his head to the three and was about to say something more with an angry face.

The three that were descending suddenly had their expressions greatly changed as they shouted, “Careful! The demon fox is alive! It was only playing dead!”

The three all shouted different words, but their meanings were all the same.

The short and stout youth was rather quick-witted, and his expression abruptly changed upon hearing them. His hand instantly blurred and a white talisman appeared between his fingers. He fiercely slapped the talisman onto the fox’s tail.

However, his actions were clearly too slow. As soon as he extended his hand holding the talisman, he felt a sharp pain coming out from the hand that held onto the fox.

He loudly shouted as he unconsciously released his grip. The fox slipped away and rolled onto the ground.

In the blink of an eye, the fox’s tail had become erect and its fur became the same as needles. The youth’s hand was now filled with holes and dripping with blood.

When the other three saw this, they flew towards the small beast in furious alarm.

The white fox wasn’t about to easily be captured. It scuttled away and turned into a white streak as it shot forty meters away. With several hops, it fled back into the shrubbery.

In a moment of desperation, Senior Martial Brother Wang and the other two surrounded the bush and released their magic tools as they slowly combed through it.

But after a short moment, the three revealed astonishment. Apart from a pile of stones, there was nothing else in the bushes. The white fox had clearly disappeared without a trace. The three then despondently stood in place.

Kui Huan unconsciously turned his gaze to the sky and shouted in alarm, “Yi! Where is Junior Martial Brother Han going?” At that moment, the others also discovered that Han Li was quickly flying off into the distance.

Han Li’s voice transmission soon arrived at their ear, “There is no need for Senior Martial Brothers to be so flustered. That fox slipped away using a vision obscuring technique and dug into the earth. Right now, I am using a magic tool to track it down. Once it comes back up, I’ll capture it alive.” With that said, Han Li flew off towards the edge of the marsh.

When Senior Martial Brother Wang heard him, he grew delighted and called out to the others before impatiently chasing after Han Li. The other three were close behind him.

As they hurried along their way, Senior Martial Brother Wang turned his head around and asked, “Junior Martial Brother Ma, how is your hand?”

The short, stout youth was at the very rear. He muttered with a shameful expression, “It’s still good. Fortunately, the fox’s tail didn’t have any poison. It’s merely a superficial wound.” After all, it was his carelessness that had resulted in the fox’s escape. Additionally, the issue had been called to attention by someone, causing him to feel quite embarrassed.

Senior Martial Brother Wang forced a smile and said, “That’s good. Let’s quicken our pace. Although I don’t know what kind of magic tool Junior Martial Brother Han is using to track the underground movements of the demon fox, we should hurry after him.”

Kui Huan turned around and repeatedly nodded his head in agreement. With an odd tone, he said, “Nevertheless, the intelligence of this evolved Snowcloud Fox is truly too much. Even Senior Martial Brother Ma couldn’t tell that the beast was playing dead. It was quite a shock.”

Grabbing onto his wounded hand, the cultivator surnamed Ma deeply blushed.

Fortunately at that moment, Senior Martial Brother Wang spoke up for him, “We cannot blame Junior Martial Brother Ma. Even if I had been the one to check, things might’ve ended up the same. It’s just that the Snowcloud Fox was too sly.”

Having heard that, the youth surnamed Ma shot an appreciative glance at Senior Martial Brother Wang and felt much better.

As the three were talking, the youth surnamed Xi suddenly wore an incredulous gaze and suddenly shouted, “Everyone, quickly look! Junior Martial brother Han drilled through the stone wall. Wh-what should we do?”

The others glanced ahead in alarm and discovered that the marsh’s end lie ahead of them. A kilometer ahead of them, there was a mountain so huge that its peak couldn’t be seen. There was a cliff that faced them that had its black walls cut through with a sword.

Furthermore, Han Li was nowhere to be found. The four stood in front of the cliff and glanced inside the opening that had been cut with dumbfounded expressions.

Han Li had truly gone inside the mountain.

At that moment, he was holding a jade scepter with a wolf’s head that enveloped his body in a faint yellow radiance. There was a meter long yellow wolf in front of him that was opening a path with an earth movement technique.

As the artifact spirit continued forward, the earth parted as if there was nothing there. Han Li followed after the wolf with a pensive appearance on his face.

Underneath the scope of his spiritual sese, Ha Li saw the white fox strive its hardest to continue forward as it blurred a hundred meters beneath him.

With his profound abilities, it was only natural for him to see through the Snowcloud Fox’s act. He even saw how the fox took advantage of a stone vein in the shrubbery to slip away.

If this were a common low grade demon beast, Han Li would’ve naturally warned the disciples as a favor. But Han Li was quite surprised to see that when the spirit fox revealed itself, it possessed spiritual Qi fluctuations that felt quite familiar to Han Li.

In his astonishment, he carefully examined it and found that the beast faintly carried the same spiritual Qi fluctuations as the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng’s incarnation, the white rabbit.

Han Li was delighted, believing that he had discovered another incarnation of a spiritual object. But after he examined the white fox once more, he grew somewhat puzzled.

The spiritual Qi fluctuations of the fox were far too small in comparison with the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng. The difference between them could be said to be as wide as heaven and earth. Moreover, upon deeper inspection, he found that the Snowcloud Fox possessed a true flesh body, not that of a spiritual incarnation. Otherwise, the trifling Obscure Track formation wouldn’t have been able to contain it.

Although the small fox wasn’t a spiritual incarnation in the end, Han Li was still deeply curious about it. He was certain that this pure spiritual Qi had something to do with how this ordinary beast was able to turn into a demon beast.

Having decided to investigate this fully, he allowed the fox to escape from the Qi Condensation cultivators and slowly followed after it, wishing to investigate the secrets of the fox.

When the fox had arrived in front of the cliff, it had turned into a ball of white light and blurred into the ground without hesitation. As a result, Han Li summoned the earth attribute artifact spirit from the jade scepter and had the wolf silently open a path. Else, if he were to use a flying sword to cut into a mountain, the fox would be scared away.

The mountain was obviously large. Han Li followed the white fox for at least a kilometer before it stopped, appearing inside what seemed to be a stone room.

Han Li rejoiced and hastily ordered the yellow wolf to hurry and clear a path. At the same time, Han Li increased the power of his spiritual sense and began to examine the inside of the room.

However, as soon as his spiritual sense neared the room, it was repelled by a strange force and he was unable to move it any further.

“Yi!” Han Li shouted out in surprise. His rush came to a stop and he suddenly grew careful.

At that moment, he felt his body grow still and heavy as if it were bearing the weight of Mount Tai itself. He then heard an insipid voice, “Since a guest has come, there is no need to be overly cautious. Don’t tell me that you’re waiting for this elder to invite you in?”

Just as this was said, countless yellow lights began to appear around him as a huge force pushed him forward.

Han Li merely saw a flash of light before he found himself inside the stone room. He was greatly alarmed and instantly waved the jade scepter, covering himself in a red-yellow barrier of light. At the same time, he opened his mouth and spat out a dozen streaks of azure light that hurriedly revolved around him outside the barrier.

It was only after this that Han Li could finally feel secure enough to look around.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 610: Black-clothed Young Woman

Without much effort, Han Li spotted the owner of the voice. About forty meters in front of him, there was a young, black-clothed woman sitting cross-legged on a stone platform.

The woman had a graceful appearance, but her complexion was deathly pale and her luminous eyes seemed to glow with sparkling light. Han Li was shocked to see that one of her sleeves was empty. She was missing an arm.

Before Han Li said anything, the young woman revealed shock upon seeing Han Li release his magic treasures.

The young woman chuckled and her bright eyes stirred. “So it turned out that your esteemed self wasn’t a Qi Condensation Junior, but a Core Formation cultivator. Your Qi Restraint Technique is truly impressive. It even tricked me for a moment.”

As she sat, the Snowcloud Fox was comfortably sitting in her lap and was curiously examining Han Li with an intelligent gaze.

After sweeping his spiritual sense past her, Han Li’s heart trembled. “So it turned out that this was Senior’s hidden cultivation area. I am truly lacking in manners.”

She appeared to be rather open and allowed his spiritual sense to easily sweep past her. He wasn’t able to discover the slightest spiritual Qi fluctuations. From what he had gathered based on her abilities and tone, this indicated that her cultivation was truly too great, not that she had some sort of cultivation concealing treasure.

Han Li grew greatly vigilant.

As Han Li pondered over how to deal with the situation, the young woman raised her flawless pale hand and caressed the Snowcloud Fox. She leisurely said, “It appears that your age is quite young yet you’ve already reached late Core Formation stage. That is quite exceptional.”

Han Li took a deep breath and calmly said, “Senior flatters me. Junior was only able to reach this stage through sheer luck. Might I know Senior’s esteemed name?”

The young woman sighed and said, “My name isn’t anything special. If I said it, you wouldn’t know of it. Let alone you, even this generation’s Nascent Soul cultivators wouldn’t know of it.”

When Han Li heard this, he felt a bitter taste in his mouth. Could it be that this young woman was an old eccentric that had remained isolated in her cultivation?

Although Han Li’s heart grew cold, he didn’t reveal the slightest trace of panic. After all, he now possessed a great number of secret techniques, especially the recently learned Bloodshadow Evasion Technique. With this, Han Li no longer held much fear towards Nascent Soul cultivators. Of course, Han Li knew he’d be no match for one in a fight, but he was confident he could escape. However, the aftermath of igniting a large quantity of blood essence would force him to remain in secluded cultivation for many years.

That being said, Han Li had no idea why this mysterious character had hidden herself beneath the three sects. Was it because she had some sort of plot in mind, or was she like himself, only wishing to cultivate in a place with dense spiritual Qi?

Han Li swept his gaze around the stone room and astonishedly discovered that this room inside the mountain was sealed, and lacked any doors or passageways. Additionally, apart from the stone platform that the young woman was sitting on, there wasn’t any other furniture. The room’s emptiness gave an extremely icy impression.

Han Li also discovered that the room’s walls were extremely crude, unlike the common clean cuts of a blade. Rather, these uneven surfaces seemed to come from the wanton swings of a huge axe.

As soon as he saw this, a strange expression flickered in his eyes. As if having seen through Han Li’s confusion, the young woman suddenly smiled and said, “Since Fellow Daoist is puzzled, why not touch the stone walls and dispel your doubts?”

When Han Li heard this, his heart stirred. He was truly curious. His recent scan with his spiritual sense discovered nothing strange. The room’s walls appeared no different than ordinary stone. “Since Senior has raised the topic, I won’t be restraining myself.”

He slowly reached his left hand towards the stone wall. But to be careful, Han Li continued to observe the young woman with his spiritual sense, fearing she would launch an attack out of greed. Although she hadn’t shown any malice, Han Li had lived through many years of hardship and had grown to become extremely careful.

When Han Li felt the stone wall, he noticed nothing strange. Then after some thought, he extended his finger and had a streak of azure swordlight emerge from the tip of his finger.

Han Li stabbed his finger into the wall and shockingly discovered that the stone wall had completely blocked the attack. All that had resulted was a crackle when the light touched the wall.

Han Li was dumbstruck, but at the same time, a trace of disbelief arose in his mind. His spiritual power surged as he suddenly struck the stone wall with a foot long swordstreak.

As a result, the wall remained completely unharmed without even the slightest scratch.

Han Li remained silent as an odd expression flickered across his face. He then pointed to one of his flying swords and had it strike the wall as an azure streak. Afterwards, it flew back with a clear ring.

The strike had left an inch deep cut but the wall started to slowly smooth itself. After a short moment, the cut had disappeared without a trace.

Han Li gasped in shock and couldn’t help but turn his head towards her, asking, “What is this? How can it restore itself? Could it be that Senior placed it under the influence of a restriction or spell?”

The young woman indifferently said, “Spells? Restrictions? You think too highly of me; this is merely Lapis Stone. Also known as Spirit Absorbing Stone, it is an incredibly rare tool refinement material. It is impervious to the spiritual power of magic techniques and treasures, and only great strength can harm it.”

Han Li faintly frowned and turned back towards the stone wall. He slowly said, “Lapis Stone? This Junior is quite inexperienced and ignorant. I haven’t heard of such a material before.”

The young woman casually explained, “Hehe, it is natural for Fellow Daoist to not hear of this material. This material was incredibly rare even during the era of antiquity, and there aren’t many that presently know of it.”

When Han Li heard this, he was flabbergasted. Just as he thought to say something else, the young woman sweetly smiled and interrupted him, “Although Fellow Daoist’s cultivation is nearing the false Nascent stage, your aptitude seems inferior. No, it would be better to say that it is terrible. It seems you’ve come across fateful encounters to be able to reach this stage of cultivation. Otherwise, your greatest efforts would’ve only taken you to the Foundation Establishment stage. Meeting me could also be considered an act of fate. If you don’t find the idea undesirable, this elder has a treasure that I can lend to you.”

As soon as Han Li heard her, he revealed a odd expression, “Lend this Junior a treasure?”

As if seeing through Han Li’s suspicions, her expression sunk and she coldly said, “Of course, there will be conditions. First, this item will only be lent. You will have to return it. Secondly, after taking the treasure, there is something you must carry out on my behalf as payment for it.”

She rummaged through her robes for a moment before taking out a jade box in her hand.

The jade box was pitch-black and only the size of a fist. Its exterior was incredibly rough and crude, but there was a trace of yellow within the black. It seemed to be incredibly old.

Han Li glanced at the young woman’s face before turning his gaze back to the black case. Still silent, his expression fluctuated for a moment as he pondered for a moment. He then gravely asked, “Could Senior first tell this Junior what is inside the box before he decides?”

Upon seeing Han Li’s hesitation, the black-clothed woman revealed a trace of impatience. With her brow raised, she pointed at the black box and said, “Surely you must know what a spirit well is. This box happens to hold a spirit well stone of the highest rank, known as a jade spirit well. At the very least, its spiritual Qi should allow you to further stabilize your cultivation at the false Nascent stage. It will allow you to condense a Nascent Soul with greater ease. This treasure has been with me for many years. If not for my current cultivation and my current inability to further use it, I wouldn’t be lending it to you.”

With that said, she stroked the black jade box with a reluctant expression.

“Jade spirit well!” Han Li’s expression changed several times. This would cut down the time it would take for him to reach false Nascent stage by two-thirds! He completely swallowed his original words to reject her.

After some hesitation, Han Li sighed and said, “Might I ask what Senior would like Junior to do? If you can’t do something with your current cultivation, how could I possibly help you?!”

The young woman revealed an expression of joy seeing that Han Li was willing to agree. “Be at ease! I’m not asking you to kill someone. I’m only asking you to run errands. Although my cultivation is great, I cannot depart from this room for a certain reason. I only want you to deliver a letter for me.”

“You only wish for me to deliver a letter?” This was completely beyond his expectations.

“Of course. Did you really believe that I’d have you kill someone?” The black-clothed woman covered her smile, revealing an overwhelming allure.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 611: A Golden Talisman

When Han Li heard this, he faintly blushed.

“If it’s only to deliver a letter, Junior is willing to accept.” It was only natural for him to accept such a trivial task, considering the reward.

The young woman seemed rather happy and raised her hand without another word. The box was wrapped in a green light and smoothly flew over to Han Li.

Han Li received the black box and swept his spiritual sense over it. The spiritual Qi within the box was truly abundant as if it really contained a jade spirit well. Of course, given Han Li’s cautious nature, he wanted to personally examine what was inside the box.

With a flash of azure light from his hand, the black box opened by itself to reveal a dense, white mist of extremely pure spiritual Qi, flooding the stone room in an instant.

Han Li’s heart stirred and he examined the inside of the box with suspicion.

He only saw a gentle white light that emitted from a sparkling white jade stone only several inches long.

Han Li was left startled not by the stone itself, but by the thumb-sized cow inside the transparent stone that was continuously wagging its tail as if it were alive.

When the young woman saw Han Li’s shock, a peculiar expression flickered from her bright eyes. She casually smiled and asked, “What’s the matter? This jade spirit well had quickly nurtured a treasure incarnation. Common spirit well stones are incomparable to it. If you were to cultivate with this, you would achieve twice the results with half the effort.”

After taking another glance at the jade spirit well inside the box, he eventually closed it and calmly raised his head. “Right. With this item, Junior would only spend about a dozen years to reach false Nascent stage instead of several tens.”

At that moment, Han Li had finally realized that the Jadecloud Fox had been stained by the jade spirit well’s spiritual Qi. That was why it had possessed such a faint, pure spiritual Qi. It was quite possible that its transformation into a demon had something to do with the spirit well.

Han Li’s regained calm somewhat surprised the young woman. She couldn’t help but take another glance at him in her astonishment.

After drawing away a loose hair from her forehead, she casually said with an insipid voice, “Alright, since I’ve already given this item to you, I’ll be giving you the jade slip to deliver as well. There is also another jade box below on the platform I am sitting on. Tear off the talisman that seals it and hand it to me. There is a token in the box that I want you to deliver with it.”

“You want Junior to take it for you?” Han Li revealed suspicion and grew vigilant.

“Humph! Still afraid this old woman means you harm? If I could grab it myself, would I ask you to do it?” The young woman resentfully smiled and lifted up her long robes with her hand.

Han Li’s expression greatly changed upon seeing her legs. They were shriveled like firewood as they were crossed together. There wasn’t the slightest flesh apart from some dried up skin. It made for a rather fearsome appearance. But what surprised Han Li even more was the several silver sparkling chains that penetrated her legs that deeply bore into the stone platform..

Han Li pursed his lips and raised his head to look at the young woman. Although his face appeared completely bewildered, he didn’t ask anything further. He knew that the woman was certain to offer the explanation.

As a result, the woman’s face grew icy and she placed her robes back down. She dryly said, “I am in this stone mountain for the Lapis Stone. I had a room of it and then I used the two chains to restrict my legs and trap myself here.”

“You trapped yourself?” Han Li was entirely confused by this.

“That’s right. My cultivation art is the Underworldly Slaughter Arts. Although the cultivation art is incredibly fast and its might is extraordinary, it has a fatal flaw. Once it is completed, the cultivator will easily lose their human nature and become bloodthirsty. Back then, I had a fateful encounter with this technique and decided to cultivate it despite the advice of others; I had been extremely confident of my exceptionally powerful spiritual sense. After I successively cultivated this technique and entered Nascent Soul stage, I was no longer able to restrain my urge to kill and swept through the cultivation world at the time in a massive storm, resulting in no small number of enemies. As a result, I finally tangled in a battle with several Nascent Soul cultivators, resulting in the loss of my arm.”

The young woman expressionlessly glanced at her vacant arm and shook her head.

“After receiving this injury, I thought long and hard. If I had no way to control myself then I would die sooner or later. As a result, I steeled my resolve and asked my dear friends to forge the Divine Heavenfire Chains and the room of Lapis Stone to imprison me. Due to fear I wouldn’t be able to tolerate the loneliness or would suddenly become regretful, I gave the key to the chains to my best friend. They made a promise that they would come visit me every so often to see whether or not I’ve gotten better so that they may release me.”

After that was said, the young woman’s expression grew sullen.

“But I didn’t expect that after coming only a few times, my good friend would suddenly disappear without a single word. I don’t know whether or not they became impatient or if something unexpected happened to them. As such, I’ve been imprisoned here until now. Because this room was refined from Lapis Stone, my spiritual sense is only able to reach out about a kilometer, despite having already reached the mid Nascent Soul stage. I wished to call for help, but I lacked any method to. These Divine Heavenfire Chains were refined through a very peculiar method, connecting them to my primal soul. Although my cultivation has greatly increased and I am able to break the chains, I will instantly die from doing so. Now that destiny has had us meet, it seems the Heavens have heard my plea. I no longer have to waste the rest of my life in this stone room.”

The black-clothed woman gave a general explanation of her past to dispel Han Li’s suspicions.

However, the story left Han Li dumbstruck. If she spoke truly, then her past must’ve truly been unfathomable.

After a moment of deliberation, he hesitantly asked, “Could it be that Senior wishes for Junior to deliver a letter to your best friend? With so many years having passed, it wouldn’t be unlikely for your friend to have passed on!”

The young woman sighed and bitterly smiled, “That’s right. Even if that’s the case, there is no need to be worried. I just ask that you to bring the key for the Divine Heavenfire Chains. We were on good terms. If anything had happened, they should’ve passed it on to their descendants for safekeeping. It’ll be the same if you found their descendants instead.”

After a moment more of thought, Han Li found this to be reasonable and that there were no gaps in logic. As a result, he stepped forward without speaking any useless words and circled around the stone platform to find a hole.

Han Li carefully probed it with his spiritual sense and he raised his brows. He reached in to find a jade box.

The jade box had an antique style and was a faint yellow with odd flames engraved on it. The silhouette of a person could be seen standing within those flames as if they were roaring towards the Heavens.

There was also a flickering golden talisman on the jade box that faintly emitted an aura that caused Han Li to feel uneasy. He unconsciously frowned.

The black-clothed woman couldn’t help but grow excited and said, “That’s the box! Fellow Daoist, tear off the talisman and let me look at it.”

Han Li had already placed his hand on the jade case and was about to tear the talisman off. However, when he the young woman’s voice trembled in uncontainable excitement, Han Li felt an indescribable feeling of dread.

After a moment of hesitation, Han Li withdrew his hand from the box and raised his head instead. Han Li’s heart thumped upon seeing her.

Her eyes had changed into a dark green and her appearance had become warped. A fearsome, menacing guise had completely replaced her previously dignified air.

When the young woman saw Han Li raise his head, she was startled and regained her awareness. Her warped appearance and green eyes disappeared in an instant. She said in a relaxed tone, “Fellow Daoist, why are you looking at me? Why haven’t you torn off that talisman? Don’t forget, the jade spirit well is a treasure rarely seen in this world and I’ve already given it to you. Why are you still hesitating?”

Han Li glanced at the black-clothed young woman and looked down at the golden talisman tightly sealing the jade box. Without saying anything further, he narrowed his eyes and slowly walked towards her with the jade box in hand.

“Fellow Daoist, what are you going? Stop! Don’t come closer!” When the woman saw Han Li walking over with the golden talisman still on the jade box, her expression immediately changed and she began to shout with a panicked expression.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 612: Cadaver Demon

When Han Li saw the young woman’s reaction, his expression immediately became gloomy and a cold glint appeared in his eyes. He wordlessly raised the box as he approached her.

Although he didn’t know why she was so scared of this talisman, he knew she wasn't harboring any good intentions toward him, and he decided to drop any formalities.

The black-clothed young woman had completely lost her mind to fear as he approached and instantly slapped the stone platform beneath her to launch herself away. However, this action activated some sort of restriction. Just as she reached three meters away, red light enveloped her and brought her back to her original position.

At that moment, the jade box flew out of Han Li’s grasp and released a series of clear rings as it flew towards the woman’s head. The golden talisman on the box flourished with radiance and released countless golden talisman characters that slowly floated down towards the young woman.

“NO!” The black-clothed woman shouted in despair. Her beautiful appearance warped in an instant. She quickly used her sole arm to cover her face and dropped her head down to her chest, desperately trying to keep her face away from the talisman.

As the golden talisman characters finally dropped down to the young woman’s shoulder, golden light sparked and released a wisp of green smoke.

The young woman’s body greatly trembled as she released a monstrous wail of anguish. The wail was deafeningly sharp and inhuman, much to Han Li’s shock. He unconsciously took several steps back and he felt cold sweat line his palm. In one hand he tightly grabbed onto his spirit beast pouch with the Gold Devouring Beetles and tightly clutched onto the jade scepter with the other as he solemnly stared at the stone platform.

As further talisman characters fell onto the black-clothed young woman, even more green smoke began to surge from her body. After a short moment, the green smoke had enveloped her. Her body could no longer be seen, but the flashes of light and wails never ceased. In a moment, the wails became screeching; in another, they became frantically hoarse. The sudden and unceasing transformations of the monstrous wails were awful to behold.

As Han Li watched in apprehension, he held his breath and pursed his lips. A fishy scent had filled the room as soon as the green smoke appeared. Each breath of it immediately caused him to feel a wave of dizziness and nausea, much to his surprise. The smoke seemed to be extremely poisonous.

Soon after, cracks began to sound out from within the green smoke.

Han Li was startled. Before he realized what those sounds were, he heard a swish of wind.

A dark green claw that was tangled in silver chains suddenly extended from the mist at the speed of lightning and fiercely swiped towards Han Li at the corner of the room. The claw was as flexible as a snake, suddenly bending and reaching out ten meters towards Han Li trying to grab him.

Han Li trembled and his grip tightened on the jade scepter. Just as he thought to execute a technique, the silver chains suddenly restrained the ghostly claws in a storm of sparks, filling the room with a scorched stench.

A painful moan roared from within the smoke and the sharp claw quickly withdrew.

Han Li stared into the mist with tightly shut lips, his expression continuously fluctuating. After some consideration, Han Li’s expression grew sullen and he drew back with two additional steps. With the Lapis Stone wall close against his back, he poured a great amount of spiritual energy into the jade scepter, thickening the red-yellow light barrier around his body and causing him to feel somewhat more at ease.

After the time it took to brew a cup of tea, yet another monstrous scream left the mist, and the radiance of the jade box’s golden talisman gradually dimmed. The amount of talisman characters it produced had also started to grow sparse.

With all that he had seen, Han Li mused, ‘It seems the golden talisman is capable of restraining either ghosts or demons, but it has a rather limited amount of spiritual Qi. It will eventually expire and will no longer be able to restrain her.”

Fortunately, Han Li’s worries were unfounded.

In the following moment, the final scream faded away and the smoke had grown still. However, the golden talisman’s light had yet to fade away.

Han Li glanced at the golden talisman and didn’t immediately approach it. Instead, he waited for a moment more. After the golden light faded away and the jade box fell into the dense smoke, Han Li’s expression began to stir.

He waved his arm and put away the spirit beast pouch for the time being. He then formed an incantation seal with the newly freed hand and began to mutter something in a low voice. In the following instant, a red, egg-sized fireball appear in front of him.

After taking a glance at the fireball, Han Li pointed into the smoke and the fireball flew into the green smoke as a streak of red light. He raised his brows and uttered, “Explode.”

Boom! The smoke was swept up in a gale and was scattered in an instant, only to be replaced with a burnt stench.

As expected, fire attribute techniques were the most effective means of dealing with poisonous Qi.

Han Li stood in place as he felt hot winds blow against him. A strange expression stirred in his eyes as he stared at the stone platform while the smoke cleared away. When he eventually saw what was there, he felt his heart jump and he dryly swallowed as a shiver went down his spine.

There was a human-shaped silhouette on the platform that remained still, and it was unknown whether it was still alive.

Although it could be said to be human-shaped, there was dense green fur covering its body. Additionally, it smelled very much like a rotting corpse.

Although he didn’t see what it truly was, it was absolutely not human.

Like its human form, it had only one arm, but this arm was much longer and had pitch-black claws. This was clearly what had attacked Han Li earlier.

What was even more notable were the many chains that wrapped around its body. Not only did they bind its legs and arm, but it also pierced through its chest and back. It had been entirely restrained.

Without much further thought, Han Li pointed to his flying swords and had them pierce into the monster.

As a result, a series of muffled clangs sounded out. The green fur had repelled them without harm.

Han Li wryly smirked, but he didn’t feel particularly surprised. Given what heavy restrictions the monster was subjected to, Han Li would’ve been somewhat astonished if that had actually cleaved off its head. It couldn’t have possibly been that simple.

Han Li waved to the swords and had them fly back towards him. He then took a few steps forward and lightly flung his sleeve towards the green haired monster. At that moment, an azure mist of light shot out form Han Li’s sleeve and gently enveloped the monster, resulting in it dropping to the floor with its true appearance revealed.

With its hair parted, it was revealed to have only skin and bone as if it were a dried up skeleton. Its half open mouth had a pair of inch long fangs emerging from it, making for a frightful appearance.

“This is...” Han Li glanced at the green fur on the body and took another look at its face. It faintly felt familiar as if he had seen it before in a jade slip.

After lowering his head in contemplation, its name suddenly appeared in his head. He couldn’t help but raise his head and frightfully shout, “Cadaver Demon!” He suddenly recalled the fearsome legends of this vicious spirit from times of antiquity.

“Cadaver Demons” were a type of Jiangshi. However, it was greatly different from cultivator refined corpses and ordinary Jiangshi that naturally rose from deep within the earth. It only appeared under extremely rare and specific circumstances.

Although no one knew of the method by which this fearsome spirit took form, there were two main conditions that a Cadaver Corpse required to take form.

First, there must be a corpse of a Nascent Soul cultivator at the very least. Corpses of mortals and inferior cultivators weren’t sufficient for a cadaver demon to form. Secondly, the corpse must have heavenly spirit roots that are either wood or earth attribute. Otherwise, it wouldn’t be able to draw support from nature to rise once more.

In addition to this, the cultivator must’ve died harboring immense grievances. With the soul unwilling to return to the path of reincarnation, it is retained by the corpse. As time passed by with some other unknown conditions fulfilled, the soul and corpse would fuse together to form the monster known as a Cadaver Demon.

The monster could be said to be half human and half Jiangshi as well as half Jiangshi and half ghost.

Not only did it lack the fatal weakness of sunlight that ghost demons and Jiangshi possessed, but it also possessed most of its memories and techniques from when it was alive. And because it died harboring grievances, this fearsome spirit was undoubtedly bloodthirsty. They were particularly fond of hunting down cultivators and slowly torturing their souls with corpsefire for their amusement as they feasted on them.

It had been ages since the last Cadaver Demon had appeared in the cultivation world.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 617: Return

“Alright, I’ll do as you said. But how will Brother Han handle this Cadaver Demon?” The white fox spoke to Han Li through a voice transmission.

Han Li took a look at the green haired Cadaver Demon and casually said, “First, I’ll see whether or not the Gold Devouring Beetles can destroy it. If that isn’t possible, then there is nothing that can be done. We’ll just leave it alone. Besides, regardless of the outcome I’ll be taking the jade box that has its main soul. It won’t be able to cause any major problems later on.”

He then slapped his waist and launched the Spirit Beast Pouch into the air, releasing countless black-tainted Gold Devouring Beetles to surround the Cadaver Demon.

Sounds of the beetle’s gnawing spread throughout the room, but soon, Han Li saw a portion of the Gold Devouring Beetles suddenly fall onto their backs and die. Their tri-colored shell turned dark-green in an instant.

“What fearsome poison!” Han Li muttered with a faint scowl. After a moment of hesitation, he had the flying beetles return to his spirit beast pouch.

The white fox pondered for a long moment and said, “The Cadaver Demon’s rotting poison might not be among the ten deadliest poisons in the land, but it isn’t something that your incomplete Gold Devouring Beetles are capable of enduring.”

Han Li snorted and frowned as he coldly glanced at the Cadaver Demon.

The monster’s body was extremely durable, far beyond that of the Venomous Flood Dragon. He reckoned that if he were to destroy the Cadaver Demon, it would cause a majority of his black-tainted Gold Devouring Beetles to perish. There was no way Han Li would suffer such a loss over a fruitless matter.

“Let’s go.” Han Li spoke without the slightest hesitation.

The white fox nodded her head and said, “That does seem to be the only choice. Perhaps there will be a later use for the Cadaver Demon!”

With that said, a strange light glowed from the white fox and a yellow wolf head emerged from its body. As soon as the yellow wolf appeared, it opened its mouth wide and enveloped them both in yellow light. Afterwards, Han Li and the white fox disappeared from the room.

Senior Martial Brother Wang and the other three Qi Condensation cultivators were anxiously standing outside of the cliff. With none of them capable of using earth movement techniques, they could only wait for Han Li to return.

Kui Huan grew impatient and asked, “Senior Martial Brother, do you think Junior Martial Brother Han succeeded?”

When the other two heard him they attentively looked at Senior Martial Brother Wang. He wryly smiled and said, “It’s hard to say. With Junior Martial Brother Han’s tenth layer cultivation, it shouldn’t have been easy for him to chase after the demon fox. However, Junior Martial Brother Han does possess an impressive magic tool. Perhaps he’ll be able to give us a pleasant surprise, but either result shouldn’t come as a shock.”

When the other three heard this, they couldn’t help but look at each other in dismay.

The short, stout youth sighed and shook his injured hand. When he thought to say something further, a yellow light suddenly flashed from the cliff to reveal Han Li with a small fox in his grasp.

“Junior Martial Brother Han!”

“You truly managed to capture the fox!”

All four of the cultivators began to speak with expressions of excitement.

Han Li chuckled and said, “It wasn’t much. The fox was quite cunning and circled several times within the mountain. Had it not exhausted its spiritual power, I fear I wouldn’t have been able to capture it so quickly.” He then tossed the white fox towards Kui Huan.

Kui Huan was stunned for a moment before excitedly catching it.

The short, stout youth hurriedly warned, “Junior Martial Brother Kui, be careful! Don’t let it run away!”

Kui Huan lifted the white fox and replied, “Don’t worry! I’ll be very careful.” Afterwards, he slapped his storage pouch and took out a dark-green bag before quickly slipping the small fox inside.

Kui Huan quickly tied the pouch closed and proudly said, “Hehe! How will you escape from this pouch, little fox?”

Han Li took a look at the small pouch, but after seeing that it was only a low grade spirit tool, he paid it no further heed.

Senior Martial Brother Wang didn’t pay any further attention to the small fox in the pouch. He instead faced Han Li and cordially said, “We were only able to capture the demon fox in great thanks to Junior Martial Brother Han. Since we aren’t an unscrupulous sort, we’ll give Junior Brother Han a third of whatever the fox will fetch us. As for the rest, we’ll split it evenly among us four. How does that sound?”

Han Li smiled in response. From Senior Martial Brother Wang’s skilled display, it seemed he truly wished to form a relationship with Han Li. As a result, Han Li nodded his head and agreed without any reservations, “Since Brother Wang has made up his mind, I have no complaints.”

Although the other three felt somewhat reluctant to receive fewer spirit stones, they all knew that if it weren’t for Han Li’s assistance they would’ve ended up wasting their efforts. As such, no one raised any objections.

In the following moments, Han Li shared a few pleasantries with the others before excusing himself on the pretenses of having a pressing matter at hand.

With Han Li heading back to the sect the other four decided to strike while the iron was hot and head straight to the market city at the center of the Dreamcloud Mountains. Since that was where the disciples of the three sects mingled the most, they reckoned they would fetch the highest price for the Snowcloud Fox there.

The four then departed from the marsh in high spirits.

Han Li didn’t travel far before casually finding a small mountain nearby. He dropped down and sat cross legged on a flat rock before closing his eyes. He had the jade scepter on hand, allowing the white fox to find him when the time came.

About an hour later, Han Li’s expression stirred and he opened his eyes. At nearly the same time, a yellow light emerged from the earth revealing the white fox.

Han Li looked at the white fox and indifferently said, “Well aren’t you fast?”

The white fox raised its head and chuckled, “It isn’t that I’m fast. It’s just that they underestimated me by using a low grade spirit tool to contain me. I fear they still haven’t discovered that I’ve disappeared.”

Han Li expressionlessly said, “But now those Drifting Cloud Sect disciples will have made a wasted effort. When the time comes, I should give them a bit of compensation!”

The white fox shook its head and said, “If that’s the case, they will have profited from this disaster.”

“Alright, let’s cut the rubbish. Shrink yourself and hide in my sleeve for the time being. We’re going to return.” Han Li then shook his sleeve.

When the white fox heard him, she wordlessly shrunk herself in a glimmer of silver light and flew into Han Li’s sleeve as a white blur.

Because of the restrictions that Han Li had placed on the white fox’s body, he had no fear of any sinister designs the white fox may hold, allowing him to confidently fly back.

Instead of returning to his cave residence, he first dropped down into the market city at the main mountain of the Drifting Cloud Sect. They should have the materials he needed to shift the housing of the artifact spirit.

He needed to hurry up and make preparations for his return. Each passing day that Silvermoon remained as a loose artifact spirit was a day that he felt uneasy.

Han Li was able to purchase the ingredients without problem. He easily found a store dealing with materials and purchased them all in one go. Although these materials were uncommon, they weren’t particularly rare or precious. As a result, no one has asked him what he was using them for.

With both the materials and white fox on hand, Han Li flew back to the medicine garden with satisfaction. But just as he arrived at the medicine garden, there were two people standing outside the restrictions.

One of them was Kui Huan who was sighing with an appearance of nervousness. The other person was a sullen-faced Senior Martial Brother Wang.

When Han Li saw them, he inwardly sighed. He obviously knew why they were here. However, Han Li landed near them with an expression of ignorance.

When they saw that Han Li had returned, they glanced at each other and wore embarrassed expressions.

Han Li stepped forward and calmly asked, “Fellow Daoists, why have you returned so quickly? Have you already sold the Snowcloud Fox?”

After a moment of hesitation, Senior Martial Brother Wang wryly smiled and said, “We... I’m afraid we’ve let Brother Han down.”

Han Li stroked his chin and asked, “Oh, what happened? Was there an incident with the Snowcloud Fox?”

Kui Huan opened his eyes wide and bewilderedly asked, “Junior Martial Brother Han, how did you know?!”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 618: Sword Trial Assembly

Han Li faintly smiled when he heard Kui Huan and calmly said, “The only thing that we have together is a business interest in the demon fox. What else would bring you here?”

When Kui Huan heard this, he opened his mouth but was left at a loss for words. At his side, Senior Martial Brother Wang sighed and said, “Junior Martial Brother Han is clearly an intelligent person. It is true that something has gone wrong with the Snowcloud Fox. We wished to sell the demon fox as soon as possible and headed straight to a market city when we departed. But not long after we left, I grew somewhat ill at ease and had Junior Martial Brother Kui open the bag to let me examine the fox. As a result...”

With that said, Senior Martial Brother Wang paused, revealing a strange expression.

Vexed, Kui Huan hurriedly finished for him, “As a result, we discovered that the demon fox had somehow managed to escape without a trace. It was truly inconceivable.”

“It disappeared without a trace?” Han Li frowned as if he was wondering about the truth behind those words.

When Senior Martial Brother Wang saw Han Li’s expression, he inwardly cursed without end.

Although Han Li’s cultivation wasn't high, he was skilled in talisman refinement and possessed a powerful magic tool. With that in mind, Senior Martial Brother Wang had planned on properly forming a relationship with him. However, he didn't anticipate such an embarrassing affair to occur before he could formally establish a friendship.

It would be fine if he were wealthy. He’d be able to easily solve this by just using his own spirit stones and leave a good impression with Han Li. But as it so happened, he along with his fellow group members were lacking spirit stones making it extremely difficult to win Han Li over.

With that thought, Senior Martial Brother Wang forcefully mustered himself out of his dejection saying, “I know that this matter is hard to believe, but it really did happen. Regardless of how it’s said, Junior Martial Brother did personally hand over the demon fox to us, but now I must take responsibility for its disappearance. I’ve already sent my Junior Martial Brothers to sell off the Huangjing to repay the spirit stones we borrowed from you, and we’ll have that for you soon. As for Junior Martial Brother’s rightful share of spirit stones, we will make up for it as soon as we can.”

Just as soon as Kui Huan heard this, his expression changed and he nervously said, “Senior Martial Brother, that is no small sum of spirit stones. Even if we were to pool together all we have, it would take at least three years to gather together that many spirit stones. It will slow down our cultivation if we cannot purchase any medicine pills during that time.”

Senior Martial Brother Wang shook his head and was about to say something when Han Li interrupted him with a smile, “There is no need for Senior Martial Brother to be like this! I believe you. The Snowcloud Fox was rather proficient in movement techniques so it’s no surprise that it was able to escape from the leather bag magic tool. I had originally thought to give a word of warning to Brother Kui, but at the time I found it to be somewhat inappropriate and stayed quiet. As for my share of the spirit stones, let’s just drop it. It’ll be fine if you just return the spirit stones that you borrowed. With that I won’t consider myself to have suffered a loss.”

When Kui Huan heard that he didn't have to give any spirit stones, he was greatly delighted and slapped his hands together saying, “I knew that Junior Martial Brother Han was a magnanimous person. Although it was our fault, we truly don’t possess the spirit stones to compensate you. And with Junior Martial Brother’s wealth, he shouldn’t mind such a small amount too greatly. I, Kui Huan, will always look upon you as a friend.”

When Senior Martial Brother Wang heard Han Li, he revealed some hesitation. A moment later, he helplessly smiled and said, “On behalf of my Junior Martial Brothers, I accept Junior Martial Brother Han’s generosity despite our shameful display. If you ever require any assistance in the future, please don’t hesitate to find us. So long as it is possible, I will not refuse you.”

Senior Martial Brother Wang felt that while Han Li’s words were polite, he feared that Han Li harbored different thoughts entirely. As a result, he strived his hardest to choose his words carefully to leave behind the best impression possible. Having said that, he then particularly paid attention to Han Li’s expression.

However, Senior Martial Brother Wang inwardly frowned since he wasn’t able to make out any of Han Li’s emotions.

The three had a chat outside the garden, but soon the other two Qi Condensation cultivators in their party arrived with the spirit stones they had acquired from reselling the Huangjing.

Han Li received the pouch of spirit stones and casually swept his spiritual sense through it before calmly putting it away.

After seeing Han Li receive the spirit stones, Senior Martial Brother Wang suddenly recalled something and asked, “Ah, that’s right. Junior Martial Brother’s magic tool is rather impressive. Will you be taking part in the Sword Trial Assembly later this year?”

Han Li couldn’t help but reply with an odd expression, “The Sword Trial Assembly?”

“What? Does Junior Martial Brother Han not know of it?”

Not only was Senior Martial Brother Wang surprised, but the other three seemed to find this hard to believe as well.

Han Li inwardly muttered to himself and calmly replied, “Is it strange that I don’t know of it?”

Kui Huan blinked and suddenly recalled something, “Of course it is. Oh, that’s right. This is Junior Martial Brother’s first year in the sect and he was staying in the medicine garden all this time. It makes sense that you don’t know of the Sword Trial Assembly.”

When the others heard this, they glanced at one another and nodded their heads, accepting this as the truth.

Senior Martial Brother Wang wore a strange expression and said, “We were greatly shocked when we heard that Junior Martial Brother Han didn’t know about the Sword Trial Assembly. After all, it is starting soon and all disciples within the sect are talking about, even the external affair disciples. Those that wish to prove their mettle are eagerly waiting in anticipation.”

The short, stout youth glanced at Senior Martial Brother Wang with admiration and said, “With that said, the only one in our group to participate in the contest of might will be Senior Martial Brother Wang. However, it is a pity that while Senior Martial Brother may prevail against external affair disciples, he will eventually be defeated when facing inner sect disciples. But even with this, Senior Martial Brother should still receive a mid grade magic tool as a reward.”

When Han Li heard this, he wore a curious expression and said, “Oh, so it is a contest of superiority within the sect. It seems that it is quite unordinary. Could Senior Martial Brother explain a few of the finer details?”

Senior Martial Brother Wang glanced at Han Li and slowly said, “Of course. The Sword Trial Assembly is actually for showing off newly joined disciples. Regardless of one’s identity, so long as they are a newly accepted disciple that isn’t over the age of thirty, one can participate. As for you, Junior Martial Brother Han, you still appear to be in your mid twenties and you’ve just entered the sect. You happen to meet the requirements.”

Han Li rubbed his chin and slowly said, “Is that so? It seems that there aren’t many disciples that can partake in the contest.”

“Junior Martial Brother’s words hold somewhat true, but the Sword Trial Assembly actually has much to do with a sacred tree that the three sects are overseeing.”

“A sacred tree?” When Han Li heard this, he was stunned and realized that they were talking about Dreamcloud Mountain’s spirit well tree. His initially careless expression was quickly replaced with a solemn one.

Han Li seriously asked, “What does the Sword Trial Assembly have to do with the sacred tree?”

“The Sword Trial Assembly takes place several days before sacred tree starts to shed Wine Nectar. The three sects use this competition to decide who receives half of the shedded Wine Nectar, leaving the remaining half to be split between the two other sects. As a result, while this assembly can only be participated by young, new disciples, it is viewed with great importance among the three sects. If one achieves great merits in the assembly, one will attract the attention of the sect elders and acquire countless benefits.”

Senior Martial Brother Wang sighed and paused for a moment before solemnly continuing, “Of course, beside those benefits, one is also heavily rewarded at the end for how many other disciples they are able to suppress. Not only were many disciples rewarded with top grade magic tools in the past, there were also a few disciples that were rewarded with a Spirit Tempering Pill. Although this medicine pill isn’t very useful for low grade disciples, there are many Core Formation experts that are more than willing to exchange them for at least four top grade magic tools. However, this assembly has almost always been dominated by the Ancient Sword Sect, leaving our sect and the Hundred Possibilities Sect to take second and third place. However, this comes as no surprise. With their incisive magic tools and techniques, the disciples of the Ancient Sword Sect make for incredibly difficult opponents for cultivators of the same grade.”

Senior Martial Brother Wang’s final words seemed to be full of both admiration and complaints.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 620: An Unexpected Encounter

As Han Li remained silent, Silvermoon asked yet another question, “I never clearly understood why Brother Han wishes to acquire the Brightsight Water even though it has no effect on cultivators beyond Foundation Establishment stage.”

When Han Li heard this, he faintly smirked and said, “The Hidden Sword Mountain cultivators were mistaken. It isn’t that the Brightsight Water has no effect on high grade cultivators. It’s that high grade cultivators have already cleansed their body’s essence upon forming their core. Their eyes can already see through simple illusion techniques and dense fog, so there isn’t much to be gained from cleansing them such a small amount. Since the amount of spirit water wouldn’t be enough to be effective for a high grade cultivator, it’s better for a low grade cultivator to use it.”

Silvermoon yelped in surprise, “Yi! How does Brother Han know about this?”

“When I was originally in the Scattered Star Seas, I read it in an ancient book. It shouldn’t be false.”

“Could it be that Brother Han has a plan in mind?”

“That’s right. I plan on using this opportunity to draw close to the Spirit Well Tree, and see whether or not I can take some of its roots. I’ll be able to mature the roots with my small bottle if I get ahold of them and could acquire countless Spirit Tempering Pills and limitless Brightsight Water. Of course, I’ll have to acquire the recipes some other way.”

“Hehe, Brother Han’s methods are truly long sighted. In that case, you’ll only need to place in the top ten. Although it will be quite attention-grabbing, it will be far safer than placing first.”

Han Li smiled and thought to say something else when he swept his gaze across and unconsciously gasped as he slowed to a stop.

In the distance, he spotted a red streak of light that enveloped a beautiful woman with an expression as cold as frost. It was the woman surnamed Mu who had assigned him to the medicine garden.

When the woman drew closer and spotted Han Li, she also wore an expression of surprise. She soon slowed down and stopped at Han Li’s side.

“Did you also receive a message to go to Dayspring Mountain?” The woman indifferently said.

Han Li replied with a calm expression, “I did, Martial Aunt Mu! Would Martial Aunt happen to know what happened or why the mountain lord has summoned all of us disciples?”

“I don’t know, but it should be related to the Sword Trial Assembly.” Mu Peiling curtly replied. Afterwards, she glanced at the flying sword beneath Han Li and frowned, “Although your magic tool is high grade, it isn’t specialized for flight. How about I use the Daystar Belt to bring you along? It will save time.” With that said, the woman enveloped Han Li in the magic tool’s red light without even waiting for his reply.

Han Li was initially surprised, but he had no intention of refusing her offer. As such, he was drawn into her magic tool’s red light and was brought along.

As they flew, the woman swept her gaze over Han Li and expressionlessly said, “Did you cultivate the Profound Ice Arts that I gave you? Although cultivating this technique won’t greatly increase your base cultivation, it will allow you to use powerful water attribute magic techniques. If you reach Foundation Establishment, you’ll be able to smoothly switch the cultivation art to your main cultivation art without any harm.”

Having heard that, Han Li found it difficult to respond. If he said that he had already cultivated it somewhat and she wished to see, he shouldn’t have any problems mimicking a few of its water attribute techniques.

Fortunately, this woman merely raised the question in passing and didn’t continue speaking.

Silvermoon knew that this wasn’t the time to talk to Han Li and stayed quiet in the presence of Mu Peiling.

As the two were about to draw closer to Dayspring Mountain, Mu Peiling’s expression stirred as she looked upward.

A moment later, a streak of green light flew down from the sky, blocking the woman’s path forward and causing them to stop.

“Junior Martial Sister Mu, I haven’t seen you in quite a while. Have you been busy recently? I’ve sent you quite a few sound transmission talismans but I haven’t received a single response.”

Han Li revealed a flabbergasted expression. The green light had faded away to reveal a sharp-eared, thin-faced cultivator in his thirties. This was the cultivator surnamed Yan who had blocked Han Li’s group when they were about to enter the sect.

When the cold woman saw this person, she revealed surprise but her expression soon grew sullen, “Yan, I am under orders of the Mountain Lord to assemble at the mountain. You dare to block me?”

“Hehe! Junior Martial Sister Mu’s words are quite heavy. How could I dare to block you? However, I merely wished to ask if you received the letters of my esteemed father? You see, the elders of our clans have already agreed to our wedding. We should discuss this in the coming days.” The cultivator surnamed Yan’s gaze wandered over the woman’s ample body with desire as he spoke. However, when he spotted Han Li, his expression grew sullen.

The woman surnamed Mu seemed to see through his wicked thoughts and a trace of hostility appeared in her eyes. She scolded him with an expression like ice, “What’s going through your mind? This is Martial Nephew Han who my master had given to me to instruct. There is nothing else between us. As for the matter of marriage, I naturally cannot oppose my clan’s seniors. However, I will always be in control of when we pair cultivate, if ever. Whenever your cultivation reaches my level, I might consider it. Otherwise, don’t even think about laying a finger on me.”

This woman loathed Yan to the extreme and couldn’t even put up a polite face.

When cultivator Yan heard her, his face went through a series of red and white flushes. But just as he thought to say something, the woman had ran out of patience. With a cold snort, she propelled her magic tool with the entirety of her spiritual power, causing them to flying over cultivator Yan in a large pulse of red light.

Cultivator Yan was greatly flustered and thought to chase them. But after some further thought, he stayed in place with a trace of resentment.

When Han Li turned around to glance at him, he saw an extremely bitter expression on Cultivator Yan’s face.

After a moment of hesitation, Han Li asked with an odd expression, “Martial Aunt Mu, you’re engaged to this man?”

Cultivator Yan was only an early Foundation Establishment cultivator, but Mu Peiling was already at mid Foundation Establishment. Also, their appearances were as different as day and night as well. Han Li felt completely puzzled as to why this woman’s clan had wed her to him.

Although Han Li felt somewhat curious, he originally wished to leave this matter alone. From the woman’s sulking expression, the subject seemed like something that should be ignored. But despite the possibility she would rebuke or ignore him, Han Li’s curiosity won over and he asked anyways.

“It is best of Martial Nephew asks little of my matters!” As soon as Han Li asked, she icily glared at him and replied without emotion.

Of course, Han Li responded by shutting his mouth and revealing an embarrassed expression. However, at that same moment, Han Li faintly heard Silvermoon giggling inside his head for a moment.

It was only a moment before they arrived at a large stage at the center of the mountain.

A large hall of antique design was erected on the stage. The words “Heart Cleansing Hall” were written on the building’s silver signboard.

At that moment, the huge black wooden doors were tightly shut, and the many disciples of Dayspring Mountain were chatting amongst themselves as they gathered outside.

There were about six hundred disciples already densely packed outside of Heart Cleansing Hall. They were all whispering to one another in small groups. However, these people were all Qi Condensation cultivators. None of them were at Foundation Establishment.

The cold woman circled once in the air before landing in front of the hall’s gates. When the nearby cultivators spotted her, they all respectfully saluted her.

The woman waved her hand and walked towards the hall without the slightest hesitation.

Through some unknown method, she gently slapped the door and it opened a sliver. Just after she entered, the door closed once more.

Han Li watched the woman disappear and shook his head, but when he thought to enter the crowd, the nearby cultivators gazed at him with strange looks. A few of the cultivators in the distance even began to point at him.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 621: Paying Audience

Han Li rubbed his chin and swept his spiritual sense past the crowd of murmuring Qi Condensation cultivators.

“Whose that?”

“What an unfamiliar face, is he a new disciple?”

“Why did he arrive with Martial Aunt Mu?”

“Is he a relative of Martial Aunt Mu? Why else would he arrive together with her?”

Han Li clearly heard many suspicious and envious words from the crowd and he inwardly sighed. Soon after, he stepped away from the hall’s entrance and entered the crowd. Even within the crowd, Han Li could still feel plenty of gazes examining him.

At that moment, Han Li heard a voice transmission with a straightforward tone, “Junior Martial Brother Han. I didn’t think I’d see you again so soon.”

Han Li turned his head in surprise and spotted a large man standing about ten meters behind him. He was Du Dong, the suspicious Qi Condensation cultivator that had entered Dayspring Mountain at the same time as him.

He was currently calling out to Han Li with a wide smile.

An odd expression flickered from Han Li’s eyes but he wore a smile and politely saluted him, “So it turned out to be Senior Martial Brother Du. Are you doing well with Martial Uncle Jiang?”

Martial Uncle Jiang was the white-haired old man that Dong Du was assigned to.

“Yes, I’m doing very well.” The large man chuckled. He appeared to be a rather simple and honest character.

Han Li inwardly sneered, but he maintained a polite exterior as they shared their experiences with each other from the past year.

He heard that the white-haired old man believed that Du Dong was rather talented in refining talismans and wished to heavily nurture him. With that said, Du Dong wore a smile full of excitement.

When Han Li heard him, he felt slight pity towards the white-haired old man. Du Dong wasn’t someone who should be nurtured. The old man would likely be implicated in whatever plans this shady individual may have.

Of course, Han Li had no intentions of warning Martial Uncle Jiang and continued to intermittently chat with the large man.

At that moment, the large man suddenly wore a mysterious expression and said, “Junior Martial Brother Han, did you know? Your mentor, Martial Aunt Mu, is the top beauty in Dayspring Mountain, and she is also among the top three beauties in the Drifting Cloud Sect. You may have caused quite the uproar by arriving with her.”

“May have? I already did!” Han Li bitterly laughed and glanced around with a trace of helplessness.

Du Dong then changed the subject and casually asked, “Since you two arrived together, did Martial Aunt say anything regarding what this meeting is about?”

“Oh! No, but it seems Senior Martial Brother Du heard something? Wouldn’t it be better for you to tell me?”

Han Li’s calm expression was replaced with a mysterious smile as he deeply looked at Dong Du.

Under Han Li’s penetrating gaze, the large man’s honest smile had frozen. Du Dong was left overwhelmed from a sensation of immense scrutiny as if his secrets were laid bare.

But soon Han Li turned his head and this feeling disappeared as if it were merely a misperception. Regardless, the man was left bewildered and he quickly bid his farewells before heading to meet with a group of acquainted Dayspring Mountain disciples, not daring to stay in Han Li’s company.

A slight sneer momentarily appeared on Han Li’s face when he saw him walking away. At that moment, Silvermoon spoke within his mind, “Brother Han, did you deliberately scare him? I fear that he will later hold suspicion towards you. Won’t he be a detriment?”

Han Li responded using his spiritual sense, “I might not clearly know his identity, but I am certain that nothing good will come of him so I made sure that he’d take the initiative to distance himself from me. If something major did happen, then I will avoid being implicated. As for any suspicion he might hold, how would that affect me? He would merely become more careful of me, and it’s not like he could succeed in attacking me. I merely wish not to be associated with him. I have no intention of interfering with his plans.”

Silvermoon didn’t reply, and it appeared that she recognized the reason in Han Li’s words. In the end, if Du Dong maliciously conspired against the sect, anybody close to him would certainly come under the suspicious notice of the sect’s upper echelon, something that Han Li would certainly wish to avoid.

In the following moments, Han Li examined the crowd of disciples in solitude.

There were disciples of both genders and of all ages. There were also those with cultivations that didn’t match their age, such as young cultivators already at the peak of Qi Condensation.

There were also a few gorgeous young woman, but all of them had a group of similarly aged men at their side. It seems young, beautiful female cultivators were pursued the same way in every sect.

Just as Han Li was lost in thought, the hall’s gate eventually opened and a dignified voice spoke out, leaving the Qi Condensation disciples in silenced awe.

“All Dayspring Mountain Disciples are to enter the hall!”

This faint man’s voice belonged to the Dayspring Mountain Lord, the mid Core Formation cultivator surnamed Xin that Han Li had met when he was assigned to the mountain.

When the disciples outside the hall heard him, they all lowered their heads and respectfully said, “We sincerely accept Martial Ancestor’s orders!” Afterwards, the crowd immediately walked into the hall in two orderly lines. Because Han Li was among the last to enter, he saw that Du Dong was also among the last to enter the Cleansing Heart Hall.

The area within the large hall was vast, spanning at least a kilometer wide with several tens of lofty pillars scattered throughout. Each of the pillars were embedded with smoothly carved moonlight stones, illuminating the hall with a faint white glow. The hall was entirely empty apart from the two thrones that were placed at the very front.

Within these two chairs sat a white-robed man with a scholarly appearance and a grey-clothed old man with fierce eyes and messy hair.

In front of the two thrones stood two rows of over ten Foundation Establishment cultivators.

The elegant beauty surnamed Mu and the youth surnamed Yu that had led Han Li into the sect were both standing in the second row. As for the youth surnamed Miao that had questioned him when he had entered the sect, he was standing in the first row, looking just as sickly and pale as before.

When the disciples entered the hall, they all simultaneously knelt and saluted the two sitting in the chairs, “Disciples pay their respects to Martial Ancestor Xin and Martial Ancestor Yu!”

“That’s enough, stand!” The middle aged man swept his arm with a smile and had the crowd of disciples stand.

The Qi Condensation disciples then split off into two rows and stood at each side of the hall. Han Li and Du Dong both happened to stand near the hall’s entrance.

Han Li swept his spiritual sense past the old man with the fierce expression and found that he was only an early Core Formation cultivator. He was the deputy mountain lord that he had heard of but haven’t seen, “Martial Uncle Yu”.

After Han Li inspected him, he recalled his spiritual sense from a lack of interest.

In the next moment, Mountain Lord Xin began to slowly speak, “I’m sure you disciples already know why I’ve summoned you all here. Yesterday, our sect received an official letter from the Ancient Sword Sect. The next Sword Trial Assembly will be held in a half year’s time. As we hosted the last competition, it is the Thousand Possibilities Sect’s turn to host it in the east of the Dreamcloud Mountains. In accordance to the usual practice, each of the three sects will send thirty disciples to participate in the Sword Trial Assembly. The final ten that remain in the competition will be heavily rewarded. As such, we must first select the best of our sect to participate.”

With that said, he paused for a moment before continuing, “Of course, each of the sect’s six mountain lords will be able nominate one person that will be able to participate in the Sword Trial Assembly without measuring their skill. As for the other twenty-four slots, they will be vied for by the disciples that meet the requirements. These victorious disciples will then be advised by sect elders in the time remaining before the Sword Trial Assembly. Yesterday, I had a meeting with the Sect Master and the other mountain lords where we decided that the sect’s Sword Trial Selection will take place in a month. But first, I must give an explanation of the two conditions required to participate for those that are unaware. Any participants must be less than thirty years old and possess a minimum cultivation at the tenth layer of Qi Condensation, else they will be barred from joining. That is all. Now, if you meet the minimum conditions and wish to vie for a position, you have until the incense burns away to decide. Oh yes, the disciple that I and Deputy Mountain Lord Yun selected to participate without trial is your Martial Aunt Mu. Jun’er, go ahead and light the incense.”

“As you bid, Master.” The youth surnamed Yu immediately stepped forward and swiftly took out a bronze cauldron from his storage pouch. He then set it at the center of the hall and placed a stick of incense in it.　　

With a flash of light from his hand, fragrant smoke began to spiral towards the sky.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 622: Preliminary Selection

While none dared to make a commotion, those who held the qualifications to participate became restless as they watched the incense stick burn.

When the incense stick burned halfway, Silvermoon saw that Han Li wore an aloof expression and couldn’t help but ask, “Will Brother Han be participating?”

“Why wouldn’t I? With the other disciples all stirring in excitement, it would draw quite a bit of attention if I didn’t.”

With that said, Silvermoon grew silent.

A short moment later, the incense stick had completely burned away and the mountain lord opened his eyes.

“Those that don’t meet the conditions or are unwilling to join may now leave.”

“As you bid, Martial Ancestor!” A majority of the present disciples then bowed and slowly left the hall.

Apart from the Foundation Establishment cultivators, there were only about forty young disciples left in the room.

When the middle-aged man examined the group, he nodded his head with satisfaction, “Good, all the disciples present fulfill the conditions. I am quite happy. Even if none of you are selected to participate, your horizons will be greatly widened as you fight against your Martial Brothers from the other mountains. It will provide great benefits to your future cultivation. Your Martial Uncle will now explain some important points about the competition. As for Martial Ancestor Yu and I, we have matters to attend to and will be departing first.”

With that said, Mountain Lord Xin and Deputy Mountain Lord Yun departed from the hall.

With a sickly appearance, the youth surnamed Miao coughed several times before calmly speaking to the Qi Condensation cultivators, “Since the Mountain Lord has handed over this matter to me, please listen carefully, Martial Nephews. After all, this competition will be a test of skill against your fellow sect members and there are things that must be avoided.”

“First of all, vicious and deadly techniques and magic tools are disallowed in the contest. Otherwise, you will be expelled from the sect and will have your cultivation scattered. Also...”

A quarter hour later, Han Li and the rest of the disciples in the hall walked out. Most of them flew off with expressions of excitement.

Han Li glanced at their departing figures and shook his head before taking to the skies and flying back to his cave residence. The journey back was smooth and uneventful.

Inside his cave residence, he began his preparations for the sect contest. Since he couldn’t display too much power in his pursuit for one of the twenty-four positions, he had to make use of talismans and several magic tools that he hadn’t touched in countless years.

Top grade magic tools were more than plentiful. He had plundered tens of them from the Core Formation cultivators that he had personally slain. But in order to draw less attention to himself, he had to carefully select only a few of them. And since he didn’t intend on using these magic tools in the sect selection, he also began to refine large quantities of mid level elementary talismans. He planned on using these talismans to crush his low grade opponents in a single blow.

Of course, he wouldn’t be able to make it through on talismans alone. Han Li especially refreshed his knowledge on the “Flame Handling Arts” he had acquired all those years ago from an old Daoist in the prince’s mansion of the State of Yue [1] . Although it wouldn’t prove particularly useful to high grade cultivators, it will prove more than effective in duping Qi Condensation and Foundation Establishment cultivators.

When Han Li had first acquired the Flame Handling Arts all those years ago, he had gained many insights from it. But with his current cultivation as a late Core Formation cultivator, it had little value to him. As a result of only a few days of effort, he grasped the entirety of the methods of transforming flames. He had even acquired subtle understandings that exceeded what had been recorded in the Flame Handling Arts.

For the rest of these days, Han Li wholeheartedly spent his time refining various talismans.

During that time, his gold-silver Gold Devouring Beetles had already begun to cannibalize one another, much to his joy. He was sure that while the Gold Devouring Beetles were still far away from complete evolution, they were growing quite close to the legendary all-devouring stage.

However, the Weeping Soul Beast in the neighboring room was proving quite troublesome for Han Li. It had remained soundly asleep this entire time without any sign of awakening. Fortunately, with the Weeping Soul Pearl refined within his body, he knew that there was nothing wrong with the beast. However, he couldn’t help but feel worried. After all, it was taking too long to complete its transformation. ...

A month later, the Drifting Cloud Sect’s main mountain was bustling with exceptional liveliness. Cultivators began to unceasingly gather at the top of the mountain, with several thousands cultivators that came to observe the contest. It appeared everyone that was off duty had come.

While they weren’t participating the battle, watching other cultivators battle in a contest of skill was a vastly enriching experience.

The contest was being held on three large, flat stages near the top of the mountain. Each of the stages were surrounded by spell formations over three hundred meters wide. They all raised a huge dome of light around the stage to prevent the spectators from receiving any injuries.

There were three late Foundation Establishment cultivators acting as judges to prevent any deaths from occuring.

The sect selection was now undergoing its third day. The past two days had resulted in many cultivators being sadly defeated.

In total, the selection contest was being conducted between five hundred cultivators. Although there were three stages to conduct battles, this process would take many days given the large number of participants.

That being said, the forty cultivators of Dayspring Mountain had been among the smaller factions. They paled in comparison to the number from Firecloud Mountain which had over a hundred disciples participating.

There were only four Foundation Establishment cultivators in the contest, but they weren’t required to fight until the final round. Although they weren’t among those that were chosen by the mountain lords, they had still managed to reach Foundation Establishment before the age of thirty. Since they were undoubtedly talented individuals, they would be given a position with just a single victory against a Qi Condensation cultivator.

At that moment, Han Li silently stood among several Dayspring Mountain cultivators. They were all watching a battle occur inside a light barrier between a cultivator of Dayspring Mountain and White Phoenix Mountain.

White Phoenix was a peculiar existence amongst the six mountains. Not only did the mountain have two female Core Formation mountain lords, they primarily relied on female disciples. As a result, their mountain possessed few disciples and only a dozen female cultivators were participating in the battle.

The Dayspring Mountain disciple that was fighting appeared somewhat aged, but he was actually in his late twenties. Although he was an external affair disciple, he was born in a reputable cultivation clan in the State of Xi. That was why he possessed a high grade magic tool of considerable power, a white gold dagger-axe. Although the young female cultivator from white Phoenix Mountain was being pushed back, her eyes were full of hope.

The Dayspring Mountain cultivators beside Han Li were clearly good friends with the male cultivator and cheered him on with excitement.

But just as the man’s white dagger-axe was about to chop down, the woman raised her brow and shout a ball of azure light from her hand, blocking the white streak. The woman’s body then blurred and she disappeared without a trace.

When the man saw this, he hurriedly formed an incantation seal with his hands as his expression vastly changed. Just as he thought to force back the woman with a magic technique, a red mist suddenly enveloped him from behind.

Then with a flop, the Dayspring Mountain disciple fell to the ground.

The lanky cultivator that was floating above the stage announced, “White Phoenix Mountain’s Jin Rong is victorious.”

When the female cultivator heard this, she respectfully saluted the judge and took out a small bottle from her storage pouch. After she placed it next to the nose of the unconscious cultivator, he began to slowly regain consciousness.

Once he realized what had happened, the Dayspring Mountain cultivator walked from the stage with a deep red expression. Afterwards, the female cultivator flew out from the spell formation with a proud appearance. The nearby female cultivators immediately surrounded her and showered her with praise, attracting the attention of a few nearby male cultivators.

Above the dome of light, the lanky cultivator expressionlessly announced, “The next battle will be between Dayspring Mountain’s Han Li and Firecloud Mountain’s Xun Tong!” Although his voice wasn’t loud, the nearby cultivators heard him clearly.

When Han Li heard this, he smiled and slowly walked into the spell formation.

Not long after, a handsome, white-clothed cultivator entered from the other side. As soon as this person entered, an uproar was raised amongst the nearby spectators.

[1]. In Chapter 294: Flame Handling Arts, Han Li acquired an interesting book from an old Qi Condensation cultivator that was surprisingly useful.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 624: Discussion

On the thirteenth day of the Drifting Cloud Sect’s selection, the final round was currently being concluded.

At that moment, there were eight Core Formation cultivators assembled together in a pavilion at the center of the mountain discussing something. Two of them were the mountain lords of Dayspring Mountain, the middle-aged man surnamed Xin and the fierce-looking, grey-clothed old man surnamed Yu.

A blue-robed old man with a white fluttering beard and a faceful of wrinkles frowned and asked, “Are there any Junior Martial Brothers willing to escort the disciples to the Sword Trial Assembly?”

A middle-aged man with a lazy expression and a long, thin mustache snorted and indifferently replied, “Senior Martial Brother Feng, the Sword Trial Assembly will always be dominated by the Ancient Sword Sect, and that vitriolic fellow Jiang Yun is always the one to bring the Ancient Sword Sect members. I don’t wish to be embarrassed without reason.”

A yellow-faced old man shook his head and said, “That’s right! I’ve even heard that in the past few years, the Ancient Sword Sect picked up a disciple that possessed a Ninesword Constitution. They will be certain to have him participate. As such, there is no hope of winning this Sword Trial Assembly. Although we do hold a few disciples that possess a peculiar constitution, they are inferior in comparison. And there is also news that the Hundred Possibilities Sect had acquired a direct descendant of the Guan Clan. It is said that while he was still in Qi Condensation, he defeated his clan’s elders by using his personally refined magic tools. I fear this could be quite a difficult trip!”

When the white-haired old man heard this, he revealed an expression of dissatisfaction. He gravely said, “Junior Martial Brothers, you aren’t wrong. The Sword Trial Assembly has already become a stage for the Ancient Sword Sect to display their power, but that is something beyond our control. If our sect does not send over any disciples that participate in the assembly, I fear we won’t even acquire a quarter of the Wine Nectar. Besides, this could easily cause the Ancient Sword Sect to view us with hostility. It would be detrimental to our sect’s development in the Dreamcloud Mountain for ages to come. We have more things to worry about, like the many clans that are covetously eyeing the three sects of Dreamcloud Mountain. We cannot reveal any weakness to them.”

A square-faced, red-robed old man with a formal appearance suddenly proposed, “Since Senior Martial Brother Feng said this, I’ll be the one to bring the disciples. Rather, I haven’t seen the Hundred Possibilities Sect’s Elder Chang Zheng in quite a while. A chance to chat would be nice.”

Old Man Feng glanced at him and hesitantly said, “Junior Martial Brother Duan, as the Mountain Lord of Firecloud Mountain, you have the most disciples under you. It would be improper for you to leave the sect.”

The red-robed old man nonchalantly said, “It is of no matter. Junior Martial Brother Li will still be there to handle Firecloud Mountain. Besides, it’s not like I’m leaving the Dreamcloud Mountains. I’m just traveling to the western range.”

With that said, the white-haired old man didn’t persist in his objections and nodded his head. He then swept his gaze over the other cultivators before staring at the fierce-looking, grey-clothed old man. He slowly said, “Junior Martial Brother Yu, I know that you don’t have any pressing responsibilities at Dayspring Mountain. How about you assist Junior Martial Brother Duan? Junior Martial Brother Xin, do you have any objections?”

The middle-aged man surnamed Xin faintly smiled and said, “Of course not. I’m sure Junior Martial Brother Yu is completely willing to go.”

The grey-clothed old man's cold expression stirred for a long while before he briefly said, “Fine, I’ll go!”

The white-haired old man smiled and nodded his head, saying, “The group of disciples will be headed by Junior Martial Brother Duan. Junior Martial Brother Yu and Junior Marital Sister Song of White Phoenix Mountain will be accompanying him. Once the final round has been concluded, you will meet with thirty selected disciples and give them guidance. Perhaps there will be a chance for our sect yet. After all, we have quite a few powerful candidates this time around. We should be able to give the Ancient Sword Sect and the Hundred Possibilities Sect quite the contest.”

A sly-faced cultivator that had been hiding in the corner yelped in surprise, “Junior Martial Sister Song will also be coming along? How did I not know of this? If that’s the case, I can take the place of Junior Martial Brother Yu.” When the rest of the cultivators in the pavilion heard him, there was a brief moment of restlessness. Three of the cultivators wore an annoyed expression.

The white-haired old man’s face grew sullen and he snorted, “Junior Martial Brother Meng, what do you mean? I’ve spoken for half a day, and you didn’t speak a single word. But now that you’ve heard Junior Martial Sister Song wishes to go, you jump at the chance. I’ll tell you the truth, Junior Martial Sister Song raised the condition that she would only accompany the disciples if I didn’t mention that she was going to begin with. Otherwise, given her temperament, why else would she depart from White Phoenix Mountain?”

As this old man had already reached late Core Formation, the sly-faced early Core Formation cultivator didn’t dare to dispute this and lowered his head.

There were other cultivators that were also tempted, but each of them glanced at one another in dismay, not daring to speak.

At that moment, footsteps suddenly came from the outside. A man’s voice said, “Reporting to Master and Martial Uncles, the last round has just finished. Three Foundation Establishment disciples have been selected along with twenty-one Qi Condensation cultivators. I’ve come with the list of names.”

The white-robed cultivator’s expression relaxed and he said, “Oh! Since that’s the case, come in. Let’s take a look.”

“As you wish!” The man respectfully replied. Afterwards, he opened the door and entered, revealing himself to be a late Foundation Establishment cultivator with a stately appearance and a tall body.

“Here are the names and details of the twenty-four finalists.” The man took out a white jade slip from his robes and handed it over to the old man.

“I’ll be taking a look first!” The old man nodded his head and took the jade slip into his hand.

“Huh?” After taking a look at it with his spiritual sense, he revealed a trace of astonishment.

The red-clothed cultivator’s expression stirred and he asked, “What’s the matter? Is there something amiss with the list of names?”

The others also oddly glanced at the old man.

“It’s nothing. Junior Martial Brothers have a look!” With that said, the old man calmly passed the jade slip to the yellow-skinned old man at his side.

After taking a look at the jade slip, he also revealed astonishment and handed the jade slip to someone else. Not longer after, everyone had looked at the jade slip and each of them had turbulent expressions.

When the Dayspring Mountain Lord Xin read through the jade slip, his expression stirred with particular surprise.

The middle-aged man with the thin mustache sighed and slowly said, “I truly didn’t expect that there would be six disciples from Dayspring Mountain to be selected. It seems Junior Martial Brother Xin has instructed his disciples well.”

The sly-faced cultivator sourly said, “It seems Junior Martial Brother Xin is determined to win this Sword Trial Assembly. You must’ve spent quite some effort to cultivate these disciples!” Only three disciples from his Hidden Sword Mountain had made it on the list, which lost him a considerable amount of face.

“No, it definitely wasn’t like that. I myself am surprised to see so many people from my Dayspring Mountain being selected. And two of them are even at the tenth layer of Qi Condensation, named Han Li and Du Dong. If I’m not mistaken, those two entered the sect just this past year. It is baffling how they managed to take a place on the list.” The middle-aged man surnamed Xin then muttered to himself for a moment and calmly said, “Martial Nephew Gao, how did they manage to acquire victory?”

The man who had just entered the room promptly replied, “Their methods weren’t anything strange. Martial Nephew Du Dong possesses an extremely powerful ice attribute top-grade magic tool. It seems capable of both attacking and defending, and it perfectly compliments his techniques as well. As a result, once he froze the ground with his magic tool, all of his opponents were left helpless against his strikes.”

The middle-aged man with the long mustache interrupted, asking, “Oh! What kind of magic tool is it? Can you give us a description?”

“It is a wheel type magic tool. It has a diameter of about a foot and is engraved with a curved moon. It sparkles with white light when it is activated, can activate an ice attribute barrier in an instant, and can attack with a mist of freezing Qi.”

The middle-aged man’s eyes flickered and he said with surprise, “That seems quite similar to the clan suppressing treasure of the Du Clan, the Ice Moon Wheel. The Du Clan was exterminated two hundred years ago. Could this Du Dong be a descendant?”

The white-haired old man curled his beard and unhurriedly said, “En! That seems quite possible. After all, the Du Clan wasn’t a small clan. There were sure to be a few direct lineage disciples that escaped calamity and lived in concealment. They probably now believe that with so many years having passed, their enemies are no longer paying any attention to them. As such, they revealed themselves once more.”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 626: Harmonic Mind

Three months passed by in the blink of an eye while Han Li remained in bitter cultivation in his cave residence.

During this time, Kui Huan’s group had paid a visit to Han Li to apologetically tell him that they had informed the sect elders of Han Li’s skills in talisman refinement, hoping that he wouldn’t take offence.

Because Han Li had already planned on using his talisman refinement techniques as a cover, he didn’t mind in the slightest. After giving a few words of forgiveness, he sent the group of Qi Condensation cultivators on their way.

As for Dayspring Mountain, because Han Li had unexpectedly made it into the twenty-four finalists, Mu Peiling had made a trip to the medicine garden and gave Han Li a long explanation on the intricacies of the Profound Ice Arts. This surprising action had left Han Li at a loss for words.

Apart from those two times, no one else disturbed Han Li during his cultivation.

One day as Han Li was strenuously cultivating the Azure Essence Sword Arts, he abruptly frowned and stood up. By the time he left his cave residence and entered the medicinal garden, a voice transmission talisman knocked against the medicine garden’s restrictions.

When Han Li saw this, he opened the garden’s restrictions and waved his arm. A moment later, the sound transmission talisman flew into his hand in a streak of fire and soon disappeared.

Han Li expressionlessly muttered, “White Phoenix Mountain’s Martial Ancestor Song. Isn’t that the number one beauty in the Drifting Cloud Sect? Will that woman be instructing me? If that’s the case, these coming days shouldn’t be too boring!” He then released a flying sword magic tool and directly flew in the direction of White Phoenix Mountain.

White Phoenix Mountain was at the eastmost side of Drifting Cloud Sect and was particularly distant from the other five mountains as if it were standing proudly in solitude. Although this mountain was the shortest of the Six Marvelous Mountains, it was by far the most verdant and beautiful.

Not long after leaving the garden, Han Li appeared near White Phoenix Mountain.

Because this mountain was made up of mostly female cultivators, White Phoenix Mountain had a few strange rules. Ordinarily, any male cultivators arriving at the mountain were required to land at the base of the mountain and receive permission to enter. Otherwise, they would only have themselves to blame for falling into White Phoenix Mountain’s restrictions.

Naturally, Han Li had no intention of forcing his way through and obediently landed at the base of the mountain.

There were currently three Qi Condensation female cultivators at the mountain gate happily chatting. When they saw Han Li drop down, they couldn’t help but curiously examine the unfamiliar male cultivator.

Han Li saluted the three female disciples and said, “I am Dayspring Mountain’s Han Li. I’ve come to accept cultivation guidance from Martial Ancestor Song. I hope Senior Martial Sisters can make a report.”

A young, freckled female cultivator smiled and promptly said, “So you’re Han Li. The Martial Ancestor has already notified us of you. Junior Martial Brother Han may directly head to the Phoenix Court Pavilion at the top of the mountain. Martial Ancestor is waiting for you there.

Han Li uttered a word of thanks before immediately flying up the mountain.

However, not long after he departed, the three female disciples began to gossip without restraint once they believed Han Li was out of earshot.

“Is Junior Martial Brother Han truly a disciple that will be participating in the Sword Trial Assembly? His cultivation doesn’t seem very high.”

“He doesn’t appear to be anything special.”

“Hehe! So you two don’t know. I’ve seen all of Junior Martial Brother Han’s fights. Let me tell you...”

Having heard all of that, Han Li recalled his spiritual sense with a wry smile. After shaking his head, he fly towards the mountain peak.

White Phoenix Mountain wasn’t very tall. After only a moment, Han Li managed to reach the top of the mountain, a flat plateau that spanned three hundred meters. It was surrounded with white clouds with abundant spiritual Qi as if it were an otherworldly realm.

Within this fantastic scene stood a sole pavilion that was only sixty meters tall and was divided into three stories. The building was constructed from a unknown white wood. Its natural untouched form produced an air of simple elegance.

Han Li landed in front of the pavilion and loudly shouted, “Disciple Han Li pays his respects to Martial Ancestor Song!” Once that was said, Han Li felt a trace of spiritual sense sweep over him. He stood in place with a calm expression, feigning ignorance of the matter.

A long while later, a woman’s gentle voice said, “Since you’ve arrived, come up to the second story of the pavilion. I’ll be waiting for you there.”

“As you bid!” Han Li then walked forward and gently pushed open the wooden doors which swung freely.

The first floor of the pavilion was completely empty apart from a spell formation to aid in cultivation.

Han Li swept his gaze past the first floor and directly headed towards the second floor.

The second floor was also quite bare. Apart from a few racks of jade slips and magic tools, there were only a few chairs and a short stone table.

Han Li also saw a blue-clothed woman sitting in one of the chairs. She was looking at a worn jade slip on the table as if she were attentively reading through it.

After a moment of hesitation, Han Li thought to say something when the woman raised her head, revealing a heart stirring beauty. She appeared to be in her mid twenties and was an early Core Formation cultivator.

“You’re Han Li?” The woman calmly asked.

“Yes, Martial Ancestor!” Han Li respectfully replied.

She stared at Han Li with her bright, clear eyes and said, “Since you were able to come here, then it can be considered fate. I will instruct you as best I can. However, you will only remain at the Phoenix Court Pavilion for three days before you depart. What you will learn during this time will depend on yourself.”

For some reason, although her cultivation wasn’t very high, Han Li felt as if both his body and mind were clearly revealed underneath her gaze, and he couldn’t help but feel alarm. Given Han Li’s immense spiritual sense, it was extremely strange for him to experience this sensation. Clearly, she had used some sort of mind reading divine ability.

Without any further thought, Han Li gave her a polite reply as he stealthily circulated the entirety of his Great Development Technique throughout his body, shielding his true thoughts.

As Han Li became inwardly alarmed and vigilant, a strange expression appeared in the blue-clothed woman’s eyes before closing them with a tired expression.

The woman gently said, “First, recite the chant for your cultivation art and then head down to the second layer. Do not come back up without my command. After I’ve obtained some enlightenment of your cultivation art, I will give you a detailed explanation on any of its intricacies. Now, start!”

“Yes. Disciple cultivates the technique that Martial Aunt Mu had given him, the Profound Ice Arts. This cultivation art...” Han Li began to slowly recite it with a calm expression.

After the time it took to finish a cup of tea, Han Li had finished. The woman nodded her head and waved an arm, indicating for him to go down. Han Li saluted her and wordlessly climbed down the stairs.

The blue-clothed woman looked at Han Li’s departing figure and motionlessly sat down in her chair with a frown.

She then took out a sound transmission talisman and calmly said a few words into it. It turned into a streak of fire and flew out the window without a trace.

...

At the center of the main mountain of the Drifting Cloud Sect where the Core Formation cultivators had last met, a white-haired old man was leisurely standing at the window when his eyes suddenly began to shine as a streak of fiery light flew towards him from across the sky.

The old man wordlessly raised his hand and emitted a mist of white light, catching the fiery light. It fiercely burned, releasing the curt voice of the blue-clothed woman, “Han Li passes, but Du Dong harbors malice.”

With an icy expression, old man coldly muttered, “Humph! Habors malice? I knew something was amiss. The Du Clan had a deep relationship with the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion’s Fu Clan. If he truly was a descendant of the Du Clan, he should’ve entered the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion rather than our Drifting Cloud Sect.”

The white-haired old man thought a moment more before muttering to himself with an expression of admiration, “However, Junior Martial Sister Song’s Harmonic Mind is becoming truly fearsome. I myself am uncertain as to whether or not I can block it. I know only my two Martial Uncles to be capable.”

...

Two months later, at the western portion of the Dreamcloud Mountains in a deep valley surrounded by mountains, there were several thousands of Hundred Possibilities Pavilion disciples converging at the heart of the valley. They were excitedly talking with each other as their clamor filled the air.

There were many disciples that repeatedly gazed to the skies with impatient expressions as if they were feeling anxious.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 630: A Boy

As soon as the party reacted the stone gate, the yellow-clothed cultivator’s command medallion dimmed and the passageway completely disappeared.

Facing the group, he indifferently said, “Follow,” before turning around and forming various hand incantations with his fingers. He then raised his arms and shot out a scarlet and yellow light from his hands towards the huge stone gate.

Suddenly, talisman characters on the tightly-shut stone gate began to stir and it began to release a series of low-hums. The gate slowly opened to reveal a long passageway.

The yellow-clothed cultivator wordlessly stepped through the passage and the others glanced at each other before closely following after him.

Han Li stood at the center of the disciples and seemed to be staring forward with great intensity. But in actuality, he was sweeping his spiritual sense across everything nearby.

This rectangular passageway was a man-made tunnel that lead into the heart of the mountain. Not only were the walls smooth, but there were a few profound talisman characters every couple of steps. Although Han Li couldn’t study them for the time being, he was certain they weren’t only there for decoration.

After walking for only about three hundred meters, their surroundings brightened and they arrived at a tidy stone hall that was about two hundred meters wide and eighty meters tall.

The center of the stone hall had a meter high limestone platform with ten lines perpendicularly intersecting from each side. From the sets of black and white pieces arranged on the platform, it appeared to be a chess game during a crucial moment.

There was an old man and a young boy sitting cross legged across from each other on the platform. The old man appeared to be in his late fifties while the young boy appeared to be less than ten years old. From his flawless appearance, it appeared as if this were a perfect child that had reincarnated.

“Martial Uncle Lan! What is Senior doing here?” When Cultivator Bai saw the child, he suddenly shouted in surprise and hastily saluted him.

“Martial Uncle Lan?”

The grey-robed old man and the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion cultivator were initially surprised to see the child there. But after hearing Cultivator Bai address him by name, their expressions greatly changed. Once they saw the boy’s ponytail, bare feet, and the golden band on his arm, they suddenly recalled the name of a legendary Senior.

“Juniors Du Bei and Yu Shan’an pay their respects to Senior Lan!” In their alarm, the two rushed to salute him.

“Stand. Didn’t you notice that I am at a crucial point in my game with Martial Nephew Hu? Let’s talk after I’ve finished.” The boy’s voice was as young as his appearance, but each of his words carried an aged tone filled with poise.

“As you command!” Cultivator Bai and the other two Core Formation cultivators instantly acknowledged him and silently loitered nearby, not daring to appear sullen in the slightest.

As for the old man playing chess with the boy, he wryly smiled at the three but remained silent. As for the yellow-robed cultivator, he respectfully stood behind the boy as if he were deferentially waiting upon him.

When the young cultivators heard their three martial ancestors suddenly call out to the boy as Martial Uncle, they became restless. They instantly realized what this meant and stared at the boy with anxious hearts.

In the instant Han Li saw the boy, he felt his heart drop. This was a genuine early Nascent Soul cultivator. Why had he appeared here?

However, he soon recovered his calm. While he wasn’t currently an opponent for an early Nascent Soul cultivator, it wouldn’t be any problem for him to escape. Additionally, he was confident that the Nascent Soul cultivator wasn’t here for him.

With that in mind, Han Li began to plan for any contingencies that may occur.

In the end, the boy and the Old Man played for another quarter hour before the old man stepped back from the chessboard and respectfully said, “Senior Lan’s chess skills are excellent. This disciple concedes!”

A trace of happiness appeared on the boy’s face, but his gaze soon turned and he doubtfully said, “Martial Nephew Hu, you didn’t deliberately lose to me, right? We agreed that you wouldn’t hold back against me.”

When the old man heard this, his face appeared to have grown longer and he hurriedly said, “Junior wouldn’t dare to deceive Senior. It is just that Senior’s chess skills have made massive improvements.”

The boy smiled and said, “Hehe, I also feel that my chess skills have made quite the improvement from before. It seems that it was quite worth it to practice against those mortal chess masters.”

The boy’s smile then faded away as he changed topics, “Alright, let’s put the chess pieces away. There is business to attend to.”

He turned turned around to face the cultivators that were waiting on him. After sweeping his gaze over the Core Formation cultivators, it finally settled onto the scholarly man’s face.

The boy leisurely asked, “Martial Nephew Bai, how many years has it been since you entered the Ancient Sword Sect?”

Cultivator Bai’s face revealed slight puzzlement, but he sincerely answered, “This Junior entered the sect over a hundred years ago.”

A strange expression flickered within the boy’s eyes and he sighed, “A hundred years! It must’ve been quite tough for you.”

The scholarly man’s expression changed and he forced a smile, “Martial Uncle, what do you mean?”

The boy stared at the scholarly man and said with an icy tone, “What do I mean? As the successor of the Righteous Dao’s Overwhelming Pavilion Sect Master, your esteemed self has maintained you cover in the Ancient Sword Sect for quite the while. Haven’t you had any thoughts of visiting your master?”

When Cultivator Bai heard the boy, his complexion instantly paled.

The other two Core Formation cultivators revealed shock in their eyes and unconsciously took several steps back from Cultivator Bai.

“Fellow Daoist Bai, is Senior Lan speaking the truth?” The middle-aged cultivator asked in disbelief.

Cultivator Bai’s face fluctuated between red and white, unable to give an excuse. After wearing an unsightly expression, the scholarly man said, “Since Martial Uncle has already fully investigated me, there is no use in denying this. However, I will not idly stand by and allow myself to be captured!”

As soon as he said that, his body flashed with white light and he shot towards the disciples behind him. His glowing white hand was reaching out towards the black-clothed Meng Di who possessed the Ninesword Spirit Constitution!

“What are you doing?!” The two Core Formation cultivators furiously shouted. Their bodies flickered with light and they moved to rescue Meng Di, but they were clearly too late.

However, Meng Di managed to react in his alarm, and he raised his hand to fiercely release a dense strike of sword Qi.

Unfortunately, there was too great a difference in their cultivations. The sword Qi wasn’t even able to injure Cultivator Bai in the slightest and was dissipated in an instant. But before Meng Di was captured by him, Cultivator Bai’s body suddenly trembled and he fell flat on the ground. The light shining from his hand had disappeared without a trace.

Meng Di couldn’t help but blankly stand in place at a completely loss.

The young boy expressionlessly rubbed his small hands and snorted, “Your sect’s Grand Qi Hand has been well refined. But you forget that I didn’t come here only to play chess.”

Apart from Han Li, no one else in the room noticed how the boy had restrained the scholarly man.

Han Li narrowed his eyes as he watched the scholarly man fall to the floor and then looked at the boy with an odd expression in his eyes.

In the same moment Cultivator Bai took action, Han Li was astonished to discover that a red string had suddenly shot out from the boy. The string suddenly shot into the scholarly man’s body and he promptly collapsed.

Han Li had initially believed the string to be a flying needle magic treasure, but under his spiritual sense, he was astonished to discover that the red string was made of a dense, icy Qi. Much to Han Li’s amazement, this string was actually refined from an icy sword Qi!

He recalled having heard that once talented sword cultivators reached a certain stage of cultivation, they were able to transform their sword Qi into a string as they desired, turning it into a battle-deciding attack! This was the first time he had witnessed this, and it was unfathomable to him just how sword Qi was able to reach this stage.

The boy turned to the old man he was playing chess with and said, “Martial Nephew Hu, lock him up in the dragon cave. Keep him alive. Your Seniors still have a use for him!”

The long-faced old man felt his heart tremble before he acknowledged his instructions. He stepped over to the fallen cultivator Bai and carried him to the side of the room before disappearing without a trace.

Han Li’s gaze then turned to look at Du Dong. He noticed that his expression appeared calm, but under closer scrutiny, Han Li noticed that he was clenching his hands into fists.

When Han Li saw this, he faintly smiled and paid him no more attention.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 632: A Plot Unfolds

The others didn’t perceive Du Dong’s small movements, but Han Li did. He had spread out his spiritual sense earlier to observe his surroundings in case of any contingencies.

Although Du Dong appeared to be meditating, his lips trembled. He was clearly speaking through voice transmission to a conspirator in the room.

Fearing that he would alarm Dong Du, Han Li didn’t forcefully eavesdrop. Instead, he swept his spiritual sense for any hidden cultivators and ended up finding nothing out of the ordinary.

Han Li’s mind quickly stirred and his gaze swept past several people. For a while, he was unable to determine who the suspect was. But Han Li then heard Silvermoon’s voice in his mind.

“Brother Han, the Spirit Well Tree’s light barrier reaches underground as well. Although I have a way for forcing through it, I cannot guarantee that it won’t disturb the Core Formation cultivator within the barrier. Should I break through?” Silvermoon softly said.

Han Li replied without a moment of thought, “Don’t rashly take action! Force will only be used as a last resort. I reckon that in the chaos soon to come, there will be an opportunity to take action. Come back for now.”

Silvermoon obeyed and silently returned into Han Li’s body. He then closed his eyes and did nothing else apart from taking note of Du Dong’s actions.

After an unknown amount time had passed, Du Dong ceased speaking and he raised his hand while glancing around with a strange expression.

Han Li’s heart trembled. Just as he wondered whether or not he was about to take action, Du Dong unexpectedly lowered his head once more. Nothing seemed to have occurred, leaving Han Li baffled.

At that moment, a huge quake violently reverberated throughout the cave. All the meditating cultivators suddenly opened their eyes in alarm and they glanced at each other in astonishment.

The grey-clothed old man and the other two Core Formation cultivators revealed a trace of astonishment, but the yellow-clothed cultivator frowned and hastily walked towards the stone gate. However, before he even arrived the door opened to reveal the long-faced cultivator Hu walking in with a sullen expression.

“Senior Hu, what happened?” The yellow-clothed cultivator hastily asked.

The long-faced old man replied with a blood-thirsty tone, “This place was attacked! A group of concealed cultivators attacked the spell formation outside the valley. Not only are they all Core Formation cultivators, but there also seems to be a Nascent Soul eccentric among them. It seems they aren’t from the Righteous Dao Alliance, but the Six Devil Dao Sects. The other powers wouldn’t take such bold, heavy actions. Senior Lan has already left to take charge of the spell formation, you must follow me and support the defense. Leave behind Senior Martial Brother Wei. As for these disciples, postpone the matter of the Brightsight water for now. Fellow Daoist Yue, bring these disciples to a safe room. Senior Martial Brother Wei, if anyone dares to enter the cave during this time, kill them without hesitation.”

Old Man Wei calmly replied, “I understand. Brother Hu, go ahead and take them. I’ll stand guard here.”

When the long-faced old man heard this, he nodded his head with a relaxed expression and immediately brought the grey-clothed old man and the middle-aged man out.

The yellow-clothed cultivator ran to Han Li and the disciples, ordering, “You heard him. The eye cleansing is postponed. I will lead you to a safe room.” He then turned around and left the cave in large strides.

The young cultivators didn’t dare to delay and hastily followed after him.

Han Li calmly followed after them and inwardly sneered upon seeing Du Dong sincerely follow them out of the cave without taking any action.

Du Dong had acted calmly until now and didn’t reveal the slightest worry. Han Li found this particularly suspicious. This had all occurred at far too perfect a time for Du Dong to be uninvolved.

A short moment later, the ten disciples followed the yellow-robed cultivator west and entered a large stone room. After giving them several orders, he departed, clearly heading towards the battle above.

At that moment, a large eruption occurred in the distance, causing the ground to violently tremble. It seemed to be a result of the bitter fighting outside.

Seeing that the yellow-clothed cultivator had departed, the disciples began to gather together into their own sects and whisper.

Han Li, Du Dong, Mu Peiling, and Sun Huo stood together.

Sun Huo sighed and vented, “I truly didn’t expect that the Ancient Sword Sect’s Martial Uncle Bai was a Righteous Dao spy. I previously felt quite a bit of respect from him, thinking that he was a vagrant cultivator that managed to reach Core Formation!”

Mu Peiling coldly glanced at the youth and emotionlessly said, “Junior Martial Brother Sun, did you truly believe that a vagrant cultivator would be able to form a core so easily? Without the support from a large backer, how could someone possibly acquire the ability to enter Core Formation? However, Junior Martial Brother Sun is a genuine vagrant cultivator that has already been scouted by many clans. Would it not be better for Junior Martial Brother Sun to join one of them for greater assistance in the future?”

The determined youth wryly laughed and said, “I am still unconvinced that I must join a cultivation clan to form a core. I still feel it beneath my dignity to join one.”

His gaze then unconsciously wandered onto the woman’s beautiful face and revealed a trace of passion. However, Mu Peiling seemed unaware of this and didn’t continue speaking.

Du Dong then suddenly said, “However, Martial Uncle Bai does seem to be a pitiful individual.”

Mu Peiling’s bright eyes glanced at the large man in surprise. Sun Huo was also surprised by his words and wore an expression of doubt, asking, “Pitiful? Martial Nephew Du, what do you mean?”

Du Dong smiled in his ordinary, simple manner and paid them no heed. His gaze then turned to Han Li and he mysteriously said, “Junior Martial Brother Han, do you think my words make sense?”

Han Li didn’t reveal the slightest surprise that Du Dong turned the conversation towards him and indifferently replied, “No, I don’t know much about Martial Uncle Bai. I’m afraid I can’t say!”

“Is that so? However, I feel that...”

Just as Du Dong thought to say something further, Sun Huo angrily rebuked him for ignoring him, “Martial Nephew Du, you are far too impudent. Did you not hear my words?”

A cold glint flickered through Du Dong’s eyes as he glanced at the youth. With a sinister expression he said, “Why are you speaking so loudly? I heard you, but I have no interest in replying to such rubbish.”

“What?! You...”

Mu Peiling discovered something was amiss and her face grew sullen. With her hand on her storage pouch she icily asked, “Just who are you?”

The other disciples noticed that something was odd and couldn’t help but look at them with astonishment.

A man’s voice suddenly echoed from outside the room. “Hehe! He’s a direct bloodline disciple of the Devil Dao’s Thousand Illusions Sect. I hope that answer is to your satisfaction!”

Bang! The doors to the room suddenly shattered.

The sect disciples were greatly shocked and hastily took out their magic tools with vigilance. However, a familiar man had emerged beyond the shattered door.

“Martial Uncle Bai!” An Ancient Sword Sect disciple couldn’t help but shout out upon seeing him. His expression soon changed while his face was filled with disbelief.

When the other disciples saw this azure-robed cultivator appear before them, they were at a loss. They had clearly seen him restrained not long ago, yet he still appeared here. And from his lively spirits, it appeared as if his magic power wasn’t restricted in the slightest.

Du Dong didn't appear surprised by Cultivator Bai’s appearance in the least and coldly asked him, “Why did you arrive so late? Any longer and we would’ve taken action first.”

Cultivator Bai bluntly replied, “Humph! You don’t know how fearsome that old eccentric’s sword thread is. Although I had prepared for it, it still restrained me at the time. If it weren’t for your continuous guarantees that he wouldn’t have dared to take my life, do you think I would’ve cooperated with your side?”

“Hehe! We didn’t expect that the old eccentric would personally come. However, it had gone mostly as expected. Martial Uncle Feng and Senior Qin should’ve bought us enough time.”

After hearing their conversation, the other disciples knew that things were far from good. One of the Ancient Sword Sect disciples was particularly quick to react and immediately flew off on his magic tool towards the door in an attempt to escape.

But as soon as this disciple flew by Cultivator Bai’s side, a sinister expression appeared on his face and a dazzling white light flashed.

With a miserable scream, the disciple and the sword were split into two. With a clang , the corpse fell onto the ground.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 633: The Greater Sifting Mirage Technique vs the Fox Enrapturing Arts

In the instant the disciple was slain, the other cultivator’s faces grew deathly pale. They began to release their defensive magic tools as they stared at Cultivator Bai. For a moment, no one dared to move.

Mu Peiling’s expression greatly changed and she stepped away from Du Dong, releasing her own ribbon magic tool around her. As for Sun Huo, he had recoiled at the sight of this incisive strike and grimaced while his gaze flickered between Cultivator Bai and Du Dong.

Han Li silently slipped into a corner of the room and his gaze continuously swept around. It was unknown what was going through his mind.

At that moment, an imposing aura suddenly swelled from Du Dong. With lines of black talisman characters appearing on his neck, black light suddenly surged from his body as he underwent a sudden transformation. He grew to two meters in height, his appearance became malevolent, and his cultivation surged to mid-Core Formation stage.

When Cultivator Bai saw Du Dong’s astonishing transformation, he couldn’t help but laugh, “Very nice! If the Thousand Illusions Sect were to say they were ranked second in concealment techniques in the Heavenly South, no one would dare to proclaim themselves as first. The Greater Sifting Mirage Technique is truly worthy of being your sect’s signature technique.”

“Humph!” The transformed Du Dong merely snorted. He then gloomily swept past the crowd and his eyes stopped on Han Li. A malicious expression appeared on his face.

Woosh . The cultivators in the room only caught sight of the Du Dong disappearing in a blur before reappearing beside Han Li. With a wave his hand, Han Li’s light barrier was shattered in an instant and his hand pierced into Han Li’s chest like a bolt of lightning. He then withdrew his hand with a bloody heart in his grasp.

Han Li’s corpse fell onto the floor.

“Ah!” When the other disciples saw this bloody scene, they shouted out in alarm, believing that they would be the next to fall. Their hearts were all struck with terror.

“Huh?” The transformed Du Dong revealed a strange expression as if in disbelief that Han Li had died so easily. He frowned for a moment and glanced at his hand. From the warm and bloody heart in his grasp, it appeared he had truly killed him.

The scholarly man grew alarmed at Du Dong’s sudden attack, and he furiously shouted, “What are you doing!? You can’t kill these disciples; a few of them have influence. One of them is even a close descendant of Eccentric Heavenvenge. Don’t attack them as you please!”

Du Dong indifferently snorted,“If you can kill one, then so can I. Besides, given how odd that youngster was, it was better to take the initiative to deal with him. Also, this person definitely wasn’t Eccentric Heavenvenge’s descendant. He entered the sect at the same time I did.” Soon after, he tossed the heart onto the ground.

The scholar’s expression relaxed and he gravely said, “So long as you realize this, that’s fine! Although I don’t know whether or not Eccentric Heavenvenge’s descendant is male or female, nor what sect they entered, the sects should’ve given consideration to Eccentric Heavenvenge’s might and allowed them to enter the top ten disciples so that they may use the Brightsight Water. It would be a great inconvenience if they actually died. As for the person I killed, I was well aware of his background, and he definitely wasn’t the eccentric’s descendant.”

“Fine, I’ll refrain from killing the others as I wish. However, we can’t have them casually stir up trouble. I’ll have to properly knock them out for the time being!” With that said, Du Dong began to twirl in place and black radiance suddenly enveloped the entire room.

The other cultivators felt somewhat relieved by their words, but the black radiance instantly rendered them unconscious as soon as it reached them.

The scholarly man nodded his head with satisfaction, “Let’s go. We can’t delay here for too long.”

“Alright.”

With those curt words, they immediately walked out of the room with large strides.

But when Du Dong walked out, he felt somewhat uneasy and unconsciously glanced down at the heartless corpse. Han Li was lying in a pool of his own blood, dead as could be.

Du Dong couldn’t help but scoff, feeling that he was overly suspicious, and he followed after the scholarly man with peace of mind. Once the two departed, the room grew deathly quiet.

A short moment later, a young woman’s voice filled the room.

“Brother Han, my Fox Enrapturing Arts must surely be above that of the Greater Sifting Mirage Technique! That man’s cultivation wasn’t weak, but he couldn’t tell whether or not he had truly killed someone. Truly laughable!”

Shortly after that was said, Han Li’s bloody corpse began to shine with faint white light. Eventually, that light turned silver and transformed into a foot-long, snow-white fox.

Han Li’s voice began to slowly speak from a meter behind the white fox, “It truly is impressive. I find it odd how a wolf like you can be so proficient in fox techniques. However, this might also have to do with them having comparatively weaker cultivation. Were they late Core Formation cultivators, it might’ve been difficult to fool them. As for the Greater Sifting Mirage Technique, I must admit it is outstanding. Even I was incapable of telling his true cultivation while he concealed himself.” In a flash of yellow light, he walked out from the stone wall with a wolf-headed jade scepter in his hand.

At an unknown time, Han Li had stealthily entered the wall and had Silvermoon stand in for Han Li through an illusion technique. Although she couldn’t maintain the transformed body for long, it was more than enough to fool the two Core Formation cultivators.

Silvermoon was unconvinced as she curled her lips, “Is that technique truly that amazing? Wasn’t Brother Han simply mistaken?”

Han Li casually replied, “With the Great Development Technique, my spiritual sense is on par with that of a Nascent Soul cultivator. Yet, I was still unable to discover anything amiss about him. It could very well be the top concealment technique in the entire world, let alone the Heavenly South.”

Silvermoon tilted her small head, but she didn’t refute him.

Han Li walked towards the center of the room and gazed at those lying on the ground, noticing that they were all unconscious. His eyes then fell onto the black-robed youth, Meng Di. Silvermoon seemed to guessed what Han Li intended and she jumped onto the youth while she snatched the storage pouch from his waist. She then obediently jumped back to Han Li’s side and delivered it to him.

Han Li accepted it with a faint smile and swept his spiritual sense into it. After taking the jade box containing the Spirit Tempering Pill, he carelessly tossed the pouch back onto the youth’s body.

Since this item held little use towards a youth at this cultivation, Han Li happily accepted it.

After putting away the jade box, he rubbed his chin and said, “Let’s go. Those two should’ve already arrived at the Spirit Well Tree’s cave. Let’s go and take a look.” After Silvermoon jumped into his sleeve, he flew out of the room in a streak of azure light.

At that moment, there were continuous explosions occurring on the outside. When Han Li heard them, a trace of doubt momentarily appeared on his face, but he soon ignored the sounds.

When Han Li arrived at the cave, the stone gate was wide open and void of restrictions. There were also shouts of furious alarm faintly coming from within.

Du Dong furiously shouted, “Brother Wei, what do you mean? How can you suddenly betray us when we’ve reached this far? Could it be that you’ve forgotten the great kindness the sect master bestowed upon you? Or have you forgotten that you are a disciple of the Heavenly Fiend Sect after having stayed in the Drifting Cloud Sect for so many years?”

Han Li’s heart stirred upon hearing this. But before he could further listen in on their conversation, his expression suddenly changed and he disappeared from his original location.

A group of eight high grade cultivators suddenly entered the cave. Shockingly, there was even a Nascent Soul cultivator amongst them. These cultivators all concealed themselves inside the earth with a barrier of yellow light as if in preparation for an ambush. As a result, the three that were already in the hall remained ignorant of their presence.

Han Li then snuck in behind them and stood at a far corner, observing everything in silence.

These underground cultivators were all familiar to Han Li. They were the group that should’ve been defending the formation from the outside. Even the boy Nascent Soul Cultivator surnamed Lan was among them.

Han Li’s spiritual sense easily penetrated the light barriers of these cultivators, discovering the Core Formation cultivators that he had seen along the way, along with Cultivator Bai’s Dao companion who was now deathly pale. The woman was also carrying an unconscious man in her arms, the long-faced old man surnamed Hu.

Han Li felt his blood run cold upon seeing them. At the same time, doubt began to well up within his heart. The explosions outside had yet to stop as if there were still a battle occuring outside. However, there wasn’t actually a battle going on to destroy the formation; it was all a trap.

At that moment, the dishevel-haired old man slowly spoke from within the golden light barrier, “I know that the Righteous and Devil Dao had discovered an ancient Profound Goddess’s Palm near the Moulan Plains. Although this tree has long shriveled, so long as it is fed with the Wine Nectar of the Spirit Well Tree, it will flourish once more and regain life. As a result, we infiltrated the three sects many years ago as disciples in a reckless attempt to acquire it. At the time, we had even abandoned our plans to topple the three sects. And now even the young master of the Thousand Illusions Sect braved danger to infiltrate here as ‘Fellow Daoist Du’ to give orders for the Righteous and Devil Dao to cooperate.”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 635: Acquiring Roots

“Shameless!” Seeing that the possessed Cultivator Wei dared to attempt to kill someone in his presence, the scarlet light python in front of the boy trembled and split into countless translucent strands as it shot towards Truelord Heavenfiend.

At that same moment, Old Man Jiang’s expression greatly changed. He hastily spat out a yellow flying sword to protect himself and he flusteredly ran backwards. He didn’t dare to meet the sect master’s strike.

Truelord Heavenfiend strangely smiled and his direction suddenly changed, appearing at the side of the white-clothed woman. His purple claw suddenly moved to grab onto her arm.

The white-clothed woman had been at a loss ever since realizing the scholarly man was a spy. But in a face of Truelord Heavenfiend’s sudden attack, her complexion paled and she tossed the long-faced old man onto the ground without a single thought. Her hands then formed an incantation gesture and an azure streak flew out from her sleeve, attempting to block the incoming attack to the best of her abilities.

Truelord Heavenfiend wildly laughed in response and blurred once more, grabbing onto the long-faced old man that was tossed away. He then formed a fist with his free hand and covered it in turbulent purple light, striking against the incoming fiery red sword threads.

With a muffled groan, the old devil couldn’t help but recoil from the strike. However, he used its momentum to carry the long-faced old man back to his original location.

Though some unknown method, the long-faced old man was somehow roused. He leapt up and said, “Many thanks for Truelord’s rescue!”

“Humph! Don’t be mistaken! If we weren’t currently short on manpower, I wouldn’t have saved a Righteous Dao junior like you. You’ll have to preserve your life with your own skill.” Truelord Heavenfiend coldly snorted and shot towards the boy surnamed Lan in a blur.

This time, he was truly going to tie down the Child Fire Dragon and allow Du Dong the opportunity to escape.

“Go! The outside restrictions have already been sabotaged by me. Its power should only be a tenth of its original. We will be able to easily break through.” The long-faced old man appeared to also be a decisive character. After shouting to Du Dong and Cultivation Bai, he took the initiative to charge towards the Core Formation cultivators guarding the exit.

Du Dong and the scholarly man were delighted by what they heard. With one taking out two white swords and the other enveloping his body in black radiance, the three changed towards the cave exit.

The three sects’ Core Formation cultivators weren’t about to easily allow the three to escape. They all summoned their magic treasures to give them a painful welcome. The cave suddenly erupted into battle between the two sides. With furious shouts and sounds of explosions, various colored lights filled the cave.

When Han Li saw this, he felt that his opportunity was drawing near and decided to take action. With the jade scepter in hand, his body flashed in yellow light. He burrowed into the ground and hastily used an earth movement technique to silently draw close to the Spirit Well Tree’s roots.

Busy with their own battles, the cultivators in the cave hadn’t taken notice of Han Li’s opportunistic actions. As a result, Han Li arrived before a faint golden barrier blocking his way.

A spirited glint appeared in Han Li’s eyes. He raised his hands, releasing a torch of azure light from each of his fingers, and silently pressed them against the barrier. The golden light intertwined with the azure light for a moment and the light barrier began to tremble.

If it were peacetime, the golden barrier’s trembling would’ve long been perceived by the cultivators guarding the Spirit Well Tree. But in the middle of fierce combat, this small movement hadn’t aroused the slightest notice.

A short moment later, his hands had forcibly pierced through the golden light and a trace of joy appeared on his face. The light from his hands surged and he fiercely pulled his hands apart, creating a slender gap in the barrier for an instant.

Woosh. Han Li’s body blurred, reappearing inside before the light barrier mended itself.

Seeing that the Spirit Well Tree’s roots were before him, Han Li wore a rarely seen grin.

Although the trunk of the Spirit Well Tree greatly differed from ordinary trees, it roots were ordinary apart from its exceptionally jade-green color.

A huge explosion erupted from above the ground, followed by the sound of shards of falling earth along with a series of trembles. It seems a fearsome attack had just been used.

In the following moment, Old Man Fu flusteredly said, “Quickly, chase after them. We cannot allow them to escape.” The sound of rustling wind was followed by Truelord Heavenfiend’s hearty laughter.

“Fellow Daoist Lan, how is the power of my Purple Deepscreen Arts? Although I had to use up this body’s blood essence, I was able to easily tie you down for the time being.”

“Old Devil Heavenfield, do you not care for your disciple? Even if your disciple survives, his cultivation will be mostly destroyed.” Although the boy’s voice was detached and emotionless, Han Li could hear a trace of anger in his words.

“My disciple? This traitor? From what I’ve heard, he already considers himself a Drifting Cloud Sect disciple, so I have far less misgivings in using him. Huh? Old Ghost Lan? Where do you think you’re going?!” Truelord Heavenfiend’s voice was extremely calm as he said this, but his voice suddenly shouted out in alarm.

“Humph! I have no interest in tangling down with your incarnation. Those Devil Children cannot be allowed to take a Wine Nectar out from our Dreamcloud Mountains.” The boy’s voice grew more distant as if he had already left the cave.

“As if I’d so easily allow you to leave!” Truelord Heavenfiend shouted as if chasing after him.

In an instant, there was no one else left behind in the cave apart from Han Li. He grew completely at ease, no longer hesitating to take action. He extended one of his fingers shot out a sparkling beam of light. With a spark, a small portion of the root was easily cut through, causing a white liquid to overflow from the opening, filling the air with a fragrant aroma.

Han Li paid no notice to the white liquid spilling out. With his body shining with yellow light, he directly grasped onto the root segment and climbed to the surface.

He swept his gaze past the barrier and spotted a ten meter large hole in the cave with sparkling rocks that were scattered all around.

It seems this Truelord Heavenfiend had completely broken through the restrictions of the resilient cave walls through a single strike. This impressive display of skill should’ve given Du Dong and the others the opportunity to escape!

Han Li hurried after seeing this. He took out a finely carved jade box from his storage pouch and carefully placed the root segment into the box.

After putting it away with a heavy expression, Han Li revealed satisfaction but something soon came to mind. He may have acquired the Spirit Well Tree’s root, but he had still yet to acquire the refinement formula for the Brightsight Water and the Spirit Tempering Pill. Although that Truelord Heavenfiend managed to possess the body of the dishevel-haired old man, the body couldn’t endure his techniques for long. He would certainly be defeated by the boy before long.

With flashes of light flickering from Han Li’s hands as he stood next to the barrier of light, his expression suddenly stirred. With a trace of astonishment on his face, he frowned and walked around to the back of the Spirit Well Tree.

There was a yellow prayer mat and a foot-wide stone platform. The stone platform had a jade slip on top of it that was glistening with a faint green light.

Han Li swept his spiritual sense past the several items and discovered that there were no hidden restrictions on the items. He raised his hand and shot an azure mist from his palm, sweeping the jade slip into his grasp.

Han Li gazed at the jade slip and remained still as he began to read through the contents of the jade slip with his spiritual sense.

A short moment later, Han Li withdrew his spiritual sense from the jade slip with a bewildered expression. It contained the records of the dishevel-haired cultivator’s techniques and a few pill refinement insights. The refinement formula for the Spirit Tempering Pill and the Brightsight Water were astonishingly among them.

With the jade slip in hand, Han Li’s mind grew vacant.

Could it be that dishevel-haired cultivator had felt his lifespan coming to an end and had prepared this jade slip? From how the jade slip had been hidden behind the Spirit Well Tree, it seemed he had left it behind for a Drifting Cloud Sect cultivator. Could this action hold some sort of meaning?

Han Li pondered a moment more while glancing at the jade slip. He then fetched a white jade slip from his storage pouch and quickly copied over the contents.

At Han Li’s current cultivation, replicating a jade slip took only a moment’s worth of effort.

Han Li placed the green jade slip back in its original place and put the white replica inside his storage pouch before walking back towards the golden light barrier. Since the three sects’ cultivators could come back at any moment, he’d best leave as soon as possible. In any case, he already fulfilled his objective.

Without worry of anybody spotting him, Han Li’s body flowed with spiritual power, cleaving a large hole in the barrier with a spark of azure light.

In the instant the hole was formed, he directly transformed into an azure streak of light and rushed out.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 636: Return

When Han Li quietly returned to the safe room, he discovered that the young disciples were still unconscious, lying disorderly around the floor.

Although their aptitudes were exceptional, they were still only low grade disciples. It was no surprise as to why they were overlooked during the moment of the climax of the battle.

Silvermoon had already transformed into Han Li, lying on the floor in an unconscious state. When she saw that he arrived, she immediately turned back into a fox and leaped into Han Li’s sleeve.

Silvermoon chuckled and asked, “How was it? Did you acquire it? By the way, nobody came. It seems Fellow Daoist was being overly careful!”

Han Li insipidly said, “It went smoothly! However, it was still better to be careful than to allow myself to be revealed.”

Silvermoon easily changed the topic and worriedly asked, “However, how will Brother Han explain his survival? This seems to be quite troublesome.”

“How I will explain it? Just say the truth!” Han Li appeared to not take this matter very seriously and spoke carelessly.

“The truth?” Silvermoon spoke with bewilderment.

As if having already thought of this, Han Li calmly explained, “I’ll just say that I previously bought a high grade illusion talisman and used it to save my life. Those who aren’t skilled in the Dao of Illusions should be none the wiser and will take the excuse at face value.”

Silvermoon soon chuckled, “Not bad. That is a rather good excuse.”

The following moments were rather simple. After half a day, a yellow-clothed cultivator walked into the safe room with a solemn expression.

Seeing that all the disciples were unconscious, he sighed and formed an incantation gesture with his hands. With a flick of his finger, a streak of white light flew into each of the cultivator’s bodies.

It was clear that the technique used to knock them out wasn’t profound in the slightest. After a short moment, each of them regained consciousness and saw that the yellow-clothed cultivators had taken the place of Du Dong and Cultivator Bai. They grew relaxed in an instant.

Of course, when they saw that Han Li was intact and unharmed, they were greatly frightened. But Han Li soon took out an illusion talisman and gave an explanation that he had prepared in advance.

As expected, considering that few delved deeply into the Dao of Illusions, mostly no one raised any suspicions. As for the yellow-clothed cultivator, he merely glanced at Han Li in surprise and didn’t further ask about it.

But for Sun Huo and Mu Peiling, they both wore a trace of doubt. After all, Du Dong had spoken to Han Li from the very start and even attacked Han Li immediately after revealing himself. It had left quite the impression on them.

Han Li wasn’t particularly worried about their doubts. Since the two didn’t have any proof, what could they possibly say? Besides, Du Dong’s sudden attack was by no means a sign of friendliness!

With the absence of the Wine Nectar and the unknown fate of the dishevel-haired cultivator to refine the Brightsight Water, the matter of the Brightsight Water had dissolved.

As a result, the upper echelon of the three sects hurriedly announced the conclusion of the Sword Trial Assembly, only giving a magic tool to each of the final ten as compensation. The three sects then returned back to their owns sects without any intention of travelling together with each other’s groups.

Seeing that their Core Formation Seniors wore such solemn and anxious faces, even an idiot would know that something drastic had happened while the ten finalists were left unconscious.

Although the low grade disciples were unsatisfied and gloomy, they could only obediently return to their sects.

Once Han Li and the others returned to the Drifting Cloud Sect, they were hastily summoned by the sect’s higher echelon and were closely questioned on what had happened in the restricted area. After that, they were sent away with unsightly expressions and were ordered to keep silent.

Afterwards, Han Li came to realize that the three sects’ plan to oust their spies had ended up an utter failure.

Not only did Dong Du and company manage to bring back the Wine Nectar to the Righteous and Devilish Dao with the assistance of the Heavenly Fiend Sect Master’s incarnation, but they mostly managed to leave the State of Xi without any harm. However, Cultivator Bai had made a mistake and was promptly killed by Old Man Fu and the others.

As for when the Heavenly Fiend Sect Master’s possession expired, the dishevel-haired cultivator was captured by the boy, and no one had heard of him since. It was unknown whether he was executed or spared.

The two Nascent Soul elders of the Drifting Cloud Sect and the three sect’s various Core Formation cultivators had been ruthlessly attacked by the Devil Dao’s Thousand Illusions Sect and the Heavenly Fiend Sect in an ambush. Not only were several Core Formation cultivators killed, but the Nascent Soul cultivator surnamed Cheng was heavily injured. Although there is no worry for his life, his origin Qi was greatly damaged.

This matter had greatly shaken the three sects. They began to ferociously pressure the Righteous and Devil Dao sects through the Heavenly Dao Union, but they continued to deny this matter had ever occurred. As a result, nothing came to be, leaving the three sects’ upper echelon with their hands tied.

But fortunately for them, through the Heavenly Dao Union’s own spies in the Righteous and Devil Dao, they were able to discover that the Wine Nectar was ineffective. After using it to water the Profound Goddess’ Palm, the tree remained in its withered state without change.

This information had brought a breath of relief to the Heavenly Dao Union.

Following these events, the three factions each became more vigilant and their peaceful attitude from the last hundred years began to grow tense. Conflict became a more likely possibility as time passed by.

...

As soon as Han Li finished reporting to the sect elders, he immediately returned to his cave residence. He headed straight to the room with the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng and planted the root of the Spirit Well Tree right next it. Since the two items were both spiritual objects born of heaven and earth, they might mutually nourish one another if they were placed close together.

In the following days after Han Li finished answering his fellow sect members about the Sword Trial Assembly, Han Li began to wholeheartedly cultivate. Perhaps due to the influence of the Sword Trial Assembly, he was finally able to breakthrough his bottleneck for the Great Development Technique. Han Li’s cultivation then proceeded to advance as he simultaneously cultivated the Great Development Technique and the Azure Essence Sword Arts, much to his delight.

He clearly understood that the reason he was able to cultivate the Great Development Technique in such a smooth manner was most likely due to the Soul Nurturing Wood beads that he wore around his neck.

Ever since he wore the beads around his neck, his spiritual sense had been gradually growing larger regardless of any effort he made to temper it. This had allowed him to rapidly progress in the Great Development Technique in an unobstructed manner, as if he were refilling a pond that had already formed.

Additionally, every time he cultivated the Great Development Technique, the Soul Nurturing Wood beads would cause his spirit to feel refreshed, allowing him to achieve greater results with less strain and effort.

During this time, Han Li began to use the green liquid to mature the root of the Spirit Well Tree every few days. As a result of a few short months, a sapling began to shoot out from the root. It appeared it was only a matter of time before it grew as large as the Spirit Well Tree in the restricted area. Han Li reckoned that it would take twenty years of meticulous care.

However, he wasn’t in a hurry. He would need many years before he could reach false Nascent stage. Furthermore, he already had a Spirit Tempering Pill on hand. It didn’t matter if it would take any longer.

With that thought, Han Li imagined the moment when the black-robed youth looked through his storage pouch only to astonishingly discover that the Spirit Tempering Pill had disappeared. Han Li couldn’t help but find it funny.

The most important reason why he had tried so hard to acquire the Spirit Well Tree was for the Brightsight Water. With his eyes cleansed from the Brightsight Water, he would gain an immense benefit in battle. Combined with his superior spiritual sense, he would be able to repeatedly decisively strike against his foes’ weaknesses.

At the same time, it wasn’t as if Han Li had given up on practicing pill refinement. He was still making his own preparations to eventually refine the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng.

With this, time slowly passed by between bitter cultivation and pill refinement.

During this time, apart from some required social interaction, Han Li didn’t take a single step from his cave residence. Amidst crucial moments for his cultivation that required focused seclusion, Han Li sent Silvermoon in his place to deal with the fellow sect members that occasionally paid him a visit.

Fortunately, Silvermoon’s fox body had made rapid improvements in the wake of large consumptions of medicine pills. Her illusion techniques have become increasingly intricate, revealing not the slightest flaw.

As for Mu Peiling, she still held her doubts, but after Han Li returned to the Drifting Cloud Sect, only to maintain a low profile, her suspicions eventually faded away. She came to merely view Han Li as a completely ordinary Qi Condensation cultivator.

Consequently, Han Li became more at ease for staying at the Drifting Cloud Sect.

In the blink of an eye, Han Li had spent twenty years at the Drifting Cloud Sect as a Qi Condensation disciple.

The day that he was about to condense his Nascent Soul was just around the corner.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 639: Nascent Soul (3)

With a light bang , the translucent ball brightly flashed, surrounding itself in a mist of rainbow light that was three meters wide. It quickly flew down and bore into the mountain in an instant. At that same moment, the dark storm clouds up above instantly disappeared, restoring the sky to normal.

This sudden change of events left the surrounding cultivators at a loss.

In the following moments, a series of dragon-like roars cried from the mountains, shaking the very heavens and earth. A three hundred meter tall silhouette of light then emerged from the mountain.

This silhouette sparkled with four-colored light and its limbs were incredibly thick, but because of the radiance that surrounded it, none were able to clearly see its true features. They were merely left with an impression of immense awe, causing the onlookers to turn their gazes away in deference. But most astonishing of all was when the silhouette nodded its head, sweeping two beams of dense light across the cultivators present, causing them to lose their breaths in an instant.

With the sound of several thumps, these cultivators felt their bodies grow heavy and they immediately knelt down. They weren’t able to move in the slightest as if Mount Tai itself were pressing down upon them. Although a few of the cultivators with deeper cultivations were able to force themselves to stand, their legs were trembling and the veins on their forehead throbbed. It appeared to take a rather strenuous effort.

As these cultivators became filled with apprehension and inwardly cursed, the huge silhouette smiled and its body suddenly scattered, filling the sky with countless specks of starlight.

This scene has left the observers dumbstruck.

...

Han Li sat cross-legged at the center of the quiet room with his eyes shut. But at the very top of his head, there was foot-tall infant that was amusing itself with his hair.

This infant had delicate skin, an azure barrier of light surrounding its entire body, and a face entirely like Han Li. However, the happy excitement on its face was entirely different from Han Li’s usual calm and taciturn manner.

As for Han Li’s main body, his complexion was rosy and his expression was serene as if he were soundly asleep.

A short moment later, the infant apparently grew tired from its playing and yawned. With an azure flash of light, it entered through the top of Han Li’s head into the body. Han Li’s expression then began to stir and his eyelids trembled. They eventually opened to reveal a hidden warmth contained in his bright, clear gaze.

He didn’t immediately stand up after awakening. Instead, he wore an expression that contained a trace of wild joy. He extended his palm and began to look across it several times. He then raised his hand and rubbed the top of his head with complete puzzlement.

After the time it took to finish a cup of tea, Han Li’s excitement eventually faded away from his face, only to be replaced with his usual calm.

He swept his gaze past the silent room and stretched himself before eventually standing up. He then extended his finger and shot a beam of azure light towards the stone door. With a flash of light, it silently opened.

Having stood guard outside Han Li’s room, Silvermoon transformed into the form of a gorgeous young woman upon spotting Han Li. She immediately lowered her head and respectfully saluted him, “Congratulations Master on forming your Nascent Soul!” Her careful and deliberate attitude somewhat surprised Han Li.

Han Li rubbed his chin and casually said, “Master? It seems that Fellow Daoist Silvermoon now truly recognizes me! However, that was to be expected. Before I formed a Nascent Soul, my cultivation was around the same level as yours. How could you have fully accepted me then?”

With complete respect on her face, Silvermoon said, “Master’s words are true. Now that Master has condensed a Nascent Soul, he has now entered the highest realm in the cultivation world. Your lifespan has been lengthened to over a thousand years, but you’ve only lived around two hundred years so far. With just a bit of luck, I believe it is possible that Master will be able to cultivate to the Deity Transformation stage.

Han Li shook his head and tranquilly said, “It is a bit too early to speak of Deity Transformation stage; it is still so far away.. Most of the Nascent Soul cultivators I’ve met were stuck at early Nascent Soul stage without any way to progress forward. You shouldn’t be too hopeful.”

“Still, I hold much confidence in you, Master.” Silvermoon pursed her lips and sweetly smiled, revealing a particularly alluring charm. Regardless, Han Li still disapproved of her words.

As of current, over a thousand cultivators had gathered nearby. They surrounded the mountain on their magic tools and were whispering to one another. With their inexperience and ignorance, they naturally didn’t know what the recent omen had signified. They could only make a few wild guesses. But from what had just happened, they couldn’t help but reveal giddy excitement.

Naturally, the medicinal garden Han Li was assigned to had attracted quite a bit of attention. The bystanders had already forced their way through the restrictions to take a look. However, they only found it to be an ordinary medicinal garden that didn’t have a soul in sight.

Mu Peiling were among those that had rushed to the scene. Her expression wavered as she witnessed all that had happened. She had a faint feeling that this fantastical display had something to do with Han Li.

At that moment, several streaks of various colored lights suddenly arrived. The lights faded away to reveal six Core Formation cultivators with heavy expressions. They were headed by the late Core Formation cultivator surnamed Feng. At his side stood a red-robed old man, the beautiful woman surnamed Song, as well as several other unfamiliar cultivators.

Old Man Feng raised his brow at the sight of so many low grade cultivators and icily said, “All disciples, listen well. The area five kilometers away from the mountain has temporarily become a restricted area. If anyone is to violate this, they will be punished severely.”

When the disciples heard their Martial Ancestor give his orders, they could only obey despite the great curiosity they all held and promptly departed.

A Core Formation cultivator with an ordinary appearance suddenly sent a sound transmission to Old Man Feng and pointed to the medicine garden down below. The old man’s expression stirred and he called out to a woman nearby, “Martial Niece Mu, stay behind for now.”

“As you command, Martial Uncle!” The woman was startled for a moment but she immediately flew before the Core Formation cultivators with a respectful expression.

Old Man Feng’s expression relaxed and he said, “Martial Niece Mu, I heard you were in charge of this medicine garden.”

“Yes! This medicine garden is being cared for by a Qi Condensation cultivator by the name of Han Li.”

“Qi Condensation disciple? Where is he now?”

Mu Peiling hesitated for a moment before replying, “I do not know. Several Senior Martial Brothers charged into the medicine garden to take a look, but he was nowhere to be found.”

The red-robed old man’s expression stirred and he asked with surprise, “Han Li? Was it that external affair disciple that made it to the top ten in the last Sword Trial Assembly? The twenty year old youth?”

“Martial Uncle Duan is correct. It is that disciple.” The woman wasn’t surprised that he knew this, given that he had led them to the last Sword Trial Assembly.

“It was truly odd that an external affair disciple was able to make it into the top ten. Could it be the omen of a Nascent Soul formation came from him?” Old Man Feng muttered to himself with a complicated expression. The other Core Formation cultivators wore a solemn expression when they heard him.

The woman surnamed Song had a particularly noticeable shift in her expression. The omen of a Nascent Soul. Could it be this person who formed a Nascent Soul?

While the others had taken it well enough, when Mu Peiling heard his ludicrous words, she felt completely shocked.

The red-robed cultivator slowly said, “Senior Martial Feng, from what has happened, it seems this person had already condensed a Nascent Soul. How should we respond to him?”

“Although they are a newly formed Nascent Soul cultivator, we are by no means their match. I reckon that the two Martial Uncles will soon personally come to deal with this matter. As for now, we must avoid all means of angering him.” Just as he finished uttering his orders, his expression suddenly replaced and he shouted, “Yi! The Martial Uncles have already arrived.”

When the others heard him, they felt relief and turned their heads towards the sky, spotting two glints of light in the distant skies. The glints of light soon turned into a streak of white and yellow light that approached them.

When Old Man Feng and company saw this, they immediately separated into two rows and wore a respectful expression.

An instant later, the grey-haired old man and the sallow-faced middle-aged man appeared before the Core Formation cultivators, and the old man indifferently said, “This matter may be passed onto us to deal with. You may do as you wish, but don’t remain here.”

When the others heard this, they each acknowledged him and left the vicinity of the stone mountain.

Of course, Mu Peiling didn’t dare to stay behind and hastily flew off after saluting the two Nascent Soul Ancestors. However, she couldn’t help but take one last look at the medicinal garden before she departed.

‘Could it truly be Han Li that had formed a Nascent Soul?’ The woman’s heart grew turbulent at the thought and her expression grew vacant.

At that moment when Silvermoon was speaking with a relaxed expression, the long-winded and aged voice came from the outside, “Congratulations on Fellow Daoist’s successful Nascent Soul Formation. I am the Drifting Cloud Sect’s Cheng Tiankun. Could my Junior Martial Brother and I enter your residence for a chat?”

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 645: Copulative Essence Arts

Mu Peiling blushed and softly said, “As you bid, Lord!”

Han Li withdrew his wanton gaze from her body. He took a purple jade medallion out from his robes and placed it on the table. He said with a cold voice, “Return and handle your affairs. Pick a mountain for your cave residence as well. This is a restriction medallion for the surrounding formations. If you wear it on your person, you will be able to leave my spell formations as you please. Once everything is prepared, I will place down a soul restriction on you and have you officially become my concubine, but let's get the ugly talk out of the way first. I don’t care if you have an ideal husband or a beloved. Cleanly sever ties with them; you are my concubine now. If you still have feelings of longing for them and still possess relations with them, don’t blame me for being ruthless. Now is the time to withdraw if you still possess any second thoughts.”

“Since I was small, I’ve dedicated myself to walking the path of immortal cultivation. How could I have a beloved? Besides, I have steeled my resolve. I won’t back down when the matter has already been decided.” Without a further thought, the woman nimbly took the jade medallion.

Han Li nodded his head and said no further. Soon after, he summoned a huge ape puppet and had it guide Mu Peiling outside.

Mu Peiling revealed a trace of surprise upon seeing the puppet. The puppet fearsomely held a level of spiritual Qi similar to her own. She was also puzzled as to why the white-clothed woman wasn’t there as well.

However, she knew that it was best to avoid probing too deeply and obediently kept quiet, following the puppet out from the cave residence.

Once the woman left, a white fox walked out from what appeared to be an empty corner of the room. “Since Master planned on taking this woman as a concubine for her punishment, why did you agree to wait thirty years? Could it be you have other plans?”

Han Li calmly admitted, “Of course I do. To tell the truth, I have no plans to touch her before she reaches Core Formation.”

Silvermoon hopped onto the table in front of Han Li and gazed at Han Li in a puzzled manner, “Huh? Why might that be?”

When Han Li saw her adorable appearance, he couldn’t help but smile. He took out a pink jade talisman from his waist and placed it on the table.

“Do you recall the storage pouch I looted off the disciple of Archsaint Six Paths? This jade slip was in his storage pouch. It contains many Devil Dao pair cultivation arts.”

Silvermoon looked at the jade slip and then glanced at Han Li with a trace of suspicion. Since Han Li took this out, she knew that Han Li would continue his explanation.

As expected, Han Li lightly stoked the pink jade slip with his finger and unhurriedly said, “There are many secret techniques contained inside this jade talisman. Although they are more powerful than ordinary pair cultivation techniques, the difference can’t be considered much. However, there were two secret techniques among them that were particularly exceptional. One of them, the Dragon Guiding Arts, are particularly suitable for Core Formation males, allowing a Core Formation cultivator to unceasingly draw on the vital Yin essence of a woman with a special constitution, greatly raising their cultivation.

“However, this secret technique was certain to cause great harm to the woman’s origin Qi. As such, any male cultivators using this technique would best have many concubines. Considering the many Foundation Establishment women at Archsaint Six Paths’ disciple’s side, he should’ve cultivated this technique. Otherwise, there would be no way he could’ve cultivated to late Core Formation stage at his young age, no matter how amazing his aptitude. After all, he didn’t have a miraculous bottle that could age plants.

“As for the other technique, the Copulative Essence Arts, its a secret pair cultivation technique that is specialized for Nascent Soul men. Unlike the Dragon Guiding Arts, it requires a woman to possess cultivation at Core Formation stage. Once a woman cultivates this technique to a deep enough stage, the male cultivator would be able to forcefully break through a cultivation bottleneck in an instant by seizing her vital Yin. It is only natural that I wish for this woman to cultivate with all her might. This technique requires a woman possessing deep cultivation after all.”

“Dragon Guiding Arts! Copulative Essence Arts! Isn’t it an exaggeration for a pair cultivation technique to be so fearsome?!” The small fox blinked and revealed disbelief.

Han Li sighed and said, “I had similar thoughts to you at the beginning, for a pair cultivation technique to be so fearsome; its simply unprecedented. However, I discovered the name of the person who established these pair cultivation techniques inside the jade slip, and my doubts were immediately dispelled.”

Silvermoon seemed to have thought of something and couldn’t help but softly shout, “Yi! Could it be...”

Han Li said with a deep voice, “That’s right! These two pair cultivation techniques were personally established by Archsaint Six Paths. Since he is a late Nascent Soul cultivator and is renowned as the number one figure in the Scattered Star Sea’s Devil Dao, these two techniques should be greatly effective. Otherwise, Archsaint Six Paths’ disciple couldn’t have kept it so closely on his person.”

Silvermoon tilted her furry head and hesitantly asked, “So Master plans on using this woman to cultivate...”

“That’s right. Once this woman reaches late Core Formation stage, we will both cultivate the Copulative Essence Arts. And once I reach a bottleneck, I will use this technique to breakthrough it. After all, there are few medicine pills that are capable of assisting in the cultivation of a Nascent Soul cultivator. From now on, my cultivation speed will be pathetically slow. Since a vast majority of Nascent Soul cultivators are stuck at the early stage, it can be observed that it is extremely difficult to breakthrough the bottleneck to mid Nascent Soul stage. As such, I must make an attempt, regardless of the validity of the technique’s effects.

“It is only a pity that according to what was described, the bottleneck breakthrough will only occur for the first time the technique is used. It will have longer have this effect once the woman's vital yin is taken. Of course, this technique also benefits the woman involved as well, but not nearly to the extent of the male cultivator. Tell me, did you think that I truly thought I acquired a concubine merely because I could?” Han Li glanced at the white fox at the side and coldly smiled.

Silvermoon appeared to sigh with relief and smiled, “At first, I did! I had thought that Master has grown proud after forming a Nascent Soul and thought to take in a concubine as a result.”

When Han Li heard this, he wore a vague expression. He then expressionlessly said, “Although I will place the woman underneath a soul restriction, it is better that she doesn’t learn of all the secrets in the cave residence. I will be able to control this woman’s very life, but I cannot control her thoughts. Just because I treat her well doesn’t necessarily mean she will be grateful. I will first treat her with great caution so I may avoid being betrayed from a moment of carelessness.

“This ‘Martial Aunt’ Mu is rather intelligent, but it would be best to keep watch of her. If she truly wishes to follow me and is unswayed by the wills of others, I will not treat her unfairly and will assist in her cultivation. After all, I have an abundance of low grade medicine pills. Silvermoon, keep an eye on her for me when you’re free. It should be a trivial effort given your skills.”

Silvermoon obediently agreed, “Yes, Master! When you are in secluded cultivation, I will particularly pay attention to her.”

“That will do. These thirty years should be enough for me to read her. I hope she doesn’t disappoint me!” During that final sentence, Han Li’s tone became sullen.

Several days later, Mu Peiling returned to the mountain and was subjected to a soul restriction by Han Li. Afterwards, she was gifted with a few bottles of medicine pills effective for Foundation Establishment cultivators. This gift had amazed her and caused her face to blossom with beauty from her delight. She eagerly expressed her thanks with adoring respect. It appeared this woman had truly thought of herself as his concubine.

After the silver-haired old man and Cultivator Lu were notified that Han Li had taken her in as a concubine, they expressed their congratulations and each gifted a top grade magic tool to Mu Peiling.

Han Li smiled in response and politely thanked them.

From then on, Mu Peiling began to dedicatedly cultivate at one of the smaller mountains surrounding the main cave residence, provided both with Han Li’s guidance and medicine pills.

During this time, Han Li would occasionally pay a visit to the cave residences of the other two Nascent Soul cultivators in the sect, humbly asking for cultivation instruction. Since the two Drifting Cloud elders intended to sincerely accept Han Li into their fold, they hid nothing from him, much to Han Li’s benefit. In hindsight, Han Li felt his choice to stay was extremely wise.

Several months later, Han Li was delighted to discover the Spirit Well Tree in the medicine garden started to shed Wine Nectar. He hastily began to refine the Brightsight Water according to the instructions that the dishevel-haired cultivator left behind.

With Han Li’s grandmaster-level skills in medicine pill refinement, he quickly grasped the knack of refining the spirit water and found it easy to concoct despite his first few failed attempts.

Currently inside the pill refinement room, Han Li was holding onto a small bottle of Brightsight Water that he concocted earlier. His gaze flickered when something suddenly came to mind, and his expression soon became determined. He opened the bottle with one hand and caused his hand to flash with azure light in the other. A ball of translucent blue liquid flew out from the bottle and slowly made its ways towards Han Li’s forehead.

By the the time the water arrived in front of Han Li’s forehead, it suddenly stopped and became completely still.

Han Li looked at the water with narrowed eyes and remained silent. A short moment later, he opened his mouth and breathed out a small mist of azure light and enveloped the water. Then as the water sparkled, two fine strands of water suddenly shot out and entered Han Li’s eyes.

Han Li felt his eyes warm up, but a moment later, the warmth turned into a bone-chilling cold. He shut his eyes and trembled from the sensation.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 647: Setting off on a Journey

Since the Celestial Ice Flames would allow him to easily exterminate Nascent Soul cultivators, Han Li didn’t dare to be careless. He possessed several techniques for refining devilfire, but he ended up choosing one of the secret techniques contained in the Profound Yin Arts as he felt it to be the most reliable.

Having decided, Han Li attentively stared at the golden ball of lightning for a moment and extended his finger towards it. With a crackle , a fine sliver of lightning suddenly arced from his finger and shot towards the golden ball. Suddenly, the golden ball trembled several times and brightly shone before being dragged into the air by the sliver of lightning.

Han Li sat down and raised his head to look up at the golden ball with narrowed eyes. At that point, he began to form a series of complicated incantation gestures with his hands.

With rolls of thunder, dense arcs of golden lightning began to flicker and form an impenetrable net of lightning surrounding the ball. Once the ball of lightning was surrounded by the net, the scene grew still.

At that moment, Han Li sighed and his spiritual sense stirred, connecting with the shell of Divine Devilbane Lightning surrounding the Celestial Ice Flames. Thunderous bellows reverberated throughout the room and the golden sphere grew dazzling. Fine arcs of lightning began to repeatedly shoot out from the golden sphere and its bindings relaxed, revealing a deep blue, translucent pearl underneath.

Han Li held his breath upon seeing the Celestial Ice Pearl. Having personally witnessed its power before, fear of it still lingered in his heart.

With the ice pearl’s appearance, Han Li spat out an azure flying sword from his mouth without further thought and momentarily pressed his hands together. A dense bolt of lightning suddenly shot out from his hands, simultaneously striking the ice pearl in an overbearing attack alongside the flying sword.

The pearl cracked open with a boom . With a pulse of light, the sphere turned into a unstable sphere of blue flames. The sphere of flames then expanded before condensing into a fist-sized blue flower. Each of its petals glistened as the flower slowly blossomed.

Simultaneously, a layer of blue frost began to spread throughout the walls, enveloping the entire room in a realm of freezing ice in the blink of an eye.

However, Han Li had long prepared for this. Although a solemn expression appeared on his face, he remained calm as a dense layer of azure light securely protected his body. With his Nascent Soul cultivation, he was able to completely protect himself from the assault of the icy flames, fearsome as they may be.

Han Li felt somewhat relieved to see that the icy Qi was unable to penetrate the light barrier protecting his body and proceeded to point into the air. The net of Divine Devilbane Lightning immediately shrunk back and enveloped the blue flower of light. Underneath the golden sparkling light and blue radiance, the huge blue flower began to change once more into a flame attempting its utmost to resist the lightning net’s constriction.

Seeing that the Celestial Ice Flames were restricted, Han Li took a deep breath and began to move his spiritual sense. Claps of thunder rang out as a small hole opened from the golden net, only to be mended a moment later. But in that short instance, a sliver of blue flame escaped and shot towards Han Li as if it were intelligent.

Han Li expressionlessly clasped his hands in an incantation in response and he closed his eyes. Azure Qi began to flow out from the crown of his head, followed by the emergence of an inch-tall Nascent Soul.

The Nascent Soul’s face appeared tense. As soon as it appeared, it stared at the incoming wisp of blue flame and it twisted its chubby arms, releasing two streaks of blinding azure light. At the same time, it opened its mouth and spat out a fist-sized ball of light, resulting in three masses of azure light meeting the wisp of blue flame.

The azure light and blue flame clashed, but the blue flame was instantly enveloped by the azure light. Despite its struggle, the flame was truly too small and was easily overwhelmed. However, even as the flame wisp was trapped, it slowly dissipated the light around it.

When the Nascent Soul saw the flame was successfully contained, a smile appeared on its face and beckoned to the azure light, bringing the flame wisp closer to it.

After revealing a trace of hesitation and fear, the Nascent Soul eye’s brightly glinted and grasped onto the azure light, shoving it down its mouth alongside the wisp of blue flame it contained.

Shortly after, azure light flashed from its body and the Nascent Soul disappeared into mist as it flew back into Han Li’s head.

Han Li’s eyelids trembled several times in response, but his expression unchanged as if he were sleeping. However, inside his Dantian, his Nascent Soul sat cross-legged wearing a solemn expression as its hands formed an incantation gesture.

...

Half a year later, Han Li emerged from the silent room with a gloomy expression.

The Celestial Ice Flames were truly ferocious. Although he had attempted to refine only a sliver of flame, it had taken half a year of hard effort. However, due to the flame’s extreme coldness, he would need to nurture it inside his body for an additional year before he could truly control it. In order to prevent any mishap, he couldn’t refine any more of the Celestial Ice Flames during this time. As for the Heavenvoid Cauldron, he refined far too little of the Celestial Ice Flames to even think of attempting the next step.

The reason why Han Li left seclusion now instead of continuing to cultivate was to visit the silver-haired old man and Cultivator Lu. He wanted to see if either of them had any news with regards to Auric Essence.

Additionally, he planned on bidding farewell to the Drifting Cloud Sect for some time. During his travels, he would pay a trip to the State of Yuan Wu in order to fulfill his promise with Xin Ruyin. [1]

At his current cultivation, exterminating a cultivation clan should only be a trivial effort.

As for the Fu Clan of the Hundred Possibilities Sect and the State of Yuan Wu, they did share some history together. The Fu Clan in the State of Yuan Wu was a distant branch of the Fu Clan in the Hundred Possibilities Sect.

However, the two clans grew distant over a long period of time and the Fu Clan in the State of Yuanwu had joined the Devil Dao, much to the resentment of the main branch who were part of the Heavenly Dao Alliance. As a result, both sides had cut relations to one another.

Han Li grew greatly relieved from this turn of events. Although the State of Yuan Wu belonged to the Devil Dao, there would be few in that country that would be capable of stopping him.

When Han Li left his cave residence, he visited the side residence in passing and swept his spiritual sense inside the cave residence to discover Mu Peiling strenuously cultivating in seclusion. From the light glistening from her face, it appeared that she had made great progress.

Pleased with her efforts, Han Li left without disturbing her and headed straight towards the main mountain of the Drifting Cloud Sect.

Six hours later, Han Li silently left the cave residence of the silver-haired old man. The old man didn’t have any concrete information on any Auric Essence, but he had informed him that in two years, there would be a grand trade fair taking place in the Nine Nation Union’s State of Yu. It was known to be the greatest trade fair to take place in the Heavenly South Region.

Many rare materials would gather there from all around the Heavenly South Region. Even half of the continent’s Nascent Soul cultivators would each make a trip there. After all, Nascent Soul cultivators were the ones who most required precious materials. Since common materials and medicines were simply beneath their notice, their only option was to find trade meetings and acquire their rare needs there.

The reason why the trade fair was to be held in the Nine Nations Union was because the Nine Nations Union was considered a neutral power. Due to the threat of the Moulan Spell Warriors, the other three powers had no fear of the Nine Nations Union harboring any wicked schemes. As a result, the cultivators of those three powers had no misgivings participating in the trade fair.

Currently, Han Li could only hope that Auric Essence would appear at trade fair. Otherwise, he couldn’t possibly know when he’d be able to use the Aureate Sword Formation. He may even have to pay a visit to the legendary Great Empire of Jin, but that was truly too far away.

After Han Li finished asking the silver-haired old man about the Auric Essence, he told the old man that he planned leaving the sect for some time. He didn't mention where he was going to go, only that he planned on traveling for some time as he had just formed his Nascent Soul, and that he was taking his leave.

When the silver-haired old man heard him, he wasn’t suspicious in the slightest. He merely mentioned the affiliations of each country and the names of a few Nascent Soul cultivators that Han Li should take notice of and never offend. At that moment, Han Li heard the name of this Eccentric Heavenvenge once more.

Han Li was quite curious towards this cultivator and made a note of him. He then expressed his thanks to the old man and departed.

On the morning of the next day, Han Li stored the most important items in his cave residence on his person and sealed his cave residence off using restrictions. He then departed from the Dreamcloud Mountains, flying in the direction of the State of Yuan Wu.

The Fu Clan in the State of Yuan Wu was once renowned as one of the three great sects in the country. When the Devil Dao invaded over a hundred years ago, this clan hadn’t resisted their invasion in the slightest and even provided assistance to the Six Devil Dao Sects. As a result, the Fu Clan hadn’t suffered any damage from the invasion; instead, they were given the opportunity to flourish. After overwhelming the other clans in the country, they became the number one clan in the State of Yuan Wu.

Because the Fu Clan had frequently placed many of their disciples into the Devilflame Sect, even giving their clan’s gifted women to the Devilflame Sect’s upper echelon as concubines, they were considered to be completely subservient to the sect. As a result, the Fu Clan gained the support of the Devilflame Sect, the dominating power over the State of Yuan Wu, and wildly flourished in the past hundred years.

[1]. In Chapter 352: Promise, Han Li made a promise to Xin Ruyin to avenge Qi Yuanxiao’s death in exchange for their knowledge on formation spells and tool refinement.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 648: A Party of Three

The Fu Clan’s main stronghold was located deep inside a mountain range in the west of Yuan Wu, The mountain range was known as the Purple Road Mountains as a purple mist sealed it off year long. Not only are mortals unable to see once they tread into the mist, if they stayed within it for too long, their eyes would start to sting and their throats would become sore. If they stayed within it for even longer, they could even die of poisoning.

Although locals knew of the dangers of this mist and would take care to avoid it, there would always be ignorant outsiders who entered, only to perish. The Fu Clan were aware of the mortals dying from the mist, but they hardly batted an eye.

If mortals died, then so be it. The Fu Clan expended a great amount of effort to create the Violet Miasma Cloud Formation, requiring them to invite several formation masters to simultaneously work on it. In a sense, these mortals could be considered lucky to have died by this formation.

In the past several days, although the Purple Cloud Mountains were still enshrouded in mist, a commotion began to stir as the typically desolate place suddenly became lively. Occasionally, cultivators would appear outside the mist and shout something. Afterwards, they would reveal a lustrous red invitation before disappearing into the mist.

The nearest mortal settlement to the Purple Road Mountains was a small city named Taihe. This city only spanned five kilometers and its population didn’t exceed ten thousand. However, it had all the facilities one would expect from a city such as inns and restaurants.

Ah’er was a waiter at one of the two inns of Taihe City. Although he was only nineteen years old, he had been a waiter for four years now. With his thin body, he leaned against the side of the inn’s doors and dispiritedly called out to those who walked by.

This wasn’t because Ah’er was being lazy, but because the weather was simply scorching hot. After yelling in the hot weather for the entire morning, he no longer had any strength left. Even that petty, crafty Innkeeper Liu couldn’t say anything in response to his dejected manner. Although he wore a dissatisfied expression, he could only grumble his complaints and gloomily handle his abacus, calculating the dense ledger on the table.

Ah’er glanced at an expanse of white clouds in the sky and inwardly cursed with all his heart. Then, after lowering his head, he muttered out a greeting to a passerby in a manner that they didn't even hear him, and he became even more dejected.

Just as he wondered whether or not he could take advantage of Innkeeper Liu’s inattention to sneak into the kitchen for a few drinks of cold water to relieve himself from the heat, the sky suddenly dimmed and he felt a chill. This surprised Ah’er, and he couldn’t help but raise his head.

Much to his shock, he discovered that three eccentrics had unknowingly appeared before him.

One of the men wore hemp robes and a tall hat. He was short and resembled a large ball. The other was a bald man with piercing eyes. The last of them was a man with long hair draping over his face. His face possessed a sinister air and his eyes were ice-cold.

Having spent so many years as a waiter, Ah’er knew how to act. He immediately smiled and said, “Do you guests wish to stay at the inn?” From his years of many experience, this party were sure to be generous customers despite their fiendish appearance.

The short, plump man glared with his small eyes and casually took out a large piece of silver. He shoved it into the waiter’s chest and impatiently said, “Cut the rubbish. Why else would we come at an inn if not to stay there? Prepare a room on the second floor for us, and a table of top-rate food and wine for us as well.”

Without waiting for Ah’er’s reply, Innkeeper Liu jumped up and immediately acted like a robust man, leaping out of the gate and taking the silver piece out of Ah’er’s hands. With a ingratiating expression, he said, “Yes, yes! Please enter, Sirs. Food and wine will be immediately sent for you. Ah’er, go prepare the rooms, don’t be slow.”

“Yes, Innkeeper.” Although Innkeeper Lui's actions had caused him to feel deeply resentful, Ah’er could only obey. He could only sigh and allow the silver piece to be taken away.

Were it not for the fact he only had the skills for a waiter and that there were only two inns in the city, he wouldn't be doing anything for the contemptable Innkeeper. After resentfully cursing Innkeeper Liu in his heart, Ah’er brought the three to a room on the second floor, before leaving to go back downstairs.

“Huh?” Just as Ah’er left their side, the scorching heat suddenly returned. This sudden change made him to feel puzzled as he scratched the back of his head. After tilting his head in thought, he went back downstairs in a confused manner.

Not long after, a table of food was quickly prepared and brought up by Ah’er and a few other servants.

The cultivators were waiting at the table in complete silence.

Ah’er was baffled upon seeing them. At that moment, the cultivator with the draped hair coldly glanced in his direction as if he had noticed something.

The glance instantly made Ah’er feel a freezing chill, as if he were suddenly submerged in ice, and with a shaken heart he lowered his head and left the room in a panic. He directly returned to the inn’s door with a pounding heart, unable to control himself in the slightest.

At that moment, the three in the room finally began to speak.

Sensing that there was no one outside the room, the short man chuckled and spoke to the man with the draped hair, “Brother Han, why did you startle the mortal? Did you find him displeasing to the eye?”

The draped-haired man flatly said, “It was nothing. It was just that waiter possessed spiritual roots. However, his aptitude is poor. He would only be able to reach the third or fourth layer of the Qi Condensation stage.”

A trace of astonishment appeared in the fat man’s expression, “Spiritual roots? That’s surprising. However, it seems that Brother Han is actually able to see through spiritual roots without any physical contact. It appears Brother Han is quite a skilled individual.”

The draped-haired cultivator glanced at the fat cultivator and slowly said, “My cultivation isn’t any higher than you two Fellow Daoists. I merely cultivated a related secret technique.”

The fat cultivator sighed and bitterly laughed, “Brother Han is far too modest. However, that waiter can be said to have no prospects in the cultivation world. Even if he managed to somehow reach the Foundation Establishment stage like us, if he doesn’t have the backing of a sect, he'll merely be a wild lone wolf, a target of humiliation to cultivators of a similar grade! We ourselves came to Purple Road Mountains to bid the Fu Clan Ancestor a happy birthday to see if we could find an opportunity to join the sect. If we're able to catch the eye of a Devil Dao Sect or the Clan Ancestor, we’d be quite fortunate. It's just a pity that us vagrant cultivators can only enter the Fu Clan Castle on the Ancestor’s birth date, so we still have to wait outside for another month.”

The draped-haired cultivator indifferently grunted and nodded his head as if he were disinclined to speak any further .

Seeing this, the fat man and the bald man couldn’t help but glance at each other. The bald man opened his mouth wide and said with a muffled voice, “Brother Han, us two brothers only formed a party together to go pay our respects to the Fu Clan Ancestor, but in the past several days we've realized that while you are also a vagrant cultivator, your cultivation is extraordinary. Where might you have cultivated previously? We’ve never heard of your esteemed name before.”

After the large bald man finished speaking, the eyes of the fat cultivator glinted as he stared at the cultivator surnamed Han.

The draped-haired cultivator’s face remained unchanged. He merely indifferently replied, “I was once a cultivator of the State of Yue, and I’ve only arrived in the State of Yuan Wu recently. It isn’t odd that you Fellow Daoists haven’t heard of me.”

The fat cultivator blinked and asked, “The State of Yue? Isn’t that the territory of the Ghost Spirit Sect? Why did Brother Han not try his luck with the Ghost Spirit Sect instead of coming to our State of Yuan Wu?”

The draped-haired cultivator calmly replied, "I did try, but had no success there. Given that the Ghost Spirit Sect is the sole power in the state of Yue, it doesn't tolerate the existence of outside cultivators. As such, I came to the State of Yuan Wu to try my luck. However, I didn’t expect to come across the Fu Clan Ancestor’s birth celebration as soon as I arrived. I couldn’t possibly allow such a rare opportunity to pass me by.”

“So it was like that. It must’ve been difficult for Brother Han.” The fat man chuckled and asked nothing else. Instead, he began to chat about a few of the rumors circulating throughout the cultivation world.

Once the wine and food were finished. The draped-haired cultivator bid his farewell and decided to rest in a neighboring room.

Once the draped-haired cultivator left the room, the fat cultivator’s beaming smile instantly disappeared, only to be replaced with a sinister expression. He suddenly took out a talisman from his robes and formed an incantation. Then with a flash of light, the talisman dissolved and enveloped the room in a soft light.

This talisman was a soundproofing talisman!

Once the talisman was in full effect, the large bald man asked, “Brother Luo, do you believe that youngster is truly a vagrant cultivator?”

The fat cultivator sneered and stroked the fat underneath his chin. He sinisterly said, “Of course not, he is most likely a disciple of a small sect!”

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 649: Harboring Sinister Designs

The short and stout cultivator explained with a proud expression, “Did you not see his magic tool when we were traveling together? That was clearly a top grade magic tool. Not to mention the many storage pouches at his waist. They were all bulging and there were even a few spirit beast pouches there. How could a vagrant cultivator possess so many items? It's clear that this cultivator came from a small sect. If he came from a large sect, he would’ve been too arrogant to travel with the likes of us. Additionally, he didn’t take out an invitation card to enter Purple Road Mountain. Hehe! After all, given how powerful the Devil Dao are, small sect cultivators wouldn’t dare to act so openly. All of them would sneakily act as vagrant cultivators for fear that they would attract the Devil Dao’s ire and subject calamity upon their clan for generations to come. That is why we’ve never heard of him despite his strong cultivation and magic tools.”

With eyes filled with avarice, the bald man rubbed his hands in eagerness, “From what Brother Luo has said, that does seem to be the case and we can boldly attack him without worry. Although he is somewhat wary of us, he definitely wouldn’t have thought that we were concealing our true cultivation. It should be quite easy for us two mid Foundation Establishment cultivators to kill an early Foundation Establishment cultivator. That youngster is bringing about his own doom to come across the Dual Fiends Peng Yi.”

The fat man licked his lips and sinisterly said, “Of course, but in order to smoothly succeed, we'll need to lower his guard as much as possible. It will take much less effort if we launch a sneak attack. Let’s wait two days prior to the Fu Clan Ancestor’s birth celebration to attack.”

“Yes, let’s do as Brother Luo says. Even if neither of us makes it into a sect of clan, we’ll still make quite a bit of profit!” The bald man seemed quite confident in the fat man and he wore a grin on his face.

The fat man chuckled and said, “Hehe, of course. If such an easy mark comes knocking on your door, how could the Dual Fiends Peng Yi return empty handed?”

While the two chatted without restraint about killing the draped-haired man, the man in question sat down expressionlessly in the other room. However, he was able to easily hear their words as if the soundproofing barrier didn’t exist.

Han Li opened his eyes with a cold glint and softly said, “Since you’ve taken the initiative to court death, don’t blame me for being ruthless.” He then closed his eyes once more and continued to refine Qi.

To tell the truth, Han Li had arrived in the State of Yuan Wu two months prior. He had passed through many countries affiliated with the Righteous and Devil Dao along the way, but as a Nascent Soul cultivator, he was able to stealthily pass through with his cultivation and appearance concealed.

After Han Li arrived in the State of Yuan Wu, Han Li didn’t immediately take action. Instead, he gathered information on the Fu Clan from the local market cities and vagrant cultivators. As a result, Han Li found rather displeasing information about the Fu Clan.

This wasn’t because the three Fu Clan Core Formation cultivators were troublesome to kill, but that the Fu Clan had many of their disciples located in the Devilflame Sect. Even with his vast abilities, he couldn’t directly contend against the Devilflame Sect itself.

And if he didn’t kill the entirety of the Fu Clan at once, the Fu Clan could one day rise to prominence once more, leaving his promise with Xin Ruyin unfulfilled! Just as Han Li was making a plan for action, rumors of the Fu Clan Ancestor’s birth celebration spread throughout the State of Yuan Wu. When Han Li heard this, he rejoiced.

Since the Fu Clan Lord took the initiative to call upon his clan disciples to pay their respects to him, the Fu Clan disciples of the Devilflame Sect should also be returning to the Fu Clan castle. This was an ideal opportunity to deal with the entire Fu Clan in a single blow.

However, given Fu Clan’s current power, not anyone could participate in the celebration. One must either be a cultivator from a clan or be a member of the Devil Dao. As for vagrant cultivators, they had to be at the Foundation Establishment stage in order to enter the castle.

After Han Li acquired the finer details, he patiently waited a month to pass by. As for the Dual Fiends Peng Yi, they immediately chatted with him along the road when they saw that Han Li possessed an unordinary magic tool. When they heard that Han Li was also heading to the Fu Clan Castle, they happily raised an invitation to travel together.

Han Li could tell the two harbored sinister designs at first glance, but he had nothing to fear from the two, given his current cultivation. Instead, he casually agreed to travel with them with plans to use their identities to allow him to enter the Fu Clan without suspicion.

But he didn’t expect that only cultivators with invitations would be allowed inside the Purple Road Mountains. Vagrant cultivators could only enter the castle on the day of the celebration.

This was to Han Li’s surprise, but it didn’t matter. After all, that day should be when all the Fu Clan disciples and members should gather together. If he were to act any earlier, he would scare a few away.

As of current, he was staying at an inn and hadn’t yet planned on how he should deal with the Dual Fiends Peng Yi. Since the two were incapable of staying patient, Han Li wasn’t going to be merciful.

In the following days, Han Li and the Dual Fiends Peng Yi took a few trips nearby and would return to the inn at night to cultivate. The time of the Fu Clan celebration drew near.

In these few days, The two spoke quite effectively with Han Li and even addressed him as “Brother Han” as if they were good friends for many years. Around that time, many vagrant cultivators began to gather at the small city. While a majority of vagrant cultivators were accustomed to the outdoors, a few cultivators were more fond of mortal comforts and stayed at the two inns of the city.

As a result, Han Li came across several other cultivators at the same inn. When these cultivators came across Han Li and two cultivators at his side, their expressions vastly changed and they steered clear of the three, doing their utmost to avoid talking to them. Han Li wasn't sure whether or not he should laugh or cry. It seemed the two at his side held a rather notorious reputation among vagrant cultivators.

When the Dual Fiends Peng Yi saw this, they feared that Han Li would grow suspicious and fabricated a story that the two didn’t get along with other cultivators. As a result, the two alternated keeping watch of Han Li, preventing him to speaking with anybody else.

When Han Li heard them, he was completely indifferent. This made the fat man grow somewhat suspicious, but his greed got the best of him and caused him to cast his suspicious aside.

Two days later, the two cultivators suddenly urged Han Li to visit a nearby scenic spot with them. They said that the scene was fascinating and was too good to miss.

After Han Li heard them, he knew that the two finally planned to attack. With a curt agreement, he followed the two with a smile and the three headed out from the inn towards this ‘scenic spot’.

Because there were far too many cultivators nearby, the two decided to bring Han Li out fifty kilometers from the city to a small remote mountain.

Once they all landed, the fat man began to speak with a beaming smile, “Brother Han, take a look! There is a small valley past this mountain. There are pure flowing streams and flowers of countless sorts. It is absolutely...” Despite the plain surroundings, he managed to continue his fanciful words about how impressive the scenery was.

When Han Li heard this, he continued to derisively laugh in his mind. There truly was a hidden valley past this mountain. But apart from the passable scenery, there was also the spiritual fluctuations of a hidden restriction. It was very faint, but he was able to detect it with his spiritual sense. It appeared the two were quite experienced at killing others as they placed down a rather simple spell formation.

If Han Li truly were an ordinary Foundation Establishment cultivator, he would find it difficult to survive if he were to enter the formation and suddenly be attacked by the two.

When Han Li finished listening to the fat cultivator, he casually swept his gaze around and mysterious smiled at the two, “This scenery here is not bad and there is no one here. But from how I see it, there is no purpose in going to the valley. Right here should be fine, what do you two think? No one would be disturbed if you were to kill someone here and get rid of their remains. It would surely go unnoticed.”

When the fat cultivator heard Han Li, his expression changed and he flusteredly spoke as if he were truly surprised, “Brother Han, what do you mean? Could it be you’ve misunderstood something?”

However, his chubby hands had already moved to his storage pouch. As for the large bald man, a savage expression appeared on his face and he silently moved to Han Li’s side with his hands tightly clenched.

Han Li held their petty maneuvers in little regard and remained in place with a serene expression.

When the fat cultivator saw this, he grew anxious and faintly felt a sense of foreboding. However, it was far too late to back down and merely moved to attack simultaneously with the bald man.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 650: Demon Nascent

In the same moment the two men moved to attack Han Li, a chuckle suddenly broke out.

“Hehe! How interesting. I didn’t think I’d wake up from my nap to see murder and plunder. But for two Foundation Establishment cultivators to attack a Nascent Soul cultivator? Could I be dreaming?”

These words were said by the soft, sharp voice of a young girl.

Once Han Li heard this, his expression changed. As for the fat and the bald cultivators, they were thunderstruck and immediately turned deathly pale.

“A Nascent Soul cultivator!?” The fat cultivator shrieked and stared at Han Li as if he were looking at a ghost.

The bald man was greatly frightened as well, but he appeared to have thought of something and hastily shouted, “That’s impossible! His colleague must be attempting to scare us off.”

Although he had attempted to rouse himself, he still took two steps back while continuously glancing around for the young girl. His courage greatly recovered when he found no one.

At the moment, Han Li was far more alarmed than the “Dual Fiends Peng Yi”.

For some unknown reason, he felt his body break into an indescribable shiver as the Nascent Soul that had been deep asleep in his Dantian awoke in a panic. A trace of dread had even appeared on its face. But what was most astonishing to Han Li was that after sweeping every inch of a five kilometer radius with his spiritual sense, he was incapable of finding the source of the voice. But from the sound of it, the owner should clearly be nearby. Despite using the Great Development Technique alongside his Nascent Soul cultivation, he was unable to discover the speaker. Could it be this person possessed deep and profound abilities?

Han Li’s throat dried up at the thought.

The fat cultivator regained a bit of color in his face as if he had been roused by the bald man’s words. He calmly glanced around and said, “Who’s there? Who is it that is deceiving us? You dare to trick the Dual Fiends Peng Yi?” His body was covered in the glow of a yellow light barrier as a small black shield appeared in front of him.

The girlish voice boldly said, “Hehe! If you could see this old woman, I’d kill myself out of shame. However, the spiritual sense of this Nascent Soul cultivator is quite strong. If it were even just slightly stronger, perhaps you’d be able to find me.”

Han Li’s expression grew sullen and he did his utmost to sweep his spiritual sense over everything in his surroundings. Even with his exceptional spiritual sense, he was unable to find even a trace of another cultivator. He felt that this was far too strange.

“Hm, I am a tad hungry. How about I make a meal out of you three? Tch tch, it’s been a while since I’ve had a taste of a cultivator’s Nascent Soul. I long to experience it once more!” The girl’s tone was completely free of malice, a stark contrast to the meaning of the words being said.

Han Li snorted and ceased concealing his cultivation while his expression remained unchanged. With a flash of azure light, an astonishing pressure began to emit from his body and many azure lights flew out from his mouth. These were the seventy-two Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords.

“He... He truly is a Nascent Soul cultivator! Senior, please spare our lives, us juniors had eyes but were blind to your magnificence. We didn’t mean to offend Senior- Second Brother, what are you doing!? Don’t run! We don’t stand a chance before Senior Han!”

The fat cultivator couldn’t help but feel completely awed after the emergence of Han Li’s true cultivation and immediately kowtowed before him as he pleaded for his life. As for the bald man, he did the opposite, and slapped a golden talisman onto his body that caused him to shoot into the sky in a streak of golden light.

“Do you truly believe you’ll be able to run away with a Goldspeed Talisman?” A derisive expression appeared on Han Li’s face. He pointed his finger and a flying sword loudly rang out before disappearing with a flash. Immediately thereafter, it reappeared at the side of the golden streak of light, displaying tremendous speed.

In a flash of azure light, the bald man miserably screamed and the golden streak dissolved into specks light, by which then the man's body had already vanished.

“Tch tch, what a shame. A Foundation Establishment cultivator’s soul also has a fine taste. I only had them several times before I woke up.” The girlish voice grumbled with slight annoyance.

When Han Li finished dealing with the bald man, he ignored the fat cultivator trembling before him and turned his gaze to a small tree nearby. With blue light flickering within his eyes, he said, “There is no need for your esteemed self to act so mysteriously. Are you not also a mere Nascent Soul cultivator? For you to speak so boldly, it seems you want me to personally drag you out.”

The girlish voice paused for a moment before coldly continuing, “How did you discover me? My Light Transmutation Technique isn’t something that a Nascent Soul cultivator can see through.”

“Regardless of my method to discover you, will you not reveal your true form? Or would you rather I chop down that tree of yours?” Han Li’s voice remained calm, but his heart was filled with trepidation. He had only found the source of the voice by a fluke.

In his panic, he had unconsciously swept his surroundings using the ability granted to him by the Brightsight Water. As a result, he found a small tree nearby that was somewhat unlike the others. With a resolved heart, he confronted it, no longer wishing to be deceived.

“A mere Nascent Soul cultivator? Your tone is also quite bold. I wonder how your Nascent Soul will taste once I swallow it.” As the girl’s tone grew sullen, the small tree flashed with green light, shrinking to reveal a person only half a foot tall.

This small person had an exquisite face and long hair. However, its body was composed of green light and completely bare. It seemed this small silhouette was the source of the girlish voice.

“A Nascent Soul! No, that’s not right.” After further examination, Han Li appeared hesitant.

The small silhouette looked at Han Li and slowly said, “A Nascent Soul? Hehe, you aren’t wrong. But you are quite out of luck to be the first Nascent Soul cultivator I’ve seen since awakening, or maybe my luck is just good!”

Soon after speaking the small silhouette flashed and appeared before the fat cultivator. it giggled and said, “Your soul would make a good fit in my stomach, yes?”

“No! Senior, please spare me!” Realizing that this small silhouette was an existence on par with a Nascent Soul cultivator, the fat cultivator pleaded for his life as he jumped away, wishing to flee.

However, a malevolent expression surfaced on the small silhouette’s face, and its body turned into a ball of green light that shot into the fat cultivator. An instant later, it came out of the man’s body back in its original form, except with a thumb-sized green ball of light that was intermittently twinkling.

As for the leader of the “Dual Fiends Peng Yi”, he had already collapsed onto the floor and was no longer moving.

The small silhouette didn’t bother speaking any further and simply gobbled the ball of light with a few bites. Afterwards, the silhouette’s body grew slightly more concentrated.

Han Li could no longer keep calm upon seeing this. After pursing his lips, he harshly shouted, “Are you ghost or man? You dare to directly consume a soul?!”

He had clearly felt the small silhouette’s cultivation to be similar to his own. It was only at the early Nascent Soul stage, but after it consumed the fat cultivator's soul it grew a sliver stronger, clearly demonstrating that it could increase its cultivation by directly consuming cultivators’ souls. It was inconceivable that this was the result of a technique.

The incandescent green silhouette ignored Han Li’s question and instead glanced at Han Li’s Dantian as if it were directly looking at his Nascent Soul. It wore a greedy expression and muttered, “The appetizer is done and now it is time for the banquet. After consuming your Nascent Soul, this old woman will be able to directly enter the mid Nascent Soul stage!”

“You want to swallow my Nascent Soul? I’m afraid it’d be too much for you to stomach!” Han Li furiously grinned and he clapped his hands together. A muffled explosion sounded out, followed by thick golden lightning arcing between his palms.

Ever since Han Li had entered Nascent Soul stage, he was able to directly store Divine Devilbane Lightning from his swords into his body. As a result, he was able to use the lightning as before despite having all seventy-two swords outside of him.

The green silhouette tilted its ahead upon seeing the golden lightning in Han Li’s palms and muttered, “Golden lightning? Where did I hear of this before? I can’t seem to recall it.”

Han Li raised his brow and indifferently said, “Then how about giving it a taste? I’m sure you’ll recall it then.” At that moment, the lightning in his hands transformed into a python and fiercely pounced towards the small silhouette.

For some reason, the small silhouette merely smiled and didn't bother to dodge as the python rushed forward. Instead, it opened it's mouth, and directly swallowed the python as it arrived. Afterwards, countless arcs of lightning burst from its body, and the small silhouette briefly glowed with golden lightning as its body released pangs of thunder.

Han Li narrowed his eye, lacking the slightest joy in his expression. Since the opponent dared to directly receive the Divine Devilbane Lightning, they were clearly well prepared and weren’t about to easily be dispatched.

Before the golden glow faded away, the girl’s laughter interrupted the sounds of thunder, “As I thought, is this not Divine Devilbane Lightning? Tch tch, isn’t this just great! It’s hard to believe that a mere early Nascent Soul cultivator could possess such a heavenly treasure. However, don’t think that this old woman is a devil or ghost cultivator. Using that lightning to deal with me is beyond its abilities!”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare + Anon

Chapter 651: Wood Spirit Nascent

The small green silhouette hadn’t taken the slightest damage from Han Li’s strike and sneered at him.

Han Li scoffed, “It’s too early to be proud. If you truly wish to devour my Nascent Soul, it’s going to take more than a few arrogant words. If I guessed correctly, you can only consume the souls of low grade cultivators. To speak of consuming a cultivator’s Nascent Soul is pure fantasy. Perhaps you might’ve been able to do this in the past, but as of current you're far too weak and are only capable of assuming that strange form of yours. Enough rubbish, let’s see how you fare against these flying swords.” These words caused the small silhouette’s expression to vastly change, revealing malice from its eyes.

At that moment, Han Li pointed to the flying swords spiraling above him, and with a clear ring, twelve of the flying swords shot forward as streaks of azure light.

The small green silhouette stood in place with a sullen expression, as the dozen of azure swordlights spiraled around it and sliced its body up into countless pieces. However, these pieces simply remained floating in the air, shimmering with faint light, much to Han Li's surprise.

Suddenly, a bewildering chuckle rang out, as the floating pieces flashed with light before joining together as the small silhouette in its original form.

“Tch tch! Not bad, not bad! Your set of flying swords must’ve been refined from Golden Lightning Bamboo. Although I don’t know how you acquired so much of it, it truly is ridiculous to think of injuring me with those swords alone. You will come to know that my words aren’t born of arrogance.”

The silhouette seemed to have been completely infuriated by Han Li’s previous words, and it formed an incantation gesture with its hands as a blinding green radiance shined forth as it was about to unleash a technique. But before it could fully finish casting its technique, bright light flashed from above its head as the twelve flying swords simultaneously pulsed with lightning and formed a dense net of golden lightning that charged towards it.

“Humph! This junior still won’t give up! Did I not say that the divine lightning has no effect on me... Wait, what are you doing?!” The girlish voice became shrill as if it grew frightened.

The net of golden lightning didn't explode as it had anticipated. Instead, the net remained firm when it caught the small silhouette, and it unceasingly tightened around its body. The small silhouette knew that this was far from good, and its body flickered with green light in its utmost attempt to resist. However, its struggle was in vain as it was soon trapped in a large golden ball.

When Han Li saw this, he couldn’t help but wryly smile.

This net of Divine Devilbane Lightning was a technique that was founded by Han Li!

Because Golden Lightning Bamboo was exceedingly rare, only one or two stalks would be used in the formation of a magic tool. On top of that, since they had a limited amount of divine lightning the lightning was only reserved as a trump card against devilish and evil techniques. Making such a large net of lightning would require over ten stalks worth of Divine Devilbane Lightning to form, as such, none could’ve afforded to do this before Han Li.

Having controlled the Divine Devilbane Lightning for so many years now, Han Li noticed that in addition to an innate ability to subdue evil and devilish techniques, the lightning also possessed the wondrous effect of restraining the five elements. Regardless of whether it was the Sacred Asura Flames or Wind Spirit Energy, they had both been actively and securely subdued. This unexpected discovery was much to Han Li’s delight.

While he was still at the Core Formation stage, he was unable to use lightning nets as he wished because of his lacking cultivation, and had rarely used them in battle. But with his current vastly strengthened cultivation and spiritual sense, he no longer had such problems.

Although he didn’t know where this little silhouette came from, he knew that it was neither man or ghost; it was more akin to a strange variation of a cultivator’s Nascent Soul. With that thought, Han Li attempted to make use of the net.

Unfortunately for the silhouette, although it had heard legends of the Divine Devilbane Lightning, it was unaware of its hidden properties. Else, it wouldn’t have so casually received the attack with its body as a Demon Nascent. In the blink of an eye, this haughty figure had been easily confined.

Seeing that he succeeded, Han Li smiled and raised his hand, shooting out an azure mist to collect the golden ball into his hand.

The golden sphere faintly trembled and released furious, ear-piercing shrieks, “You dare to trap this old woman!? Quickly release me or else I will refine your soul and subject you to a fate worse than death!”

Han Li frowned and sullenly said, “Refine my soul? It seems your esteemed self still doesn’t understand your situation. Let’s talk about this again once you’ve properly calmed down.”

Claps of thunders rang out as lightning shot out from his hands again. These thin slivers of lightning wrapped layers around the golden ball, consuming nearly half of his swords’ lightning reserves. After further inspecting the enlarged golden ball, he wore a satisfied expression.

Paying no heed to the girl’s raving shouts from the golden ball, Han Li took out a white jade box from his storage pouch and shut it inside. He then took out a few restriction talismans and slapped them onto the box without any hesitation, putting a sudden end to the rant.

Han Li weighed the jade box in his hand and his expression was once again normal. After putting the jade box away, he glanced down at the soulless body of the fat cultivator and indifferently turned it to ash with a fireball before calmly flying in the direction of the small city.

A short moment later, Han Li leisurely made his way to the tavern and simply waited for the birth celebration to draw near.

Not long after, there was a shocking discovery in the State of Yuan Wu. The Duel Fiends Peng Yi, who were notorious murderers of vagrant cultivators, had completely disappeared from the country. Not a single trace of them had been found, which of course signified to many that they had died.

When this news spread, the vagrant cultivators in the country cheered. There were those that said they were disposed of by a sect they offended, while there was also word that they encountered an expert on their travels and were slayed as a result of their notoriety. For a time, all sorts of rumors flew around.

......

Tens of thousands kilometers away in the distant State of Tian Luo was the nest of the Six Devil Dao Sects. The Grand Spirit Mountains in the west of Tian Luo spanned over tens of thousands of kilometers without interruption. The mountains were steep and home to countless spirit beasts and exotic insects. It was the location of the Controlling Spirit Sect’s monastery.

In the instant that the Demon Nascent was sealed, an old man’s furious shout suddenly echoed from a pitch-black stone room, “Who is it!? Who dares to imprison the Wood Spirit Nascent! Servant quickly contact the Spirit Controlling Sect members in the State of Yuan Wu. If they are unable to find the Wood Spirit Nascent in three month’s time, then they will have to kill themselves for the sin of their failure. Also, they must act carefully not to let the Devilflame Sect catch wind of this matter.”

Although the old man was furious, his orders were concise.

“As you bid, Martial Senior. I will pass down the commands.” A man’s stern voice came out from outside the room.

The old man continued, “I’m not done! Also call for Yunzhi and Liu Yu’er to personally make a trip to the State of Yuan Wu. They both have wood attribute spiritual roots and have the most suitable bodies for the Wood Spirit Nascent, perhaps they will be able to feel something if they get closer to it. However, have the two women be careful. Whoever restrained the Wood Spirit Nascent is certain to possess great abilities. Those two won't be able to confront the culprit. So long as they find the person who imprisoned the Wood Spirit Nascent, I will personally come to deal with them.”

The man’s voice respectfully replied, “Yes, I will personally tell the two Junior Martial Sisters to go. This Martial Nephew will now take his leave.”

Soon after the man’s footsteps faded into the distance, a deep sigh filled the room and the darkness became silent once more.

......

Behind the concealment of the purple mist of the Purple Road Mountains, the Fu Clan Master Fu Tianhua, was in high spirits with a flushed face. He viewed all the juniors in his clan with a kind face, leaving his juniors feeling overwhelmed with favor. They were all used to him wearing a more stern expression.

This was of no surprise. The Marital Ancestor’s celebration of four hundred years of life was about to arrive. He was the oldest Core Formation cultivator in the clan, and even two of the Devilflame Sects’ enforcers were going to come today for his birthday celebration. This greatly increased the Fu Clan’s prestige.

The Fu Clan juniors didn’t dare to be negligent and were doing their utmost around the castle so that this birth celebration wouldn’t result in a loss of prestige for the clan ancestor.

After the Fu Clan ancestor made a round through the castle, he seemed quite satisfied. He then entered a side hall with a few juniors in tow.

The sharp-eyed, purple-robed Fu Clan Ancestor leaned against an armchair in the room and slowly said, “Qing’er! Have the honorable guests from the Devilflame Sect arrived yet? Is there something keeping them busy?” While his voice wasn’t loud, it was filled with dignity, suitable for the man who led the Fu Clan through over a hundred years of prosperity.

“Venerable Ancestor, the Devilflame Sect’s Senior Sun has sent over a disciple stating that he and Protector Mo will certainly arrive to offer congratulations. However, it will take one or two days more.” A pale forty-year-old cultivator helplessly replied in a hurry.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare + Anon

Chapter 659: The Disciples of Splintered Soul

A strange glint appeared in Han Li’s eyes. He glanced at the old man and indifferently asked, “What? You recognize me?”

The old man shivered underneath Han Li’s icy gaze and hastily answered, “No, I am mistaken. How could Junior have possibly recognized you!”

“You’ve admitted to be mistaken?” Han Li indifferently rubbed his chin and swept his gaze past the others as if he believed the old man.

The grey-clothed man seemed puzzled as he glanced at the old man. Although he felt it was odd, he couldn’t afford to pursue the matter. He could only think of flattering Han Li and somehow taking an opportunity to flee.

Before any of them could respond, Han Li slowly said, “Since you are Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators and have discovered my trail, you’re just out of luck. I will be taking your lives!” As soon as that was said, Han Li’s expression grew dark and he waved his sleeve, releasing over ten streaks of azure swordlight. As soon as these swordlights left his sleeve, they transformed into over forty swordlights in a blur, and engulfed the black-clothed cultivators in an overwhelming strike.

When the grey-robed cultivator heard Han Li’s voice grow harsh, he knew that matters had taken a turn for the worst. His complexion grew pale upon seeing Han Li’s momentous attack.

Of course, he wasn’t about to submit to death. He instinctively whirled his body, releasing countless stands of black Qi to cover his body. A gold and a silver prong soon flew out from the mist and transformed into a gold and a silver python to guard the front of the black Qi. The grey-clothed cultivator then did his utmost to fly backwards in a streak of black smoke, abandoning the rest of the black-clothed cultivators to their fates.

Apart from the old man, the rest of the Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators were helplessly beheaded by the assault of azure swordstreaks. As the old man was paralyzed from fright, Han Li flicked his finger, launching a slim azure strand from the sword streaks. It instantly bore into the old man’s body and caused him to collapse on the ground.

When Han Li saw this, he no longer paid any attention to the old man and focused on the grey-clothed cultivator that had fled over a three hundred meters away. Han Li sneered and casually pointed at the swordlights and had over a hundred streaks of swordlight converge together, instantly forming a huge azure sword.

“Go,” Han Li softly uttered. The huge sword trembled and released a muffled hum before launching itself forward at an unfathomable speed. In the blink of an eye, a dazzling explosion of azure light erupted from the black smoke.

The strike from the huge sword annihilated the black Qi and the pythons at the same time. With a wretched scream, the grey-clothed cultivator was rent into a mist of gore.

Han Li recalled the magic treasure and his expression grew sullen as he glanced at the old man lying unconscious on the ground.

After some further thought, Han Li raised his hand and drew the old man’s shriveled body into his grasp. Azure light flickering from his free hand, he pressed it against the old man’s head without any reservations. After the time it took to finish a cup of tea, fire flared from his hand and turned the old man into ash.

Han Li floated in the air with his arms held behind his back and wore a flabbergasted expression on his face, “That disciple left behind to the Harmonious Bond Sect, Dong Xuan’er [1] , actually formed a core. However, it is truly odd that she would send men after me.”

The old man’s origins were quite complicated. He was once a disciple of the Harmonious Bond Sect, but because he had greatly violated the sect’s laws and feared that his soul would be refined, he changed his appearance and identity. He had remained hidden inside the Ghost Spirit Sect ever since.

Naturally, Han Li didn’t care for such matters. What shocked him was how the old man along with many other Harmonious Bond Sect disciples were sent to frantically search for Han Li by the Core Formation stage Dong Xuan’er. These people were even sent into the Nine Nations Alliance in order to search for traces of Han Li. It seemed the old man had shockingly recognized Han Li due to having seen his portrait before.

At the time, Han Li had been in the Scattered Star Seas and the matter was ultimately left unresolved.

As of current, Han Li felt greatly confused. He wasn’t so vain as to think that Dong Xuan’er fancied him. As such, he felt that there was a deeper reason for her continuous search for him. It was only a pity that the old man’s status at the time wasn’t high and he had no further information on the matter.

After pondering for a moment, Han Li couldn’t think of a reason why Dong Xuan’er would send men to search for him and he shook his head, placing the matter at the back of his mind.

Now that so many years had passed, this matter didn’t affect him in the slightest. There was even less cause for concern since he was now a Nascent Soul cultivator.

With that thought, Han Li dealt with the Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators’ corpses and glanced in the direction of the former location of Yellow Maple Valley before departing from the Tai Yue Mountain Range.

Unbeknownst to Han Li, at the same moment he killed the grey-clothed cultivator, a black-robed, shrivelled-skinned cultivator awoke from his meditation with a frown and sighed. He then took out a dull, pitch-black bone medallion from his robes.

The black-robed cultivator fiddled with the bone medallion and glanced at it with narrowed eyes. A stern expression appeared from his face. A moment later, he stood up and walked out of the secluded room.

After walking down a long corridor, the black-robed cultivator arrived in a large hall and he calmly took a seat in a stone chair. With a white flickering light emitting from his hands, he took out a small bronze bell.

A loud clang rang out with a casual swing of the bell. A deep ring continued to reverberate from it, spreading over an unknown distance. The black-robed man put away the small bell and remained still inside his chair.

A short moment later, three Core Formation cultivators hurriedly entered the hall from three side doors, two men and one woman. They differentially stood in front of the old man with their heads faced down with solemn expressions.

“Just now, the light from your Sixth Junior Martial Brother’s life medallion was extinguished. It seems he met a vicious end. Although I don’t know what exactly happened, he was a disciple of me, Splintered Soul. I cannot allow his death to remain unanswered. Find the killer and bring him to me alive. I wish for them to give me the story behind what happen!” The black-clothed cultivator indifferently spoke as if he were discussing a trivial matter.

The three cultivators were initially surprised but they soon saluted him with bowed heads, “As you bid master. We will immediately depart.”

“I hope the next time I see you, you will have already placed the killer in the Immortal’s Hold.” The black-robed cultivator nodded his head and left the hall without another word.

Only the three Core Formation cultivators, the disciples of Splintered Soul, remained in the hall.

After a moment of consideration, the cultivator with a bold and clear appearance orderly arranged, “Fifth Junior Martial Sister, send a voice transmission talisman to the sect branch in the Tai Yue Mountains as soon as you can. Let’s see whether or not they know about Sixth Junior Martial Brother meeting with mishap. If they are unaware, have them send men to investigate the whereabouts of the killer. Junior martial brother Que, your relationship with the side branch master is quite good. See whether or not he can send men to investigate if any unfamiliar high grade cultivators have recently entered the State of Yue.

“Also, we will all send our own competent disciples to investigate the last known location of Sixth Junior Martial Brother and see whether or not there are any clues. Once this information is relayed back, we will set forth together to capture this person. Since he was able to kill Sixth Junior Martial Brother, his cultivation should be high. It is best to be careful.”

The other two cultivators were a middle-aged woman who still possessed beauty, and an eerie scholarly man wearing embroidered robes.

The woman smiled upon hearing him, but the scholarly man frowned and revealed a somewhat unsightly expression. A moment later, he reluctantly nodded.

As if feeling worried, bold-faced cultivator stared at the embroidered-robed scholarly man and coldly said, “Junior martial brother Que, I know that you were on bad terms with Sixth Junior martial brother. However, this matter was personally given by the master. You should know what will happen if you disobey. Don’t forget that Second Senior martial brother brother and Seventh Junior martial brother were also punished for mishandling their affairs.”

The scholarly man wryly smiled and chuckled, “That isn’t the case. Although we didn’t get along, he is dead now, and this matter is now assigned to me by the master. Please be at ease, Third Senior martial brother. I will definitely try my hardest.”

The bold-faced cultivator slowly said, “If Junior martial brother knows how things stand, then let us set off.”

The three then left the hall to attend to their own matters.

Several days later, the Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators had tracked down where Han Li killed the party of cultivators. After further inspection, Han Li’s original cave residence was also discovered.

When the three disciples of Splintered Soul heard this, they rushed to the Tai Yue Mountains with a group of disciples in tow. After entering, they looked at each other in dismay as they stood in front of the large hole where the spirit well used to be.

At that same moment in a land far away, Han Yunzhi and that woman surnamed Liu were hurriedly crossing through a series of towering mountains into the State of Yue.

[1]. Dong Xuan'er was a woman first introduced in Chapter 224: Mechanical Puppet Beasts. She was an unruly flirt who seduced many men, resulting in her ancestor pairing her up with Han Li. She was later abducted by the Harmonious Bond Sect.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 661: Han Family Shrine

After entering the small restaurant, a sharply dressed waiter welcomed Han Li.

Han Li didn’t head to the second floor and instead chose to sit in a remote corner of the first floor. He ordered a few dishes and silently observed everything that was occurring in the restaurant.

There were people from all backgrounds sitting on the first floor, just like Han Li had seen from other restaurants. Regardless whether it be hard laborers or small business merchants, they were all present. The only thing that stood out was the table full of burly men.

These six burly men were all effortlessly carrying a meter long cloth bag at their sides. Han Li didn’t need to use his spiritual sense to guess that they were bladed weapons. From their similar uniforms, they clearly belonged to some sort of organization. However, this greatly aroused a feeling of familiarity from Han Li as he recalled his days in the Seven Mysteries Sect.

He swept his spiritual sense past the people and he clearly heard their conversation. As expected, they were killers belonging to an organization. Han Li soon lost interest and turned his attention to examining the other patrons.

At that moment, two young scholars walked into the restaurant. They were walking slowly and chatting with smiles on their faces.

“I heard that Assistant Minister Han has arrived back to the home village to pay his respects to his ancestors. Not only are grand characters of the province coming to pay an official visit, but the Fan and Li clans are also sending men over. It seems the Han Clan truly wishes to have this matter be bold and grand.”

“Exactly so! I heard that for this ancestral offering, the Han Clan sent out many letters summoning their side branch clansmen regardless of the distance. Even the government officials of little repute are sending men to pay their respects. From how I see it, the Han, Fan and Li Clans will soon become the three great families of the Jing Province.

“Tch tch! It is rather inconceivable that the Han Clan’s abrupt rise in power took place over a span of just a hundred years!”

“What’s so odd about that? Ever since a member of the Han Clan managed to rank first in the imperial exams, their rise in power has been momentous. Each of their later descendants began to achieve great rankings in the imperial exams. With several generations of success, it is no wonder they are currently so impressive. Still, it would be better for us to later...”

The two scholars casually sat down at a table next to Han Li while they spoke.

‘The Han Clan!’ When Han Li heard them, he hastily thought to continue listening to them, but the two scholars quickly changed the subject and began to discuss literary works, much to Han Li’s annoyance. After some thought, he suddenly stood and walked towards the scholars.

“Brothers, my name is Han Li. Might I ask which Han Clan you were referring to? I’ve arrived here after receiving an invitation to pay my respects to the clan’s ancestors. However, I’ve grown up in a small countryside and am extremely unfamiliar with the main clan, nor do I know where to pay my respects. Could you two brothers give me a few directions?”

The two scholars were stunned, but after seeing that Han Li also wore a scholar’s robes and spoke with refined words, the two replied without any suspicions, “So it turns out that brother is a Han Clan disciple! We’ve been quite rude. However, there is only one Han Clan, the Han Clan of the Three Kilometer Valley.

‘The Three Kilometer Valley!’ This entire area was the small village where the Han Clan once resided. Because the entire village only spanned three kilometers over the mountains, it received this unsophisticated name. It seems the Han Clan they spoke of were most likely related to him somehow.

With a calm expression, Han Li insipidly said, “If that’s the case, then this Han Clan is truly my own. Could you two tell me about the finer details of the clan? I’ve never participated in the clan’s ancestor offering. I’d rather not make a fool of myself.”

The two scholars glanced at each other and then examined Han Li. Feeling that he wasn't holding any ill intentions, they agreed, “This... we can only give a few general details. They are known by everyone.”

“Many thanks!” Han Li smiled.

One of the scholars began to speak, “If Brother is participating in the ancestral offering, it would be best for you to not immediately head to the Three Kilometer Valley. Several decades ago, the Han Clan changed their location to the Han Clan Castle. They will only return to their ancestral home in Three Kilometer Valley on the day of the ancestor offering. The Han Clan...”

Han Li’s expression remained calm as he listened, but his heart stirred with excitement.

Four hours later, Han Li appeared above the verdant mountains from his past. He didn’t descend, merely looking down in silence.

Was this the same small village from the past?

The yellow earth roads, short walls, thatched huts, and village children could no longer be seen. Instead, they were replaced with large courtyards, roofed buildings, pebbled roads, and well clothed servants. Not a single sign of the past remained.

Han Li shook his head at the sight and thought to depart when his gaze suddenly arrived at the building at the very center of the residence. This building wasn’t larger than the others, but it was the only building to have more than a single story making it rather eye-catching.

The building’s doors were shut and a pitch-black signboard appeared on the outside. The words “Han Clan Shrine” were written on it in silver paint.

A strange expression appeared on Han Li’s face. After some thought, he reappeared in front of the building in a blur.

Several burly shrine attendants stood in front of the shrine, but with Han Li’s invisibility technique, they were incapable of spotting him. He casually swept his gaze past them and entered without further thought.

Once he entered the shrine, he spotted rows of memorial tablets, numbering over several hundred. They were arranged on long tables which had empty spots on them for future generations.

After sweeping his gaze over them, he found many names but none that he was familiar with. Without any further thought, he climbed to the second floor.

The memorial tablets on the second floor were clearly more grand and important. Not only were there many lit incense burners, there was also a huge cauldron at the center. It was filled with scented oil and had a huge candle wick that was brightly burning. It made for a solemn sight.

This time, Han Li blankly stood in place as he read the several memorial tablets at the center.

“Han Zhu, Han Tie, Han Tiansheng...” These familiar names were all coldly written on the pitch-black memorial tablets. Han Li’s heart grew heavy and he found it difficult to breath.

As the saying goes, the great Dao was emotionless! However, that was only a self-deceiving lie. Han Li may be an Immortal from this land, but he was incapable of severing his emotions. He was only able to bury them deep inside his heart.

Han Li eventually moved, and slowly walked towards the memorial tablets at the center of the room. He stopped and expressionlessly stared at the memorial tablets as images of his close relatives began to continuously appear in his mind.

An unknown amount of time slowly passed by. The heavy sound of the building’s door opening woke Han Li from his reminiscent mood. However, he merely stood in place without making any moves.

At that moment, the footsteps and voices of two middle-aged men could be heard.

“Brother Li, you are far too impatient. Didn’t I say that I would lend you the letter for reading after the shrine visit? There is need to be so anxious!” This man spoke with a helpless tone.

In the other person’s embarrassment, they responded, “Hehe! Esteemed Brother Han, who was it that had you mention that the later portion of the letter had a set of nameless martial arts left behind by your ancestor? I am rather baffled as to why our Li Clan knows nothing of this matter despite the fact that our ancestors created it. It is only natural for me to wish to see it as soon as possible.

However, why is it that you enshrined the letter? It would be an absolute shame for someone to steal it!”

The first voice sighed and spoke with a voice of complete confidence, “Who would possibly think of stealing something from a clan’s ancestral hall? While our Han Clan isn’t necessarily a nest of dangerous characters, we still have many skilled martial artists standing guard. Ordinary people wouldn’t even be able to approach it. Even if they succeeded, they would still have to fear our retaliation.”

“That’s true!” The other man agreed.

As the footsteps became clear, a scholarly man and a man with thick facial hair appeared on the stairs of the second floor.

The two initially arrived with a smile, but after spotting Han Li, their expressions froze.

In their alarm, the large man stepped forward and covered the front of the middle-aged scholar. With a fluttering mustache and beard, he softly roared, “What a clever villain to think of waiting here in ambush, but you will not be leaving alive.” Once that was said, the man’s hands tightened into fists and he ferociously pounced towards Han Li.

But before he arrived, a gale with astonishing pressure suppressed him.

Han Li remained motionless as he stood in place with his back facing them.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 664: Exposed Tracks

By the time the last word was spoken, Han Li was already ten kilometers away from the Three Kilometer Valley while flying across the sky in a streak of azure light.

Although he had something of a relationship with the Han Clan members, he had always viewed his true family to be his parents and siblings. Although the scholar and the large man had treated him with great respect, Han Li felt no real intimacy towards them. After all, the distance of many generations and the vast changes to Green Ox Village and the Three Kilometer Valley caused Han Li to strongly feel as if he were an outsider.

However, this trip to his hometown had weakened the last worries he held in his heart. He was sure that with the passage of time, these worries would truly disappear and his distant ties with these descendants would truly fade away.

As such, Han Li quickly gained his bearings and set off.

Several days later, Han Li passed through the Lan Province, specifically making a detour at Jia Yuan City. Little had changed about the city apart from its inhabitants.

Not only did Sun Ergou and the Fourth Level Gang disappear, but even the Rainbow Sect had disappeared over a hundred years prior. It had been replaced with a newly emerged gang by the name of the United Heavens Union.

If he remembered correctly, the Rainbow Sect had had the backing of Spirit Beast Mountain in the past, but at the climax of the war with the Devil Dao, Spirit Beast Mountain defected to the Controlling Spirit Sect. Now that the State of Yue was under the control of the Ghost Spirit Sect, the fall of the Rainbow Sect came as no surprise.

Additionally, he had no idea if Mo Yuzhu or her daughter had met with any mishaps. It was a pity that so many years had passed as even if Han Li asked around, there would be no information to be found.

Han Li could only sigh and hurriedly depart.

As for Sun Ergou, he didn’t manage to find any information on his clan. Han Li didn’t mind this in particular since he didn't hold them in much regard. Although he had given Sun Ergou many benefits, Han Li had received little in return.

As such, Han Li left the city of Jia Yuan and thought to fly in the direction of the State of Yuan Wu. Once he passed through the State of Yuan Wu, he planned on returning to the Drifting Cloud Sect. But half a day after he departed Jia Yuan City, his expression froze and he stopped in mid air.

He turned his head and gazed into the distance. He couldn’t help but narrow his eyes.

At that moment, a party of cultivators suddenly stopped a hundred kilometers away. The two white-clothed woman hesitantly glanced at each other as their expressions grew heavy.

The old man standing behind them nervously asked, “Martial Aunts, did something happen?”

“Yes, I just felt the Spirit Nascent’s position suddenly stop. I don’t know whether or not we’ve been discovered.” The sharp-eyed, white-clothed woman surnamed Liu no longer wore her normal lazy expression which had been replaced with an incisive air.

The burly man spoke with an odd expression, “That’s impossible. Even a Nascent Soul cultivator cannot sense something at this distance. Could it be that Martial Aunt’s secret technique disturbed the Spirit Nascent and alerted him?”

The woman surnamed Liu shook her head and firmly said, “That can’t be. Our technique was something that was passed down by your Martial Ancestor. It only allows for the one-sided detection of the Wood Spirit Nascent. So long as the other party hasn’t yet reached late Nascent Soul stage, he shouldn’t be able to perceive anything strange. After all, it would be considered fearsome for Nascent Soul cultivators to see within even a fifty kilometer radius, even if their spiritual sense was exceptionally powerful. Could it be that we are chasing after a late Nascent Soul eccentric?”

The green-clothed woman amongst the four Foundation Establishment cultivators seemed to have thought of something and worriedly said, “But Martial Aunt Liu, why is it...”

Suddenly, Han Yunzhi broke her silence as she was tracing the Spirit Nascent’s location and spoke with an alarmed expression, “Not good! The Spirit Nascent’s position is moving towards us!”

“What? Its coming over in our direction? Has that cultivator truly discovered us?” The woman surnamed Liu turned pale and she hastily clutched her hands in an incantation gesture. After a short moment, the woman grimaced and spoke with certainty, “The cultivator who restricted the Spirit Nascent is indeed moving towards us at an extraordinary speed. He is certain to be a Nascent Soul cultivator.”

After muttering to herself for a moment, Han Yunzhi slowly said, “Quickly run! Fighting means certain death. I recall that a branch of the Ghost Spirit Sect is located in the nearby Lan Province. Let’s flee there. Although we do not get along well, we are still on the same side. We will draw on the support of their spell formations to fight this unknown Nascent Soul cultivator.

Besides, the Nascent Soul cultivator might not necessarily dare to brazenly attack the Ghost Spirit Sect branch. It will greatly increase our chance of escaping.”

“Martial Aunt Han speaks true. Let us quickly go, or else it will be too late!” When the large man heard that a Nascent Soul cultivator was about to arrive, he felt his mouth turn dry in alarm.

The woman surnamed Liu raised her eyebrows and coldly glanced at the large man, “Humph! Panicking and spouting unnecessary words. We will use the Spirit Joining Arts to combine our magic power into one. This way, we will increase our speed by nearly half. Let us hurry!”

The large man felt his heart drop and he didn’t dare to say any more.

Under the lead of Han Yunzhi and Cultivator Liu, the six immediately made use of the Spirit Joining Arts and flew off on their magic treasures and tools as a single streak of yellow light. With their united spiritual Qi, their speed was amazingly fast.

At that moment, Han Li immediately noticed this and his expression grew sullen as he flew forward at full speed.

Han Li didn’t entirely understand just how powerful his spiritual sense currently was. He merely knew that by utilizing the fourth layer of the Great Development Technique, his spiritual sense was able to envelop a fifty kilometer radius around himself. Past that, he wouldn’t be able to observe anything in detail. He would only have a vague observation of anything within a hundred fifty kilometers.

A moment ago, Han Li suddenly felt a sliver of strange, concealed spiritual power linger near his body that had greatly alarmed him. Ordinary Nascent Soul cultivators wouldn’t have been able to easily detect it with their spiritual sense.

Although he didn’t know exactly what this was, Han Li knew that trouble had arrived at his door. He guessed that it was more so the matter that he had casually tidied up with the Ghost Spirit Sect rather than his extermination of the Fu Clan back in the State of Yuan Wu.

As a result of this discovery, Han Li spread out his spiritual sense and discovered that a hundred kilometers behind him there was a party of several cultivators that were stealthily following him. Although it was too far away for him to clearly see their faces, Han Li surged with killing intent and flew towards their direction without any hesitation.

As cultivators that were capable of tracking him, he absolutely couldn’t allow them to continue following him. Eradicating them would prevent future troubles. And since there were only two Core Formation cultivators in their party, it should prove to be an easy affair.

In the following instant, a dazzling thirty-meter-long streak of azure light quickly chased after a dense beam of yellow light, producing waves of clear rings from their wake.

In only a short moment, Han Li had already closed the gap by fifty kilometers. When cultivator Liu sporadically detected Han Li’s position through her techniques, she couldn’t help but grow pale in terror.

At this speed, the six wouldn’t even reach half the distance to the Ghost Spirit Sect branch before being chased down by the Nascent Soul cultivator.

With great worry, the woman turned her head to Han Yunzhi and thought to discuss further plans to flee when Han Yunzhi suddenly smiled and whispered, “Quickly, look ahead. There is a party of Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators that seem to be heading towards us.”

“Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators?”

Han Yunzhi’s soft voice roused the spirits of not only Cultivator Liu but the other four Foundation Establishment cultivators as well. Although they didn’t dare to imagine that they would have enough strength to fight a Nascent Soul cultivator, they would be able to assist them in buying more time.

As expected, they soon saw over ten black dots approach them from the distance.

Cultivator Liu felt somewhat at ease when she saw them. Nevertheless, she snuck a glance at Han Yunzhi, shaken that her Senior Martial Sister Liu had discovered the Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators far earlier than she had.

Since there was only one Wood Spirit Nascent, they were actually rivals despite their appearance as martial sisters. While they would ordinarily call each other martial sisters with great familiarity, they felt a great competitive spirit in their hearts hoping for the opportunity to fuse with the Wood Spirit Nascent. It was only natural to covet an opportunity to reach for greater heights.

At that moment, the six had arrived before the party of Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators and scattered the spiritual Qi around them to reveal their true appearances. The Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators had long discovered the Controlling Spirit Sect cultivators. Although they didn’t take any malicious actions, they each assumed a cautious attitude.

“Yi! Isn’t it Junior Martial Sisters Han and Liu from the Controlling Spirit Sect? A truly rare visit indeed for you to have arrived at the State of Yue!” A surprised voice spoke out from among the black-clothed Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators. Three Core Formation cultivators then walked out from the group, two men and one woman.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

PR: Vare

Chapter 673: Trade Meet

After glancing at the jade box in his hand for most of the day, Han Li sighed and slowly placed it back into his storage pouch. Azure light then flashed from his hands and the azure jade slip reappeared.

Should he take the risk to refine a second Nascent Soul? He would put the decision off until he fully comprehended the incantations for the profound Nascent Formation Arts. This matter was dangerous and extremely difficult, as such it would be better if he were cautious. With his mind made up, he sank his spiritual sense into the jade slip and entered a state of obliviousness.

Not far away from Han Li, Silvermoon was peacefully cultivating in her own secluded room. All of the other miscellaneous tasks were being handled by Han Li’s ape puppets.

Time quickly went by, and yet another year had passed.

One day, two streaks of light, one azure and one white, flew in the direction of Han Li’s cave residence. Two silhouettes could be faintly made out from within them. They were the two Drifting Cloud Sect elders, a silver-haired old man and a sallow-faced middle-aged man.

They couldn’t help but exchange a smile when they saw that the restrictions around Han Li’s residence were in full effect.

The middle-aged man surnamed Lu flicked his finger and sent a previously prepared letter talisman into the restrictions in a streak of fiery light. Once the talisman disappeared from sight, he smiled to the silver-haired old man and said, “It seems ever since Junior Martial Brother Han returned, he remained within his cave residence in diligent cultivation.

The silver-haired old man surnamed Cheng spoke with a strange expression, “That is to be expected. How else could Junior Martial Brother Han have formed a Nascent Soul in two hundred years? It is a pity that the end of my lifespan is drawing close. I am incapable of treading further on the path of Immortal cultivation, and I reckon you know this too.”

The middle-aged man hastily consoled him, “Senior Martial Brother Cheng must be joking. He still has another two hundred years ahead of him at the very least.”

The silver-haired old man shook his head and calmly said, “Hehe, Junior Martial Brother Lu, how could I not know of my own circumstances? Perhaps if I hadn’t been wounded from the last battle, I might’ve been able to live another two hundred years without a problem. But despite my full recovery, the battle caused great harm to my vitality. It is something that cannot be solved through meditation.”

“Senior Martial Brother!” The middle-aged man’s expression changed and he thought to say something, but the old man interrupted him with a wave of his hand.

The old man slowly said, “Even if I enter no further battles, I will live only sixty years more at most, that much is certain. There is no need to comfort me. Why else would I have so painstakingly roped Junior Martial Brother Han into our Drifting Cloud Sect? I have even done my best to befriend him. Normally, even if we were truly impatient about taking him into our sect, we would’ve done a meticulous investigation into his background. Fortunately, our hasty judgement has turned out to be correct. Although this person’s history is somewhat complicated, he holds no ulterior motives towards our Drifting Cloud Sect.”

The middle-aged man was stunned, “Senior Martial Brother sent disciples to investigate Junior Martial Brother Han’s background?”

“That’s right. Although Junior Martial Brother Han’s background is rather vague, with his name and appearance, I’ve sent disciples to stealthily make some inquiries into the State of Yue, and ended up with a rough background of our Junior Martial Brother Han. You might not believe it, but over a hundred years ago, our Junior Martial Brother was originally a Foundation Establishment cultivator of Yellow Maple Valley. During that time, he had earned a small reputation for himself. It was said that during the war with the Devil Dao, he alone managed to kill many cultivators of the same grade.

“But when Yellow Maple Valley was later routed, that Treacherous Ghost Linghu abandoned him for some reason. Afterwards, there was no further trace of Junior Martial Brother Han. Perhaps he was cultivating in concealment and had only recently emerged when he reached late Core formation stage. He then arrived at our Drifting Cloud Sect and formed a Nascent Soul. It seems that during this missing period, Han Li should’ve had some fortuitous encounters.”

The middle-aged man sneered, “It is quite ridiculous for him to be abandoned at the time. Throwing away a sect disciple that happened to be such a rare cultivation genius! In a short amount of time, he managed to cultivate from Foundation Establishment stage to Nascent Soul stage! I reckon that old ghost Ling Hu would be driven mad if he knew about this matter! After all, Yellow Maple Valley hasn’t been faring very well in the Nine Nations Union. It should be quite difficult for his sect to rely on him alone. If I recall correctly, he should’ve entered Nascent Soul stage the same time Senior Martial Brother Cheng did. The end of his lifespan should also be drawing near.”

“That’s right. Old Ghost Ling Hu is just a bit older than me, but he is quite a bit more proficient at extending his lifespan. Additionally, Yellow Maple Valley should also have no problem after his death. They can just rely on the repute of their allied Nascent Soul cultivators. I’ve also had similar worries for the Drifting Cloud Sect when I passed, and feared that Junior Martial Brother would find it difficult to stand alone!

“Were if not for the sacred spirit veins of the Dreamcloud Mountains, Junior Martial Brother would’ve found it difficult to preserve the sect by himself. But even so, many would look at our sect with greed once it appears any weaker. My original thoughts were to urge Junior Martial Brother to take the initiative to withdraw from the Dreamcloud Mountains once I passed, avoiding any potential calamity the sect may encounter. But now that Junior Martial Brother Han has joined us, the situation has changed.

“Although Junior Martial Brother seems to be a cultivator who is wholeheartedly dedicated to pursuing the Immortal Dao and is disinterested in sect affairs, I am actually relieved by this. So long as we carefully win him over, our sect will continue to exist without worry for another thousand years!” The silver-haired old man twirled his beard in his hand as if he had a plan up his sleeve.

The middle-aged man hesitated for a moment before worriedly saying, “But while Junior Martial Brother Han may be a cultivation genius, his age is too young and he just recently condensed his Nascent Soul. I don’t know whether or not his skills are up to par.”

With a pensive expression, the silver-haired old man said, “Yes, I also share the same worries. After all, there are a few cultivators wholeheartedly dedicated to pursuing the Dao that are unwilling to spend much time cultivating powerful abilities. While this results in a deep cultivation, these cultivators may be unable to defeat cultivators that are a grade lower than them. Although I don’t believe Junior Martial Brother Han to be such a cultivator, it would be better to test this. As such, I will be staying behind to guard the sect. You will accompany him to the trade meet.”

“Does Senior Martial Brother mean to say...” The middle-aged man revealed a sudden trace of understanding.

The old man smiled and thought to say something further when the mist in front of him suddenly parted. The old man immediately grew quiet as the middle-aged man followed suit.

The two walked into the path that opened through the fog without any reservations and disappeared from sight.

...

The largest trade meet in the Heavenly South convened at the southmost country of the Nine Nations Union, the State of Yu. Deep within the mountains of this country laid Soaring Heavens City, the capital of the Nine Nations Union. Cultivators from all over the continent flocked to this country.

Be it man or woman, young or old, all of those that resided within the city were cultivators. This city alone even had seven cultivators at mid Nascent Soul stage or higher stationed there, resulting in the immediate deaths of any cultivator who dared to cause trouble in the city. As a result, regardless of a cultivator’s affiliation, none dared to act imprudently within.

Two months before the start of largest trade meet in the Heavenly South, the Nine Nations Alliance activated a spell formation with a resounding reputation, the Greater Light Extinguishing Formation, to protect the city in place of a majority of its normal restrictions.

Because a few cultivators have already made their way to the city out of impatience or otherwise, there were already stalls placed inside. Trade was already being conducted between cultivators.

While the official days of the trade meet would have treasures of all kind in great number, they weren’t something that common cultivators could afford. They would rather find a few suitable uncommon materials ahead of time instead.

The quiet, cold Soaring Heavens City soon became bustling with activity as if it were filled with the liveliness of the marketplaces in common mortal cities. However, those walking the streets of the city were cultivators of high rank and the currency being used were spirit stones.

The city only possessed a single auction house which was under the control of the Nine Nations Union. It had also begun to appraise and auction off all sorts of rare treasures, contributing to the liveliness of the city.

Just as the trade meet was only half a month away, there were three streaks of light steadily flying through the sky several thousands of kilometers away.

Once the three lights grew closer, they were revealed to be two men and one woman. The woman was a cool and elegant beauty. She flew at the side of a youth with a common appearance that wore a rather intimate expression.

The third person in their party was a blue-robed middle-aged man whose clothes fluttered through the wind in a display of unordinary majesty.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

Chapter 676: Spiritual Sense Formation

“Fellow Daoist speaks the truth, but I have no intention of handing over my concubine. I merely wish to exchange a few pointers.” Han Li spoke calmly and soon released his spiritual sense. With the appearance of an astonishing aura, something shot towards the Marquis.

“Good.” Marquis Nanlong appeared completely calm and released his spiritual sense. Two streaks of nearly incorporeal force appeared between the two and burst in a collision. A violent gust suddenly appeared and blew out in every direction.

Marquis Nanlong felt alarmed by the development as his initial spiritual sense probe instantly grew several times greater in size. Layers and streams of violent white instantly flew into the gap of space between Han Li and the Marquis, causing their silhouettes to blur as if there were two originless and unmoving shadows .

“Spiritual sense formation! How can this be!? How is Junior Martial Brother Han’s spiritual sense so strong!” Lu Luo couldn’t help but cry out in disbelief.

“Spiritual sense formation? Could my Lord win?”

“I’m not sure either, but ordinarily, spiritual sense formation is a divine ability only mid Nascent Soul cultivators can grasp. For Junior Martial Brother Han to be able to use this technique, his main cultivation art must be specialized in spiritual sense. That is the only possible explanation.” Lu Luo’s excited words turned into a pensive mutter halfway through.

Filled with hope by her Martial Ancestor Lu’s explanation, Mu Peiling said, “In that case, my Lord must have a fighting chance!”

With a shifting expression, Lu Luo said, “That’s hard to say. There are differences in strength among even similar grade cultivators. Marquis Nanlong had already entered the mid Nascent Soul stage three hundred years ago. Although his progress has stalled, he is without a doubt only a step away from late Nascent Soul stage. It should be quite difficult for Junior Martial Brother Han to win against this old eccentric!”

When Mu Peiling heard this, her briefly hopeful heart immediately turned ice-cold once again.

At that moment, the explosions in the skies suddenly became far more dense and winds began to continuously revolve, forming a huge ring of white wind around Han Li and the Marquis.

Lu Luo yelped in surprise as an odd expression appeared on his face, “I can’t believe it. Junior Martial Brother isn’t losing.”

Mu Peiling was overjoyed by this and thought to ask something more, but a series of blinding white lights filled the skies. Soon after, claps of thunder rang out and the ring of wind surrounding them ruptured, sweeping up their surroundings in a violent windstorm.

A hundred meters away from them, the others revealed shock as they saw the overbearing squalls arrive towards them.

“Not good!” Lu Luo softly shouted. His figure blurred and blocked Mu Peiling. At the same time, he crossed his hands, summoning a blue light barrier in front of them.

In that short moment, the fierce squall had already arrived at their barrier. Strange creaks continuously sounded out from the wind as if it were a heavy strike. An instant later, there was a deep indentation left behind on the barrier.

Fortunately, the winds quickly scattered and a majority swept past them. The light barrier was soon restored to its original form.

As for Marquis Nanlong’s group of soldier cultivators, they lifted their golden halberds in a disciplined manner, forming a huge barrier of golden light around them and the carriage.

However, the golden light only lasted against the white gale for an instant before shattering. When the remaining gust swept through, the cultivators behind the barrier held their heads in their arms and miserably screamed. Blood bled from every opening of their head in a frightening display.

Only the two concubines were safe due to the carriage’s protective restrictions. However, their faces were pale from fear.

Mu Peiling felt her blood turn cold at the sight as she turned her gaze once more to Han Li, mesmerized.

At that moment, Marquis Nanlong coldly snorted. A ball of golden light suddenly appeared and burst into countless streaks of golden light that quickly surrounded his servants.

When the golden light appeared, his servants ceased their screams and stood firm once more. Although they appeared panic-stricken, they no longer seemed to be in pain.

Having saved his subordinates, Marquis Nanlong turned his gaze towards Han Li and revealed bewilderment as if he couldn’t believe that Han Li’s spiritual sense could rival his own.

In that previous bout, he had released a majority of his spiritual sense but Han Li was able to effortlessly continue. From how relaxed he appeared, it seemed possible that Han Li’s spiritual sense was actually stronger than his own.

Marquis Nanlong’s contempt had long disappeared and his heart wavered.

At that moment, Han Li widely smiled at him and casually said, “Shall we stop the contest? I fear I might not last if this continues.”

With some further thought, Marquis Nanlong’s expression relaxed and he said, “Haha! Fellow Daoist Han is far too modest. Let alone your techniques, but even your spiritual sense isn’t inferior to my own in the slightest. Let us drop the contest, else we may end up injured.”

When Han Li heard this, he inwardly sighed despite the smile on his face. Although he wasn’t willing to truly fight against this Marquis Nanlong, from what he had experienced in the contest, Han Li should prove an equal match at the very least.

However, their recent struggle had caused the Marquis to view Han Li with some apprehension and he didn’t dare to treat him lightly. Moreover, his spiritual sense was strong enough to meet his conditions. He had a request to make of Han Li.

Marquis Hanlong strangely smiled at Han Li and stealthily sent him a voice transmission, “Since Fellow Daoist Han’s spiritual sense is on par with mine, I will tell you the true reason for the contest. It is as Fellow Daoist guessed; I had a different objective in mind for forcibly testing your spiritual sense. However, this matter is quite important and it is inconvenient to speak of it here.

The jade slip contains a map. On the fourth day of the trade meet, there will be a gathering of cultivators as indicated. I will introduce you to these Fellow Daoists, and we will discuss a matter that will benefit us all.”

Afterwards, he stroked his storage pouch and took out an exquisite jade slip that he tossed towards Han Li without any regard to Lu Luo.

When Han Li saw this, he immediately extended his hand and took the jade slip. After examining the Marquis for a moment, he placed the jade slip into his storage pouch for later.

The Marquis chuckled at the sight and then descended towards his carriage in a sphere of golden light. The carriage’s golden light then appeared once more and he quickly made his way towards Soaring Heavens City with his escort.

The Marquis seemed to ignore Lu Luo in his departure. While other Nascent Soul cultivators would feel indignant and dissatisfied by this treatment, Lu Luo knew of the Marquis’ eccentric personality and could only smile wryly.

At that moment, Han Li descended towards Elder Lu and Mu Peiling.

“My Lord, are you alright?” When she saw Han Li return, Mu Peiling greeted him with a flushed face as she stared at him with bright eyes.

Although her 'Lord' had contested with Marquis Nanlong for only a moment, that recent display of mighty ability had greatly shaken her heart. She felt somewhat more appreciative of her position by his side and faintly developed a sense of security from him.

“It was nothing, merely a bit of effort.” Han Li calmly said. Her sudden display of concern had made his heart throb.

Lu Luo looked at Han Li for a long while with admiration before beaming and said, “Junior Martial Brother, you keep your secrets well. You made me worry for nothing.”

Han Li calmly said, “I never meant to conceal this from my two Senior Martial Brothers, it’s just that you haven’t ever asked me about it, but let’s hurry for now. Those spiritual sense gales will certainly draw the attention of many cultivators.”

Lu Luo instantly agreed, “That’s right. It would be troublesome if this were widely spread! Let’s quickly head to Soaring Skies City!”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

TL Note: Mu Peiling now refers to Han Li as "My Lord" or "Lord" instead of "Sir"

Chapter 677: Meeting the Boy

Han Li stood on the side of a mountain and glanced at the huge city walls several kilometers away. He softly said, “This is Soaring Heavens Mountain?”

Lu Luo stood at Han Li’s side and spoke with a similar expression, “Has Junior Martial Brother never seen such a large city before? The Nine Nations Union have expanded this city several times before reaching such a size. Although I wouldn’t dare to say that this is the largest city in the Heavenly South, it definitely is among the top five. The entire city is also made of huge stones from the same source.”

When Han Li heard this, he faintly smiled. What city could possibly best Scattered Star Seas’ Heavenly Star City? Now that city was truly gargantuan existence. Although Soaring Heavens City was a huge city that spanned over fifty kilometers, it still wasn’t something that could be compared to Heavenly Star City.

Han Li didn’t care much of it, but Mu Peiling was clearly amazed by the sight of this stone city.

“Nevertheless, we will have to approach Soaring Heavens City on foot. How troublesome!” Lu Luo shook his hand and spoke with slight dissatisfaction.

Han Li pursed his lips and replied, “The Nine Nations Union can’t help it. There are far too many high grade cultivators that have come. They would have no way of managing the city if they were to come by air. Fortunately, these restrictions are merely superficial against Nascent Soul cultivators like us. If we truly wished to fly, these restrictions couldn’t do anything to us.”

“I didn’t expect for Junior Martial Brother to be so open minded. Alright, let’s go. The sooner we get to the city, the more profit will be had!” Ever since Han Li’s bout with Marquis Nanlong, Senior Martial Brother Lu had treated Han Li in a far greater familiarity.

Han Li nodded with a smile, and the three began to walk towards the city gate in stride.

Because they were in the vicinity of Soaring Heavens City, there were vast crowds entering the city from every direction.

Han Li and Lu Luo already concealed their cultivation as they didn’t wish to cause a disturbance. They entered the crowd under the guise of Foundation Establishment cultivators and made way towards the city gate.

Although there were protectors from the Nine Nations Union, they didn’t discover anything amiss from Han Li or Lu Luo.

After they entered Soaring Heavens City, they spotted orderly rows of stone buildings. There were stone streets of varying length between each of the stone buildings, forming what seemed to be a crowded weblike pathway.

Since Lu Luo had been at Soaring Heavens in the past, he suggested, “Let’s first get a fixed residence. There is no need for us to barge into any inns. There are distinguished pavilions that are specialized for Nascent Soul cultivators like us. We’ll be heading there directly.”

Han Li didn’t raise any objects and followed after Elder Lu with Mu Peiling in tow.

Lu Luo ended up bringing to the two towards a corner of the city. A short moment later, the three passed through many roads before arriving in front of a white light barrier. Behind the light barrier laid many pavilions that were simply designed but elegant nonetheless.

There were other cultivators outside the light barrier, peering inside with expressions of admiration and reverence. However, they didn’t dare to stay for too long and each of them eventually hurried on their way.

“The restrictions here are only something a Nascent Soul cultivator can dissolve.” Lu Luo pressed his hand against the light barrier and blue light flickered from his palm. With a woosh, the white light barrier formed a hole from where Lu Luo’s palm had touched it. He then flew inside with a blur, followed by the light barrier closing at an inconceivable speed.

After a moment of surprise, Han Li opened his mouth and spouted out a mist of azure light. The white light barrier flickered upon contact with the azure light and a three meter large hole immediately shattered. Han Li grabbed onto Mu Peiling’s waist and quickly brought her through the light barrier.

Mu Peiling blushed from being in Han Li’s embrace and felt a peculiar emotion in her heart.

Lu Luo appeared amazed at how easily Han Li had broken through the barrier, but his calm soon returned.

Lu Luo pointed to a few of the pavilions with a smile and said, “These pavilions are for the use for any Nascent Soul cultivators and any disciples they may bring. They may be chosen at will, but the light restrictions surrounding the pavilions illustrate whether or not they are already occupied. However, not all Nascent Soul cultivators are willing to use this place. There are a few eccentrics that are willing to stay outside the city or at inns.”

As expected, a small portion of the pavilions were already glowing with light restrictions.

Lu Luo pointed to two pavilions a couple hundred of meters away and proposed, “Junior Martial Brother, let’s pick those neighboring pavilions. If anything happens, it will be best if we look after each other.”

After examining them for a moment, Han Li replied, “Let’s do as you say.”

Just as Lu Luo was about to say something else, the white-yellow light barrier covering another pavilion suddenly opened to reveal a small figure. When this person swept past Han Li and Luo Lu, they astonishedly said, “Yi! Is it not Brother Lu? I didn’t expect for you to arrive so early!”

Han Li hastily peered in the speaker’s direction.

This person was a child with delicate, flawless skin. He was the Child Fire Dragon that Han Li previous saw at the sacred area of the three sects. Once he finished speaking, his bright eyes turned towards Han Li and Mu Peiling, resulting an expression of astonishment.

With his vast memory, he was able to recall them both being among the finalists of the last Sword Trial Assembly. However, Han Li was now only using a superficial cultivation concealment technique, something ineffective against cultivators of the same grade. After a moment of surprise, the boy revealed an expression of understanding.

Lu Luo quickly smiled upon seeing him. It seemed their relationship was quite good. “Hehe! So it turned out to be Fellow Daoist Lan! How are we early? You obviously rushed over here. Ah that’s right, this is our newly joined Elder Han. Junior Martial Brother Han, I believe you’ve met Brother Lan once before. There should be no further need for introductions.

When the Child Fire Dragon heard this, he wryly smiled and said, “So it is true that Fellow Daoist Han entered the Drifting Cloud Sect as a new elder. My eyes were truly awry that day.”

Having heard this, Han Li offered a cursory explanation with a smile, “I had merely heard of the grand reputation of the Sacred Spirit Well Tree and wished to enter the sacred area to take a look. I sincerely hope Fellow Daoist Lan didn’t take offense.”

“Since Fellow Daoist is now an elder of the Drifting Cloud Sect, this matter need not be mentioned further. However, you two have arrived quite timely. I happened to be meeting a few friendly acquaintances of mine at the Crystal Dragon Pavilion for a small scale trade. How about you two Fellow Daoists come and take a look. Perhaps you might find something you like.” The Child Fire Dragon seemed to have a straightforward temperament to have invited them with a beckon.

Lu Luo joyously said, “To think there would be an exchange so soon. Tch Tch. We’ve definitely come at a good time,” he then hastily turned towards Han Li with his expression quickly turning solemn, “Junior Martial Brother Han, there aren’t many exchanges that occur between Nascent Soul cultivators. We must go, else we could miss some good items.”

Han Li calmly smiled and said, “Then let us follow Senior Martial Brother Lan!”

After Han Li and Luo Lu arranged restrictions outside their pavilions, they followed the Child Fire Dragon out of the residential area.

Han Li had instructed Mu Peiling to stay inside the pavilion for the time being.

The Child Fire Dragon explained in a clear voice, “The Crystal Dragon Pavilion was opened by a good friend of mine from the Nine Nations Union. My good friend has made a wide range of connections, acquinting himself with those from every power. As such, he was able to form this trade meeting. However, In order to prevent any unnecessary trouble, all of those attending will be concealing their true appearances.”

Lu Luo’s heart stirred and he spoke with amazement, “Brother Lan seems to be talking of Daoist Heavencrystal. However, I recall that Daoist Heavencrystal isn’t fond of business matters. Did he truly take the initiative to hold this trade meeting?”

The Child Fire Dragon chuckled and said, “Hehe, I didn’t expect that Fellow Daoist Lu would know of my old friend’s reputation. That’s right, while my old friend isn’t fond of such inconvenience, there are a few required materials that he had been searching for. I reckon he took the initiative to start this trade meet in order to find them.”

Lu Luo nodded his head, “Oh, if that’s the case, it does seem quite likely.”

As Han Li listened to the two, his expression remained as always.

The three walked towards a pure white pavilion ahead of them. It was three stories tall and grew more narrow towards the top. There was a silver sign that hung from the building with the words “Crystal Dragon Pavilion.”

Chapter 678: Nascent Soul Meeting

“It’s right here. Fellow Daoists, let’s go in.” The Child Fire Dragon smiled at the two and walked towards the Crystal Dragon Pavilion with a swagger.

Once they approached the pavilion’s large gate, Han Li casually took a look inside and revealed surprise. The interior appeared to be that of an ordinary restaurant. Not only was it full of guests that were eating and drinking, there were also several waiters that were scurrying between tables with dishes in hand. The scents of fine wine and food were accompanied with the clanging of cups.

After they pushed open the gates, they saw a foot long wooden plate hung at the side. ‘This building is taken, outsiders are prohibited’ were written on it in pitch-black words.

“That old ghost Heavencrystal is still playing around with silly illusion techniques. Really!” After muttering those words, the Child Fire Dragon paid no more attention to it and walked in with a stride.

When Han Li heard this, his heart stirred and he swept his spiritual sense past the floor. He soon revealed a strange expression, but he continued inside. Once they passed the gate, the guests, waiters, scents and sounds, all disappeared like the pop of a bubble.

Han Li casually swept his gaze at the scene and saw that all that remained was a grey mist surrounding the building. There was merely an old-fashioned table at the center of the room with a copper lamp that was lit with a grey-robed Daoist with an amiable face sitting behind the lamp. He appeared to be sixty years of age and was glancing at the three with a smile.

“I didn’t expect that Brother Lan would arrive, let alone bring guests. This old Daoist’s eyes are rather poor. It seems as if I’ve never seen this azure-robed Fellow daoist before. Could he have recently entered Nascent Soul?” The grey-robed Daoist smiled and cordially beckoned to them. His intimate manners unconsciously aroused in a good impression amongst them.

The Child Fire Dragon returned the smile, but he spoke with an unexpectedly harsh tone, “Brother Heavencrystal, I’ve brought two uninvited guests. Surely you won’t refuse them?”

“Why would I do that? This place welcomes all Fellow Daoists. Besides, I am acquainted with Fellow Daoist lu. It is only...” The old Daoist’s gaze hovered towards Han Li.

Han Li took a step forward and saluted him, “I am the Drifting Cloud Sect’s Han Li, a newly ascended Nascent Soul cultivator. I hope Daoist Heavencrystal can provide me some guidance in the future.”

Daoist Heavencrystal pleasantly smiled and said, “So it turned out to be a sect member of Fellow Daoist Lu. From his young age, he certain to have boundless prospects.”

“Enough, old friend.The others should be arriving soon. We’ll be going upstairs.” From his direct words, it seemed the Child Fire Dragon had a rather deep friendship with him.

Daoist Heavencrystal sighed, “Brother Lan is still so impatient. Almost everyone has already arrived. I’m sure a few of the more impatient ones have already started trading as well. Here are two black spirit masks for those Fellow Daoists. Brother Lan, do you need one?” He then flipped his hands and summoned two black wood masks into his hands with a flash of white light. Talisman characters appeared on their surface.

The Child Fire Dragon’s cheeks bulged as if he were annoyed. He snorted and said, “Of course you should know that with my stature, regardless of any illusions I use, I cannot conceal myself.”

“Of course. Please come up. This old man will join you in a bit.” Daoist Heavencrystal casually smiled and tossed the masks to Han Li and Lu Luo. At that same time, a white streak of light show towards the mist behind him. The mist disappeared and revealed stairs of glittering light that led to the second floor.

Without any further courtesies, the Child Fire Dragon wordlessly walked around the table and climbed to the second floor. Lu Luo and Han Li saluted the old Daoist before following him up the stairs.

Once Han Li discovered that his mask was exactly the same as Lu Luo’s, he wore it without any reservations and climbed up the stairs.

The mask was cold to the touch and soft. To Han Li’s surprise, it was so comfortable, it felt as if it wasn't even there.

He turned his head to look at Lu Luo and saw that he also wore the mask, turning his face into an icy wooden carving. Han Li faintly smiled at the sight.

At that moment, the three had already arrived on the second floor. It was well lit with over a hundred fist-sized moonstones embedded in the ceiling and walls.

But what surprised Han Li most of all was that the second floor was several times more spacious than the first floor. It appeared far narrower than the first floor from the outside.

Of course, the second floor wasn’t empty. There were tables lined up against the walls with chairs accompanying each of them. There were various clothed cultivators sitting in many of them. From their bodies and hair, it appeared there were men and women of all ages.

When Han Li and company arrived, countless cold glints swept past them.

Many of them clearly recognized the unconcealed Child Fire Dragon; the expressions of their eyes varied anywhere from goodwill, hatred, and indifferences. There were a few gazes that even carried unconcealable killing intent, suggesting they formed animosity in the past.

The Child Fire Dragon was unconcerned with these gazes and led Han Li and Luo Lu to an empty table. At that moment, Han Li glanced at the others.

Because of the masks’ concealment, those with formidable spiritual sense such as Han Li were unable to clearly see their faces. However, there was no doubt that each of them were Nascent Soul cultivators from their spiritual Qi fluctuations. There were even two among them that were at mid Nascent Soul stage, but they were sitting alone and none dared to rashly sit next to them.

What appeared to be a small pavilion held at least twenty Nascent Soul cultivators, something that was rarely heard of.

Before this, Han Li hadn’t seen so many Nascent Soul eccentrics in one place. It seemed one’s cultivation had to be at a similar level to encounter so many cultivators.

Han Li’s gaze flickered and it suddenly focused at a particular corner of the floor. As Daoist Heavencrystal had mentioned, there were already a few impatient cultivators that had gathered around a table.

Their lips were moving from voice transmissions and they occasionally exchanged jade boxes and small bottles in some small scale trades.

However, most of the other cultivators were sitting with their eyes closed in meditation. They were waiting for everyone to gather before they started trading. It seemed what was being traded prematurely wasn't anything particularly valuable.

Also, in what seemed to be an attempt to avoid being recognized, many of the cultivators were completely silent, and only spoke to one another through voice transmissions.

The second floor of the pavilion had completely maintained its silence in a bizarre and stifling manner.

The Child Fire Dragon hadn’t bothered to wear a mask, attracting many gazes as a result. Nevertheless, there were none who took the initiative to reveal themselves to him.

Sitting right across from Han Li and company was an extremely fat man, who also wore no mask. His waist was four times thicker than the average person and even caused his chair to slightly deform. Regardless, this person didn’t seem to mind in the least. When he saw Han Li glance at him, he shot a beaming smile in his direction. However, the many layers of fat on his face made it difficult to accept his kind intentions.

Sitting at the plump man’s side was a very shapely female cultivator. Although she wore a mask, her eyes with vivid and captivating. Still, everyone present was certain of the cunning of those around them, and none paid any particular attention to the woman’s charm.

When Han Li saw this, he heard Lu Luo’s voice transmission, “Junior martial brother Han, be careful. That fatty may seem harmless, but together with the woman at his side, they are the Devil Dao Harmonious Bond Sect’s Flesh Rouge Devils. With their secret pair cultivation techniques, they are able to contend against even mid Nascent Soul cultivators. Avoid provoking them, they are incredibly difficult to deal with!”

When Han Li heard this, he felt his heart tremble and he immediately added their names onto a long list of those he should be wary of. After he finished observing the characteristics of all others in the room, he closed his eyes and silently meditated.

Over the period of a long while, several masked Nascent Soul cultivators continuously entered the room.

Daoist Heavencrystal was the last to enter, drawing the eyes of all the cultivators present. He directly walked to the center of the floor and casually waved his arm, summoning a table and chair towards him with white light. He then smiled and said, “Everyone should’ve already arrived. If nobody has anything else to say, let us start the trade meet.”

Chapter 683: Two Choices

Han Li turned his head and coldly glanced at the two Core Formation cultivators that were passing by, causing them to immediately swallow their words. He didn’t recognize the two middle-aged cultivators, nor did he know which sect they belonged to.

At that moment, the shopkeeper and his two assistants had already been thoroughly forced to the ground due to their close proximity to the immense spiritual pressure. They were incapable of moving in the slightest, seeming panic-stricken, only to grow even more terrified upon hearing that Han Li was a Nascent Soul cultivator. They hurriedly tried to beg for forgiveness, but they could barely even gasp for air, let alone speak.

The surrounding cultivators all paled, while a few of the more cowardly ones had already fled in fear of being implicated.

Han Li showed consideration for Sun Huo, and the pressure had little effect on him apart from his initial recoil. But once he recognized Han Li, his expression changed before he deeply saluted him and said, “Disciple Sun Huo pays his respects to Martial Ancestor Han.”

Paying no further attention to the three men in front of him, Han Li turned around and looked at the half-torn talisman in Sun Huo’s hand. He nodded his head and said, “It seems there is no need for introductions. You already know of my identity.”

When Sun Huo recalled the rude words he spoke to Han Li at the sacred area, he felt greatly worried and humbly apologized with sincerity, “Disciple was unaware of Martial Ancestor’s true form. I hope he will forgive disciple’s arrogant words.”

Han Li looked at Sun Huo and slowly said, “I had yet to become a sect elder at that time, so of course I won’t blame you. However, that torn talisman of yours seems to have something to do with me.”

Sun Huo was stunned as something suddenly came to mind. He joyfully said, “Could this ruined talisman be...”

Han Li waved and cut him off, “Leave this matter for later.” Han Li’s eyes then narrowed as he gazed at a silver streak of light flying across the sky.

The only cultivators that were allowed to fly in Soaring Heavens City were obviously the Nine Nations Union protectors. They were responsible for keeping order during the entire duration of the trade fair.

Sun Huo didn’t dare to speak any further and obediently stood still in place. However, his heart was brimming with uncontainable excitement, and his grasp on the talisman paper grew even more careful.

At that moment, the streak of light arrived before Han Li to reveal a yellow-haired old man possessing mid Core Formation cultivation. A small golden sword was embroidered on his chest, the emblem of an enforcer.

The old man could sense Han Li’s astonishing pressure from a distance. However, this area laid within his jurisdictions. Even if there was a Nascent Soul cultivator showing their might, he had no choice but to confront them.

Once the old man spotted Han Li motionlessly standing on the road, he saluted him and said, “Junior is an enforcer of Soaring Heavens City, Wu Fei. I am unaware as to why Senior is angry. Might I ask how I can help?” Given the vast disparity in their cultivation, it was only natural for the enforcer to speak respectfully.

Hands behind his back, Han Li indifferently said, “It’s not much. I was merely walking through the street when I heard this shopkeeper speak a few words about our Drifting Cloud Sect. Therefore, I merely wished for him to repeat what he said.”

“Ah! The shopkeeper certainly spouted nonsense. How dare they offend Senior? You three, hurry up and apologize.” The old man felt an immense headache upon hearing Han Li. When the matter pertained to a sect’s reputation, it was hard to say how severe the matter was. As such, he first offered a word of appeasement before rebuking the shopkeeper and his associates.

Han Li immediately withdrew his spiritual pressure, allowing the three to tremblingly crawl up from the ground. With a bloodless complexion, the shopkeeper immediately said, “Senior, Junior’s words were completely mistaken. Junior truly meant no disrespect to your sect. Just now that Fellow Daoist had ruined a firecloud talisman, but Junior will no longer be pursuing any compensation. Junior can only offer his apologies.”

When Han Li heard this, he frowned and his expression grew gloomy. With a sinister smile, Han Li said, “What? You believe that I will let you off so easily? First let me take a look at the firecloud talisman in that box. If it truly was refined by a grandmaster, I will pay the spirit stones on this disciple’s behalf. But if it isn’t, hehe...”

The shopkeeper reacted quickly and hurriedly spoke before Han Li could glance at the wooden box, “There is no need Senior! That firecloud talisman is an ordinary talisman. Junior accepts any punishment!”

Han Li said nothing further and took a glance at the enforcer.

When the old man saw this, he knew what to do. He immediately bowed and said, “Please be at ease Senior. This shopkeeper will be heavily punished for his transgressions. Senior may hand this matter over to me.”

“Since that’s the case, then so be it. I don’t have the leisure to handle such a petty affair. Sun Huo, you’ll be coming with me!” Han Li’s body blurred, and reappeared at Sun Huo’s side. Then with flashes of blinding yellow light, the two disappeared into the ground.

The cultivators nearby yelped in admiration at such a marvelous earth movement technique. They hadn’t seen such a thing before.

Upon seeing Han Li depart, the old man immediately felt relieved. But when he glanced at the three offenders who were heaving large sighs of relief, his expression grew icy, “You three will follow me and tell me the truth about everything that happened. This matter won’t be forgiven so easily.”

When the shopkeeper heard this, his relief instantly turned to misery.

A moment after this exchange, Han Li appeared with Sun Huo in a flash of yellow light inside a secluded stone building.

Han Li deeply glanced at Sun Huo and said, “Here will be fine. Let me take a look at that torn piece of talisman paper.”

“Yes, Martial Ancestor!” Sun Huo presented the torn talisman paper to Han Li without any hesitation.

Han Li took the talisman paper and quickly glanced at it before silently taking out the other half. Under Sun Huo’s unwavering gaze, Han Li put the two halves together and found that they matched without a single flaw.

Sun Huo’s deepest fear disappeared without a trace before he deeply saluted Han Li without any hesitation, “Sun Huo pays his respect to Master.”

Han Li calmly nodded his head and turned the talisman paper to ash with a flicker of red light. Sun Huo was startled by the sight but immediately calmed down. Han Li found the youth’s willpower to be satisfactory.

Han Li calmly asked, “It seems you’re a descendant of Sun Ergou, but don’t go calling me Master in such a hurry. First, how about telling me what generation descendant you are?”

Sun Huo immediately relied, “I am a seventh generation descendant of the ancestor.”

“During that year, Sun Ergou pledged that the Sun Clan that he raised would hold me as their master [1] , but because of a few peculiar matters, I had to leave the Heavenly South. As such, the Sun Clan has never truly served me nor have I offered the Sun Clan any protection. Now that a descendant of the Sun Clan has successfully entered the cultivation world, that pledge may no longer hold. But since I had some relation to your ancestor, I will give you two choices.”

Han Li smirked and calmly continued, “The first option is that I directly give you some good cultivation supplies, such as medicine pills and magic tools. From then on, there will be no relation between us. Don’t hold any hope that I will show any further consideration towards you. The other choice is that you fulfill the pledge of your ancestor and serve me as my retainer. I would in turn place a restriction on your body to prevent you from betraying me. Also, I will assign you tasks that will be potentially dangerous. However, I will also do my utmost to increase your cultivation and provide you with cultivation guidance. There will be benefits far beyond your imagination and so long as your aptitude isn’t too poor, there may be hope of you achieving Core Formation.”

Once this was said, Sun Huo’s expression wavered and he appeared to be at a complete loss for a moment. It was clear that this scenario was far from what he had expected.

After a long while, Sun Huo’s expression grew resolute, “Martial Ancestor, I...”

Han Li abruptly interrupted Sun Huo and said, “There is no need to rush. Give me your answer once the trade fair ends. Consider this an opportunity for you to make certain of your decision. Take this time to make careful deliberations and find me at my cave residence once you return to the State of Xi.”

Sun Huo felt that this was a rather generous proposal after some further thought and hastily agreed, “Disciple will do as you command. Many thanks for your understanding, Martial Ancestor!”

“Good. Now, that that’s taken care of I have other matters to attend to. Look after yourself!” Han Li nodded with a relaxed expression and disappeared in a flash of yellow light.

Sun Huo didn’t leave immediately. Instead, he muttered to himself for a long while and sighed before slowly walking out.

By the time Sun Huo was leaving, Han Li had already returned to his residence and raised his head to look at the night sky while a strange expression slowly surfaced on his face.

[1]. Sun Ergou was luggage carrier that was roped into serving Han Li (first appeared in Chapter 100: Jia Yuan City). In the past, he looked after Crooked Soul while Han Li was at Yellow Maple Valley.

In Chapter 335: Astonishment, Sun Ergou swore servitude to Han Li in exchange for the protection of his clan. He was given torn talisman paper as an identifier.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

Chapter 685: Meeting the Marquis

Once the old Daoist heard what Han Li wanted, his uncontrollable excitement promptly faded away. With his newly restored calm, he said, “It seems Fellow Daoist Han plans on using this to extort me.”

Han Li calmly said, “Extort? Those words are mistaken. Until now, I’ve never made any demands of you; rather, I gifted you with several rare soul stones. If Fellow Daoist doesn’t feel this arrangement to be profitable, just pretend I never asked the second question, and you can keep those soul stones.”

Daoist Heavencrystal’s expression relaxed and then began to waver while Han Li simply stood at the side without urging him in the slightest.

After a long while, the old Daoist coldly said, “If I give you the puppet designs, you will more or less be able to tell whether they are legitimate. But how can I possibly know if you were telling the truth about the Umbra Beasts?”

Han Li unhurriedly responded with a tranquil tone, “To tell the truth, even if Fellow Daoist knew where the Umbra Beasts are, he would have no method of getting there. Not only is that place deadly beyond belief, but even if one is fortunate enough to enter, there is no way to return. Even I was only barely able to escape alive. Even if you don’t believe me, my soul stones are genuine all the same. I’ll give a portion of them to you for the puppet refinement designs. Enough so that Fellow Daoist definitely won’t suffer a loss. Besides, what use are puppet refinement methods without the soul stones required to use them.”

Daoist Heavencrystal frowned and revealed a trace of hesitation.

After the old Daoist deliberated on what there was to gain and lose, his expression relaxed before he said, “Fine! I have no interest in mulling over whether the supposed source of your soul stones is real. I will only ask how many soul stones you plan on using to exchange for the puppet refinement designs? If it’s too few, I would rather just monopolize them.”

While Han Li was happy about this outcome, he betrayed none of it in his voice, “I will have to see the value of the ancient puppet designs first. If they are only on the level of the puppets that were traded during the day, then I have no interest in looking at them.”

The old Daoist wore an odd expression, “Those puppets were only defective goods I found. From what you’ve said, it seems the more powerful these puppets are the more soul stones you are willing to pay.”

Han Li pursed his lips, “That’s right. If there are designs to refine a puppet that can match the strike of a Nascent Soul cultivator I would be willing to exchange thirty soul stones for it.”

Daoist Heavencrystal seriously asked, “Would these soul stones be of the same quality as the ones you’ve given from the start?”

‘Could there truly be designs for ancient puppets on the level of Nascent Soul cultivators?’ Han Li was amazed at the prospect and immediately grew overjoyed. Without any restraint, he said, “Since when have my words been false?”

“Fine. This jade slip contains the designs for the ancient puppets. I will be directly giving it to you, not lending it.” The old Daoist quickly took out a white jade slip from his storage pouch and tossed it to Han Li while a cunning expression appeared on his face.

Han Li was stunned by his actions and faintly felt like something was amiss. After some thought, he bluntly took the jade slip and swept his spiritual sense through it. After a long while, Han Li’s complexion fluctuated between red and white before he started glaring at Daoist Heavencrystal in silence.

The old man beamed back at him and said, “What’s wrong? The greatest of these puppet designs are able to match the strike of a mid Nascent Soul stage cultivator. Is there something not in accordance with your request?”

Han Li angrily said, “Humph! What part isn’t? The main ingredients for these puppets are heaven-defying materials on the level of ten thousand year old Ironwood. And the supplementary materials aren’t just rare, I’ve never even heard of them. Where am I supposed to find them?”

“Hehe! You have this humble Daoist’s sympathies, but there is little I can do. Look on the bright side, there’s an illustration accompanying each of the materials. Perhaps Fellow Daoist may come across them with enough luck and will even manage to acquire enough to make a puppet!”

As the old Daoist anticipated, Han Li’s expression quickly grew furious and he asked, “Could it be Fellow Daoist Heavencrystal has already found the materials? Why else would he be gathering soul stones?”

With a calm expression, Daoist Heavencrystal said, “When did this humble Daoist say that he would be personally refining the puppets? I merely found two half-finished high grade puppets from the ruins. With these soul stones, I’ll be able to use them. There is no need for me to create them from scratch.”

“You...” After hearing this Han Li grew silent for a long while.

“Alright, this humble Daoist already gave you the puppet refinement designs. Now about the...”

“They’re yours!” Before the old Daoist could even finish speaking with his insincere smile, Han Li unhappily swept his sleeve across the table. With a flicker of green light, a small pile of soul stones appeared.

Daoist Heavencrystal was overjoyed, but he thought he should say something further out of embarrassment. Han Li dismissed this by waving his arm and saying, “Because I was careless, I suffered quite a loss, but I have no complaints. Now that the debt has been settled, I will be taking my leave.” Han Li gave a salute before gloomily leaving the building.

The old Daoist glanced at Han Li’s departing figure and shook his head with closed eyes. He then nodded his head and excitedly placed the pile of gems into his storage pouch. He had managed to trade some unusable puppet designs for so many soul stones. It was only natural for him to feel satisfied. With these soul stones, he will be able complete those half finished puppets. However, the old Daoist was truly shocked to see Han Li take out so many soul stones and couldn’t help but think higher of him.

Unbeknownst to the old Daoist, Han Li’s gloomy expression had completely disappeared when he walked several streets away. Instead, he was holding onto the white jade slip with a strange smile on his face.

While ten thousand year old Ironwood would prove difficult for others to acquire, it would only take Han Li a bit of time. As for the supposedly unknown materials, they seemed to be salvageable from the remains of the puppets he found in Heavenvoid Hall if he remembered correctly.

If luck would have it, he should be able to gather the materials needed to create several high grade puppets. With strength rivalling Nascent Soul cultivators, these puppets would increase his combat power severalfold. His previously obsolete puppet techniques were about to once again become one of his killing moves.

Furthermore, the jade slip also contained several designs for puppets that were equivalent to of Core Formation cultivators. Although they could be considered rare, they were still purchasable with large quantities of spirit stones. These weaker puppets might not pose a threat to Nascent Soul cultivators when in small groups, but if he were to create several hundreds of them they would have the power to force a Nascent Soul cultivator to dodge.

However, these were simply musings. Even the lowest grade puppet designs had a cost equivalent to common magic treasures. Creating several tens of them, not to mention several hundred, was something that Han Li couldn’t afford at the moment.

Refining several hundred of the Thousand Bamboo School’s grade three puppets had nearly bankrupted him. Even after selling off most of his demon beast materials at the time, he was still barely able to afford them. The cost of the Nascent Soul level puppets paled even more in comparison. Han Li wryly smiled at the thought and gained his bearings before heading towards the city’s west gate.

Although the day was already late, it made no difference to him whether or not the sun was shining. As such, he decided that it was still a good time to seek out the owner of the Auric Essence.

...

With the official start of the trade fair, cultivators from various regions of the Heavenly South Continent now crowded the city. On the start of the second day, auction houses began to start accepting bids on various valuables. The rare goods that were displayed attracted the eyes of many wealthy cultivators.

A middle-aged cultivator standing at the very front of the hall wore a wide smile on his face and said, “The chunk of Auric Essence is sold to this Fellow Daoist for seven hundred sixty thousand spirit stones.”

There was an emerald tray sitting on top of a red wood table which had a walnut-sized piece of faint gold ore that appeared entirely unremarkable.

Afterwards, a silver-robed cultivator excitedly walked forward and handed over the spirit stones before acquiring the Auric Essence.

Sitting in the audience, Han Li simply sighed before taking his leave from the auction hall. Although the following items that were to be auctioned were even more precious, he had little desire for them.

On that night, he was able to easily find the owner of the Auric Essence with his spiritual sense. However, the owner would only exchange it for a grade seven demon beast egg or a legendary treasure refinement material named Divine Unity Paste. Possessing neither, Han Li could only depart in disappointment.

But from what was said, Han Li realized that he only possessed enough Auric Essence to temper seven of his swords.

But despite this, Han Li had still participated in the auction for the Auric Essence. But once the price exceeded five hundred thousand spirit stones, Han Li had completely given up. It seemed it would still be quite a while before he could complete the Aureate Sword Formation.

Having left the auction, Han Li went around the city, buying supplementary materials for puppet refinement. After he finished, he headed towards a corner of the city.

He recalled what Marquis Nanlong had previously said. As it was already the fourth day of the trade fair, he curiously headed towards the location mentioned in the jade slip.

After Han Li swept the surroundings with his spiritual sense, he stood in front of a stone building with an ordinary appearance. He approached the door, and it opened before he even knocked on it.

A long-bearded, purple-robed man wearing a jade crown then walked out of the building.

Marquis Nanlong spoke rather enthusiastically, “Fellow Daoist Han, you’ve arrived. Let me introduce you to our associates.”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Barbant

Chapter 686: Secret Meeting

“Thank you for the trouble Marquis. And apologies for the wait!” After a few polite words, Han Li followed Marquis Nanlong inside.

The building’s interior was completely bare, to Han Li’s shock. But after he swept his spiritual sense through the building, he discovered restriction fluctuations throughout.

The Marquis smiled upon sensing Han Li’s actions and said, “This small trick of mine can’t be concealed from Fellow Daoist Han of course. Please follow me.” He then formed an incantation gesture with his hand and flung a golden mist from his sleeve.

With the appearance of the golden mist, the unremarkable interior flickered with white light, revealing a set of dark stone steps.

Marquis Nanlong wordlessly descended down the stairs. Han Li frowned, but he followed him all the same.

The stairs were rather short. After only a moment, they arrived before a small underground hall.

There were a few moonlight stones that were softly illuminating the room.

The hall had eight cultivators. Six of them were sitting and the other two were a man and woman pair standing together.

When Marquis Nanlong and Han Li walked in, all of them simultaneously glanced at them.

“It’s you!” The man that was standing couldn’t help but shout in shock at the sight of Han Li’s appearance.

A bright glint appeared from Han Li’s eyes. His sights fell onto the face of a late Core Formation cultivator. He caught sight of a deeply familiar silver mask. After a moment of shock, Han Li sneered.

That man was the young master of the Ghost Spirit Sect, Wang Chan, who had pursued him in the past [1] . He had the same silver mask, but the youthful rage contained in his eyes was replaced with an varied arrangement of emotions.

“I didn’t expect that I’d see an old friend here. What a surprise!”

“How is this possible? You... You condensed a Nascent Soul?” The Ghost Spirit Sect’s young master voice was hoarser than from his youth, but the terror in his voice was unmistakable.

The black-robed, middle-aged scholar sitting in front of him coldly asked, “What the matter? You recognize this Fellow Daoist?”

“Second Uncle, this person is the Yellow Maple Cultivator surnamed Han. During that year, he...”

The middle-aged scholar revealed a trace of shock, but he frowned and decisively said, “There is no need to speak of it. Fellow Daoist Han is already a Nascent Soul cultivator. He won’t bring himself down to a junior’s level.”

He then gently smiled at Han Li and amiably said, “I am the Ghost Spirit Sect Master Wang Tiangu. My nephew had an overexaggerated opinion of his own abilities in the past and had committed many offenses, but I hope Fellow Daoist Han will overlook these matters for my sake.”

“Those matters with Fellow Daoist Wang is merely a matter of the past. With so many years gone by, how could I still bear a grudge? Your esteemed self need not worry!”

Han Li glanced at the black-robed man and smiled as if he truly planned to let bygones be bygones. However, Han Li inwardly sneered. The Ghost Spirit Sect’s young master had nearly taken his life two times, forcing him to take the risk of leaving the Heavenly South. How could such hatred be easily resolved?

Were it not for the many Nascent Soul cultivators present, and the Ghost Spirit Sect Master in particular, he would’ve immediately taken Wang Chan’s life. For now, all he could do was examine the others and see whether or not they were Devil Dao cultivators. If he didn’t keep his grudge in check, it was possible that he would be surrounded.

At that moment, Marquis Nanlong took the opportunity to cut in, “Hehe, so it turned out that Fellow Daoist was from Yellow Maple Valley. I originally believed you came from the Drifting Cloud Sect. However, it is great that Fellow Daoist was able to let go of this old enmity. After all, I’m sure that everyone I’ve invited doesn’t wish to see such an unhappy affair occur.”

Wang Tiangu smiled, but as one of shrewd mind, he wasn’t about to easily believe Han Li’s words. He then nodded and said, “Fellow Daoist’s open heart has truly earned my admiration. Be completely at ease Fellow Daoist Han. When I return I will most certainly punish my nephew. But for Fellow Daoist Han to have climbed from Foundation Establishment stage to Nascent Soul stage in a mere two hundred years, that is quite unbelievable. Perhaps in a few more hundred years, it may be possible for Fellow Daoist to reach late Nascent Soul stage. As the rest of our aptitudes are poor, it is a rather unattainable goal.”

Once that was said, all of the other cultivators present had vastly changed expressions.

Han Li inwardly cursed and felt bone aching hatred towards the Ghost Spirit Sect Master. This clear word of praise intended to mark a target on him.

After a long moment of silence, a tan man asked with an odd tone, “Fellow Daoist hasn’t yet reached three hundred years of age?”

“Sect Master Wang must be joking. I’ve only recently entered Nascent Soul stage. How could I dare to have high hopes of achieving late Nascent Soul stage? It would take countless years.” Han Li casually touched on the matter before sweeping his gaze past everyone in the room.

At that moment, he discovered that there was an amazingly beautiful late Core Formation woman standing at Wang Chan’s side. She was also standing behind Wang Tiangu.

The woman’s calm appearance suggested that she was an exceptional character. He had heard the the top clan in the State of Yue, the Yan Clan, had secretly left the country to immediately join the Ghost Spirit Sect. Additionally, this woman Yan Ruyan had married Wang Chan and possessed Heavenly Spirit Roots. Han Li couldn’t help but suspect this woman was her.

As for the six that were seated, they were all Nascent Soul cultivators. The only one that was a mid Nascent Soul stage cultivator apart from the Marquis was a white-clothed beardless old man.

After taking several more glances at those present, Han Li’s gaze met the old man’s and he

immediately shivered. His gaze contained a penetrating and chilling cold. However, Han Li had casually turned his head and avoided his gaze.

When the old man saw this, he faintly smiled.

At that moment, Marquis Nanlong called out for Han Li to sit down. Without any hesitation, Han Li found an empty seat and sat down with undue deliberation. Afterwards, he glanced at Wang Chan with a mysterious gaze.

Although the young master of the Ghost Spirit Sect was full of terror, he managed to keep a calm exterior in the presence of Wang Tiangu. Regardless, he still felt immense trepidation at what Han Li’s eyes seemed to suggest.

In the past, their cultivation were a match, but his current jump to Nascent Soul stage was much cause of resentment and alarm. As of Yan Ruyan, she glanced at Han Li with bright eyes. It was unknown what she was thinking.

Once Han Li saw this, he sneered before paying them no further heed.

As the group’s leader, Marquis Nanlong stood at their center and spoke with a deep tone, “There are Fellow Daoists that are from the Righteous Dao, Devilish Dao, and there are even a few vagrant cultivators among you. However, you are all similar in which your spiritual senses are exceptionally vast. It is for that reason that I’ve asked all you Fellow Daoists to come here today.

A portion of you should already have a general idea of the matter, but a majority should be ignorant of the matter. I will be giving a thorough briefing on the matter before everyone can decide to participate in the matter. If you are unwilling, I will not force you.”

When Han Li heard this, his spirits were roused. The heart of the matter has finally arrived.

A stern-faced cultivator sitting across from the black-robed man suddenly said, “Hehe! I don’t care about the others, but why are those two Ghost Spirit Sect Juniors here? Don’t tell me that their spiritual senses are a match with ours.” At that same moment, he gave a hostile glance at Wang Tiangu as if they were enemies.

The Marquis predicted this would happen and spoke as if he already had an answer, “Fellow Daoist Long, you will have to overlook it. Although their cultivation isn’t very high, they are proficient in secret techniques. When they later join their spiritual senses with ours, they will provide a significant boost. You should know that it is difficult to find cultivators with spiritual senses as powerful as ours, regardless of how their spiritual sense became so strong.”

The stern-faced cultivator expressionlessly replied, “Since that’s the case, pretend I never said anything!”

The other cultivators had no complaints and glanced at Marquis Nanlong, waiting for him to start.

Marquis slowly swept his eyes past everyone present and slowly said, “The reason I’ve gathered everyone here is for the purpose of traveling to the Moulan Plains.”

“The Moulan Plains?” Marquis Nanlong’s words came as a large surprise to most of those present, Han Li included.

[1]. Wang Chan was last seen in Chapter 363: Transfer, and had tormented Han Li several times in the past.

[Back]

Chapter 687: Cang Kun’s Buried Treasure

“Brother Nanlong, did you speak correctly? The Moulan Plains?” The stern-faced cultivator frowned, speaking as if he couldn’t believe what he had heard.

The other cultivators didn’t fare much better. But since all of them were old eccentrics that had faced countless hardships, they were able to preserve their calm in spite of their turbulent emotions as they waited for Marquis Nanlong’s reply.

Marquis Nanlong calmly explained, “Fellow Daoist misunderstands. I didn’t mean that we would head deep into the Moulan Plains, merely fifty kilometers within its borders.”

The stern-face cultivator shook his head as if greatly fearful of the idea, “That is still extremely dangerous. The Moulan Tribes have been honing their strength for many years already, and have become restless. The edge of the Moulan Plains has already become a danger zone. I fear that many Nascent Soul level spell warriors will be gathered there. Although only a few of those spell warriors possessed a magic treasure, their cultivation is still on par with ours. Additionally, their spirit techniques are not only vastly powerful, but they are extremely adaptable as well. If we were discovered, it would be difficult to escape unharmed.”

Marquis Nanlong sullenly said, “Of course I know how difficult they are. In the past, I fought against a Nascent Soul spell warrior for three entire days. Although his cultivation was on par with mine and his magic treasure was greatly inferior, the battle had ended in stalemate.”

“Since that’s the case, there must be an important reason why Fellow Daoist intends to go there. Why else would Brother Nanlong brave such danger?”

“Hehe, Brother Wang truly understands me. Have any of you Fellow Daoists of the name of Master Cang Kun?”

A bright glint flickered form the eyes of the old woman that had yet to speak, “Master Cang Kun! Wasn’t that the mad cultivator that suppressed both the Righteous and Devilish Dao five thousand years ago?”

With an odd expression, the Marquis said with a strange voice, “Lady Tai is correct. It was that madman that wreaked havoc against both the Righteous and Devilish Dao in the past. Although no one had officially conceded this, the daring mad cultivator was definitely the greatest vagrant cultivator during that time. He had profound abilities that swept past many fearsome opponents in the Heavenly South. Even the great elder of the Harmonious Bond Sect and the Righteous Dao Alliance Leader, the number one figures of both sides at the time, didn’t dare to say that they could prevail against the mad cultivator.”

Wang Tiangu asked with an odd expression, “So Fellow Daoist Nanlong means to say that this matter is related to the mad cultivator?”

The Marquis heavily said, “Hehe! It is as Brother Wang says. We will be heading to where Master Cang Kun died. It is a meticulously hidden cave residence.”

The old woman strongly shook her head in disbelief, “Impossible! Wasn’t that madman killed after being surrounded by many of his enemies?”

Marquis Nanlong simply smiled and was give an explanation when the other mid Nascent Soul cultivator, the white-clothed old man, suddenly said, “Master Cang Kun wasn’t killed by the attack. Rather he was forced to self detonate two of his puppet incarnations to create the opportunity to escape. The cultivators who surrounded him were none the wiser and had believed that one of the incarnations was his true body. However, the battle had greatly injured Master Cang Kun’s vitality and it was extremely difficult for him to restore his abilities.

“As a result, he spent several years there in recovery, and his original cave residence disappeared alongside any messages. It was only when Fellow Daoist Nanlong and I recently discovered his place of death that we came across this knowledge from a remnant message. Once Master Cang Kun disappeared, he braved Devilfall Valley and was the very first person to make it out alive.”

The old woman sharply yelled with an expression of excitement, “He returned from Devilfall Valley alive? How is that possible?!”

All of those that heard the story felt their breathes turn cold. For a moment, they were both shocked by this information and were pondering the validity of these claims. For a time, they couldn’t help but glance at each other in dismay.

The tanned cultivator pondered for a moment before asking with a sneer, “Even if this matter was true, what does it have to do with the Moulan Plains? Don’t tell me that Master Cang Kun buried the treasures he acquired from Devilfall Valley inside this hidden cave residence?”

Marquis Nanlong twirled his beard and expressionlessly said, “Fellow Daoist Bing’s words are mostly correct. According to what was left behind at Master Qian Kun’s place of death, he stayed at Devilfall Valley for several years, but not long after, he met death in meditation. He possibly relapsed from his old injuries or acquired new injuries from Devilfall Valley, but either way, he should’ve brought many treasures out from Devilfall Valley. Treasures that caught the fancy of the greatest vagrant cultivator of that era is no small matter. Furthermore, from his capabilities to suppress crowds of cultivators as a vagrant cultivator, he must’ve possessed extraordinary secret arts and magic treasures. Are you still be unwilling to head into the Moulan Plains?”

The white-clothed old man calmly added, “As a group of many Nascent Soul cultivators, common spell warriors will not be able to block us. Moreover, if the worst occurs, we will simply break through their enclosures separately. If you are unwilling to risk this amount of danger, please do not force yourselves to join. We will find others to go instead.”

Once that was said, the other cultivators began to wear expressions of hesitations. Han Li suddenly said, “There is something that puzzles me. Since you two know where the treasure is, why have you sought us out in particular, those with particularly strong spiritual senses? Could it be related to how well hidden the cave residence is?”

Marquis Nanlong revealed a helpless expression and said, “I was just about to explain that in a moment. If we could acquire the treasure by ourselves, we’d be able to monopolize the treasure. However, we were able to find the cave residence after much searching when the two of us snuck off to the Moulan Plains. Unfortunately, the cave residence is surrounded by a marvelous ancient spell formation. Despite our best efforts we were unable to break through it. Of course, we didn’t dare to linger too long as we were still in the Moulan Plains. We committed the spell formation’s characteristics to memory and returned to the Heavenly South. After searching through various records on spell formations, we eventually discovered the ancient spell formation was the ‘Wondrous Soul Restriction’ which was thought to be lost with time.”

Wang Tiangu revealed amazement, “Wondrous Soul Restriction! Is that not one of the ten great ancient restrictions? How could it be there?”

A majority of cultivators hadn’t heard of the spell formation before, but their hearts trembled upon hearing the Ghost Spirit Sect Master. Anything from the ten great ancient restrictions would absolutely be difficult to dissolve.

A trace of astonishment flickered from Han Li’s eyes, but it soon disappeared.

The Marquis was somewhat surprised that Wang Tiangu knew of this. After exchanging a glance with the white-clothed old man, he smiled and offered a word of praise, “I had already heard of Brother Wang’s grand reputation as a master of formation spells. To know of such an obscure ancient formation, I see that his reputation was well deserved.”

Wang Tiangu seemed to realize something and politely declined to speak, “Brother Nanlong, please continue. I’ve only heard of its name and know nothing of how to dissolve it. The matter is completely unfamiliar to me.”

When the white-clothed old man saw this, he gave a rare smile and he directly said, “We spent several years after our discovery researching the method of breaking through the restriction. We either had to whittle it away with brute force or find eight cultivators with powerful spiritual sense capable of manifested spiritual sense to dissolve the restriction.

Forcefully breaking through the restriction definitely wouldn’t do. Ancient restrictions were extraordinarily profound. Even if we were to violently attack the formation without end for several months, it may not be enough to break it. Of course, there would be no way we would so boldly display such actions inside the Moulan Plains! If we were to dissolve it with manifested spiritual sense, it would only take a day to breakthrough so long as all of your abilities are sufficiently powerful.”

The cultivators in the hall now understood why they were all called together.

Perhaps other mid Nascent Soul cultivators would possess stronger spiritual sense and be more suitable for breaking the restrictions, but the two clearly didn’t wish for other powerful cultivators to join them in fear that they would be betrayed. After all, while two mid Nascent Soul cultivators might not be able to win against the early Nascent Soul cultivators, they would be able to force a stalemate, if just barely.

Regardless, all of the cultivators present in the hall each felt rather excited at the thoughts of treasures from Devilfall Valley.

Although it would be dangerous to enter the edge of the Moulan Plains, the danger was insignificant in comparison to what there was to be gained. This was an opportunity that was seldom seen but often sought.

Marquis Nanlong confirmed their participation and revealed a genuine smile upon seeing that no one had backed down.

“There is still something I must make clear to you all. If we are successful and are able to truly enter the cave residence, Brother Yun and I will have first pick. Then we will split the remaining treasures evenly. Any objections?”

Chapter 690: Grand Sage

The other cultivators remained calm after hearing this. Each of them realized that spell restrictions were used to trap them because the enemy lacked the forces to engage them. However, they couldn’t remained trapped for too long, else the Moulan’s reinforcements would arrive.

The Nascent Soul cultivators each began to flicker with light, making full use of their abilities as they began to strike the restrictions surrounding them. As Han Li remained in the air, he waved his arm in passing, releasing three streaks of azure light from his hand. An instant later, the three streaks of azure light flew off into the distant winds of sand.

Rippling fluctuations began to appear under their strikes. In a flicker of yellow light, the restrictions began to tear as if they were made of thin paper.

The others were shocked at how easy this was. When Han Li saw this, his expression greatly changed and he hurriedly flew forward through the gap that opened. It was quite ordinary for a hastily placed restriction to be easily struck down. There was no need for hesitation.

Han Li’s blunt and sudden actions had shocked the others. But they immediately understood and closely followed after him.

Once they escaped, they still found themselves in winds filled with sand, but the stifling sensation of the restriction could no longer be felt. Han Li felt some relief from this and swept his spiritual sense around, wishing to regain his bearings before taking further action.

But at that moment, Han Li’s expression stirred and his eyes narrowed. As he motionlessly floated in the air, he stared off into a certain direction of the sand. His eyes pulsed with faint blue light in a demonic display. A moment later, his expression returned to normal.

As Marquis Nanlong caught up to Han Li, he noticed that Han Li was motionless. He bewilderedly swept his spiritual sense in the direction that Han Li was looking, and he discovered nothing strange. He bafflingly asked, “Fellow Daoist Han, what are you doing?”

Han Li turned his head towards the Marquis and calmly said, “Nothing, I was only pondering. Which direction should we go?”

“It is hard to make use of our spiritual sense in this cursed sandstorm, and the naked eye is hardly any better for making a decision. But just as it so happenes, I have a star alignment treasure that is suitable for the situation.” Initially scoffing at being asked, Marquis Nanlong reached to his waist and took out a faint red jade disk.

With the one hand holding at the jade disk, he formed an incantation gesture with the other. After muttering a cryptic incantation, he opened the hand with the incantation gesture and a golden light shot out from his palm, striking one of the talisman characters on the disk. The disk then began to shine with a strange red-gold light.

Han Li’s heart stirred and he took another glance at the magic treasure. There was marvelous designs made of golden starlight that shined from the plate that seemed to signify stars, the sun and moon, as well as other astrological symbols.

Han Li was entranced by the sight of it. The others also crowded around with curious expressions.

Marquis Nanlong wasn’t bothered by this and merely concentrated on the patterns shining on the jade disk. A short moment later, he put away the treasure with a flip of his hand and briefly said, “Follow me!” He then enveloped himself in a ball of golden light and shot off.

The rest of the party wordlessly followed after him. They were clearly confident in the Marquis’ judgement.

In a flash of black light, Wang Tiangu enveloped Wang Chan and Yan Ruyan and brought them along. However, when he passed by Han Li, the Ghost Spirit Sect elder seemed to faintly glance at him before calmly brushing past him.

Han Li returned the glance with a mysterious smile. He faintly saw that Wang Chan had lowered his head and didn’t dare to look in his direction in a rather meek fashion. On the contrary, the beautiful Yan Ruyan calmly turned her gaze towards Han Li for a short while with bright eyes before turning away.

Han Li soon found himself at the rear of the group. But with a careless smile, his body flashed with azure light as if about to set flight. But before that, he unconsciously turned his gaze to where he glanced previously and wore an odd expression. He then coldly chuckled and flew off.

In that instant, Han Li’s figure disappeared into the sandstorm.

A short moment after Han Li disappeared, a flash of blinding yellow light shined from where he had been looking at. A huge dark hole that suddenly appeared from the ground where a huge shiny black insect had crawled out of.

This demon insect was astonishingly large and was about twenty meters long and twelve meters wide. Its body was in the shape of a disk. But what was most frightening about it was the dozens of dark yellow compound eyes spread on its head. There were also several slender horns on its head along with a pair of massive, incisive fangs that coldly glinted. There were also four transparent wings on its back that were gently fluttering.

Standing on top of this dreadful demon insect were three silhouettes of varying heights. One of them shined with blinding white light and another was enveloped in a strange dark green mist, obscuring his true form. As for the last figure, their body flickered with faint blue lightning as if they were a materialized god of lightning.

“Grand Sage, are we just going to allow them to leave? Is this not bad?” The silhouette covered in white light glanced in the direction that Han Li’s party disappeared in. His words carried a faint trace of worry.

The green mist figure coldly snorted and icily said, “How could an illusion formation possibly constrain them? Don’t forget that they are mostly Nascent Soul stage cultivators, characters at the same grade as us. Even the weakest two are still late Core Formation cultivators. It is delusional to think that our Yellow Sand Tribe could hope to restrain them.” His temperament seemed harsh.

“But how will we deal with the Heavenly Wind Tribe’s Sage Mu? He was the one who personally sent a message to have use block the group of cultivators to our greatest ability. The vanguard is under his tribe’s command for the time being. He should’ve already sent orders to gather the Grand Sages from the other tribes. Would it be better for us to unleash our tribe’s holy protection artifact, the Devilearth Banner? Even if we can’t cause the Nascent Soul cultivators much harm, it should be possible to trap them for the time being.” The white light silhouette raised the proposal with an anxious tone.

The green mist figure grew furious and bluntly rebuked, “Nonsense! How can we so casually use the thirty six Devilearth Banners? The ancestors of our Yellow Sand Tribe have always instructed us to never use the sacred banner unless our tribe is on the verge of extermination. And even if these cultivators were trapped for a time, given their abilities, they would certainly destroy a few of the banners. How would we respond then? Without the sacred tribe protecting artifacts, how could we steadily maintain our position in the ten great tribes? There may be even a few smaller tribes that may pry into the matter and exterminate us.”

“I was careless! Many thanks for Grand Sage’s reminder.” The spell warrior within the white light hastily apologized for his offence.

“Since you’ve only recently become a Sage, this fault will be forgiven just this once! In any case, it’s not as if we did nothing. They were simply too powerful and we were incapable of restraining them. Grand Sage Mu sure had a good idea to send our Yellow Sand Tribe to tie the intruders down. Once both sides suffered, he’d conveniently arrive to finish them off and take the lion’s share of the credit and loot. On the other hand, if we don’t take out our tribe protecting artifacts to block them, we will be seen as harboring malicious intentions, leaving an opportunity for them to enact reprisals!” The Grand Sage in the green mist coldly spoke as if he had an extremely poor opinion of the Sage Mu.

The Moulan spell warrior shrouded in lightning calmly said, “I fear this is how Sage Mu intends to act. After all, our two tribes never did have a good relationship. However, we are now allied armies and aren’t truly subordinate to them. Our loss of strength isn’t truly something they will take to heart. Moreover, the Heavenly Wind Tribe’s Wind Riding Chariot is extremely fast. It should be able to overtake the intruders. Hehe, it will be hard to say who will end up victorious! But so long as they managed to buy enough time for the main force to arrive, the Heavenly Wind Tribe will be the victors.”

The Grand Sage in the green mist disagreed, “Although the Wind Riding Chariot is extremely fast, by the time enough people are gathered together to use it, it will perhaps be too late.”

After a moment of thought, the Grand Sage muttered, “Whether or not those cultivators are caught is no concern of ours. But I am puzzled about the youth that managed to first breakthrough the formation. It seemed he discovered where our concealed hole was. How baffling. The Xumi Insect is an exotic insect from antiquity, and although its combat power isn’t great, it has the innate ability to temporarily tear a crevice in space. It in an expert in concealment. Although it is still immature and the amount of time it can maintain a spatial tear is limited, it was still enough to prevent the two mid Nascent Soul cultivators from discovering us. But unexpectedly, it wasn’t enough to prevent this particular early Nascent Soul cultivator from discovering us. It seems that youth is an exceptional character. If it isn’t due to a particular secret technique, then it must be from an exceptionally powerful probing treasure.” A trace of bewilderment could be heard from the Grand Sage’s voice.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 691: Wind Riding Chariot

Han Li followed after Marquis Nanlong and company, flying through the sandstorm for tens of kilometers. During this time, not one spell warrior had appeared before them. It was clear that a warning was given. Han Li then recalled what he had unintentionally discovered when he broke through the restriction.

It had been quite the coincidence. Because he was incapable of using his spiritual sense to see through the sandstorm, his only option was to channel spiritual power through his eyes and use the ability granted by the Brightsight Water. Since he had already used the Brightsight Spirit Water several times to cleanse his eyes, he may as well use this opportunity to test if it had any effect.

The results had greatly surprised him. His spirit sight was able to clearly see through the dense sandstorm, much to his delight. However, he was also astonished to see a circular shadow within the sandstorm that was forty meters away.

In his shock, the spiritual power faded away from his eyes and the shadow could no longer be seen. His naked eyes could now only see the sandstorm.

He channeled his spirit sight once more and the shadow appeared once more in its original position. But this time, Han Li channeled even more spiritual power into his eyes. He was able to see the shadow slightly more distinctly and he could see silhouettes faintly swaying inside.

Even after pouring in additional spiritual power, this was the limit of what he could see. But still, it was enough for him to clearly see through their nearby concealment. Although he didn’t know what amazing ability was being used, only spell warriors would be capable of concealing themselves from Nascent Soul warriors in these parts.

It seemed the enemy also knew that their party was quite powerful and didn’t wish to fight to the bitter end, instead opting to keep watch on them. As such, Han Li didn’t reveal their location and left in feigned ignorance. Since these people weren’t brave to begin with, they wouldn’t obstruct him later on.

Once Han Li’s party left the yellow sandstorm, they immediately flew off in bursts of light and tore through the skies at their top speed. Although they had managed to shake off the spell warrior vanguard, their main force would soon be arriving. If they didn’t make it out of the sandy wasteland, their lives would be put at risk.

Not only would there be high grade cultivators from the main army to match them, but there would also be countless spell warriors wearing them down. Therefore, Marquis Nanlong and the others were all wordlessly flying as quickly as possible.

With their deep cultivation and fantastical speed, they were able to spot a faint trace of green off the horizon in less than half a day of flight. They had finally reached the edge of the Moulan Plains.

Marquis Nanlong let out a long sigh and smiled, “Good. We can finally relax. We’ve managed to make it through without any mishap.”

He slowed his speed. After such a long period of prolonged high-speed flight, they had consumed large quantities of magic power. Even if he could manage to bear through it, the others certainly wouldn’t fare any better.

The tan cultivator sighed with relief, “Yes, since we’ve managed to reach so far without any mishap, they shouldn’t be able to catch us no matter how desperate they may be.”

“Don’t lower your guard! There are formidable characters amongst the spell warriors, who possess unfathomable abilities. We... Yi!” The white-haired old man cut off his own words with a yelp and he suspiciously glanced behind him.

Han Li felt his heart thump. Just as he was about to ask the old man a question, he faintly heard a piercing crack from behind them.

In an instant, the odd sound grew louder, attracting the attention of everyone in the party.

They saw white light flickering on the horizon behind them. There was a small sphere of light that was speeding towards them with unconceivable speed.

The white-clothed old man recognized what it was at a glance and wore an expression of furious alarm. “Not good! That’s the spell warriors’ Wind Riding Chariot. They wouldn’t dare to chase us unless that had a similar number of Nascent Soul grade spell warriors.”

After sweeping his spiritual sense past them, Wang Tiangu gloomily said, “There are five Nascent Soul stage spell warriors sitting inside it. It seems they don’t wish to defeat us, but to tangle us down and stall for reinforcements.”

“We cannot allow them to tie us down. We won’t be able to defeat five spell warriors in a short amount of time. Additionally, they will act together to prevent us from escaping. Scatter and use your own abilities to escape them. Here are some jade slips. Each person will take one and remember the area. In three days time, we will gather there once again.” Once Marquis Nanlong finished speaking, he immediately took out a few identical jade talisman and tossed them to each person. In that moment of delay, the crackling from the distant wind chariot became clearer.

“Fellow Daoists, take care of yourselves. I will see you once more in three days time.” Marquis Nanlong then enveloped his body in golden light and shot off without delay.

The white-clothed old man sullenly transformed into a streak of white light, and flew off in a different direction from the Marquis. As for the others, they received the jade slip and each began to scatter without delaying, making use of their own secret techniques to flee.

The tan cultivator emitted meter tall, yellow flames from his body and directly disappeared into the earth. It seemed he was making use of an earth movement technique.

The old woman’s hand flashed with silver light and she summoned a silver crane hairpin. After breathing out a mist of spiritual Qi onto the treasure, a cloud of white crane feathers began to surround her. In a blur, the old woman unsteadily stood on top of a crane. Then with a long shriek, the white crane took off into the skies with the old woman still on its back.

As for the stern-faced cultivator, his entire body glowed with silver light. He formed an incantation gesture with his hands and merged with an unknown treasure, transforming into a silver flood dragon before disappearing into the clouds.

Wang Tiangu, Wang Chan, and Yan Ruyan used some unknown secret Ghost Spirit Sect technique and flew off together into a broad streak of black light. They traveled at an incredibly fast speed. In only a moment, they already became a black speck in the sky.

Han Li was also quick to act. At nearly the same time he caught the Marquis’ jade slip, his body began to glow with red light. A crimson cloak suddenly appeared on his body.

After identifying his direction, he began to pour great amounts of spiritual power into the cloak. Then with a hum, it burst with crimson light, enveloping Han Li in a ball of light and launching him through the air. Travelling at the speed that rivalled the others, he still had the leisure to turn his head and glanced at the Wind Riding Chariot behind them.

Although there was still quite some distance between them, Han Li was able to clearly see it with his immense spiritual sense.

The chariot appeared truly strange. It was a completely white chariot, but there was nothing that was pulling it. In place of its wheels, it had a pair of twenty meter long dark-red wooden wings. There were talisman characters floating on it and it glowed with a rainbow light. After examining it for a moment, he shockingly discovered that the exquisite white body of the chariot was made from the bones of an unknown beast. It carried a faintly vicious aura.

Due to the obstruction of the white light, Han Li could only vaguely make out the people sitting inside. And since he had never fought with a spell warrior before, Han Li wasn’t about to rashly probe the Wind Riding Chariot. Instead, he turned his head forward and focused on controlling the crimson cape, flying directly towards the south of the Moulan Plains.

A short moment later, Han Li and the rest of the party were over five kilometers separated from one another. When the Wind Riding Chariot arrived where the party had split up, Han Li couldn’t help but take another look at it.

The Wind Riding Chariot had stopped for the moment. In a flicker of white light, four different silhouettes left the chariot, three men and one woman. These four spell warriors gathered together and had a quick discussion before chasing four different Nascent Soul cultivators. Fortunately, none traveled in Han Li’s direction.

Han Li grew relieved at the sight, but he then inwardly shouted, “Not good!”

At that same moment, the Wind Riding Chariot wildly pulsed with white light and fiercely shot in Han Li’s direction, releasing sharp cracks that seemed to bore into the mind. As Han Li flew in the crimson light, his expression grew unsightly.

Soon Han Li coldly snorted and his body began to emit blinding light and his speed grew faster. The crimson cloak began to also release low hums.

A white sphere of light began to chase after the red sphere of light in the sky with a distance of five kilometers between the two.

While the Wind Riding Chariot was astonishingly fast, Han Li’s crimson cloak wasn’t something to make light of. Both parties had found themselves at a deadlock for a time.

A short moment later, the two spheres of light disappeared from the edge of the plains as they flew deeper towards the heart of the Moulan Plains.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 694: Frozen Over

With great alarm lingering within, the old man thought to retreat. Han Li on the other hand glanced at the black mountain with a trace of awe.

Such a peculiar and astonishing treasure wasn’t something that this old man was able to refine. It was most likely some ancient treasure that had remained from antiquity. Han Li was certain that this treasure’s might wasn’t something that even a late Nascent Soul cultivator could endure.

So long as the strike landed, it would decide any battle in a single blow. With this item in hand, he would be able to resolve his lacking attack power. Not to mention that he was also interested in the old man’s Wind Riding Chariot.

With that in mind, Han Li’s gaze shifted to the old man and his expression gradually grew hostile. A trace of killing intent could be seen deep within his eyes.

Although he hadn’t fought much with the old man, Han Li was confident that he understood most of his techniques. It seemed to be the old man’s misfortune that he was specialized in ice-attribute techniques.

With the Celestial Ice Flames, they wouldn’t pose much of a threat against Han Li. Despite the vast number of ice crystals that had attacked him, he was able to easily dissolve them with the Celestial Ice Flames.

This teleporting black mountain should be the old man’s most powerful treasure. However, with the instantaneous movements of the Thunderstorm Wings, it was of no use against Han Li. In this case, it should be possible for Han Li to kill the old man.

Having come to a decision, Han Li no longer held any hesitation.

The ice flowers in his grasp trembled and flickered with blue light, quickly transforming into an egg-sized flame. It hovered in his palm and emitted a bizarre aura.

At that same moment, Han Li pointed to the huge sword and the silver bell with his free hand. Soon after, he flapped his wings and disappeared, leaving only thunder in his wake. In the next instant, he reappeared three hundred meters away from the old man, with blue flames in his grasp.

The huge sword and the silver bell flourished with radiance as they shot towards the old man in brilliant streaks of light. Along the way, the huge sword suddenly dissolved into several hundred foot-long swordlights which filled the sky, surrounding the old man within a swarm of swords.

Azure light flickered without end as the swordlight began to fiercely pierce through the old man’s light barrier. The bell unleashed wave after wave of silver soundwaves, shaking the old man’s light barrier upon impact.

Although these attacks greatly alarmed the old man, he still kept a sound mind. In addition to pouring a large quantity of spiritual power into the pearl above him, strengthening the barrier around him, he also quickly formed a hand incantation. Blue light pulsed from his body and shed off from it.

After a quick rotation in the air, the light transformed into four, meter-long ice shields that rotated around him. They were small and exquisitely refined.

The old man felt more at ease with these ice shields protecting him. He immediately beckoned to the black mountain in the distance, and it began to fly back towards him in a streak of black light. As this happened, he continuously glanced around him in fear that Han Li would launch a sudden attack on him. As expected of a Nascent Soul stage spell warrior, he possessed much combat experience.

With another burst of thunder, Han Li appeared about forty meters away from the old man in a flash of lightning. A dense barrage of incisive, azure threads suddenly shot out from his hand - a display of the Nightazure Needles treasure talisman [1] .

At such a short distance, the old man was unable to respond in time. The myriads of azure threads pierced through the blue light barrier and directly struck the ice shields.

Sounds of cracking ice filled the air as the azure threads struck the ice shields. In a brilliant flash of white light, the needles became covered in dense, glistening ice and began to fall to the ground.

When the old man saw this, his alarm turned to joy. With a chuckle, he opened his mouth and shot a beam of blue light directly towards the nearby Han Li. In response, Han Li disappeared from sight in a flash of silver light.

In that moment of delay, the black mountain flew above the old man. Its towering figure made for an astonishing sight.

Without any hesitation, the old man struck the mountain with a spell seal. The mountain then began to tremble and released a large glow of black light from its bottom. With the old man at its center, the mountain enveloped the several hundred azure swordlights and the huge silver bell in its radiance.

These treasures immediately began to swivel and shake in an attempt to break free, but their power was greatly weakened. The swaying light barrier had returned to normal once more.

When the old man saw this, he felt greatly relieved.

Soon after, he flipped his hand. The Wind Riding Chariot reappeared in his palm with a flash of white light. He lightly tossed it into the air, and it began to expand to its original size. A short moment later, it was successfully restored and flew off to the side.

For some unknown reason, the old man felt a sense of dread ever since Han Li transformed the ice flowers in his palm into small blue flames. With the additional appearance of Han Li’s Thunderstorm Wings, he felt that matters had turned for the worse, and decided to flee, rather than continue the fight.

Seeing that the Wind Riding Chariot had been successfully prepared, the old man immediately transformed into a streak of light. Several flashes later, he charged past the obstructed flying swords and towards the Wind Riding Chariot in nearly the blink of an eye.

When the light faded away, the old man was already safely located inside the Wind Riding Chariot. With relief in his heart, he thought to retrieve his pearl and the black mountain, when he suddenly heard thunder at his side.

In flash of light, Han Li suddenly appeared before him.

“Ah!” The old man roared and raised his hand, but it was too late. Han Li’s arm was already shooting towards the old man like a bolt of lightning. The Celestial Ice Flames completely enveloped his hand.

The old man felt his heart sink, but the shields of ice floating around him automatically moved to protect him. In a flash of white light, they appeared in front of the old man just in time.

The old man felt a trace of joy after seeing this. Han Li had attacked his Crystal Ice Shields without any defenses. ‘He was simply courting death! Surely in just a moment, his arm will be frozen through by the frigid Qi.’

With a muffled peng , white and blue light brightly shone.

The old man felt his heart drop at the sudden turn of events. The flame-clad hand was already pressing against his chest. It felt extremely soft to the touch.

Before the old man could even scream, the strange icy flames had quickly spread from Han Li’s grasp, engulfing the old man in a single breath. In a short instant, Han Li saw a majority of the man’s body turn into a statue of ice.

With a fearful expression, the old man hurriedly summoned the core Yang flames that he spent several hundreds of years diligently cultivating. It wound around his neck and released a blinding white light, preventing the ice from spreading to his head. For a moment, the core flames were in a deadlock with the blue ice.

When Han Li saw this, he scoffed. He waved his free hand. A streak of azure sword Qi then appeared in the air and ruthlessly chopped towards the old man’s head. A short moment later, the white light trembled, and the blue frost quickly covered whatever remained of his head.

The severed half of the old man’s face revealed despair, but soon, hostility filled his eyes. A clear sound rang from the top of his head. A Nascent Soul with the old man’s face had manifested.

Han Li’s expression grew sullen and he spat a bolt of lightning towards the Nascent Soul without any reservations.

However, the Nascent Soul immediately disappeared from sight in a pulse of blinding blue light. The bolt of lightning had missed.

When Han Li hurriedly glanced around, he saw that the Nascent Soul was already three hundred meters away. Without any hesitation, it disappeared once more in a flash of blue light.

At that moment, the blue pearl trembled for a moment before disappearing as well. The pearl then reappeared inside the Nascent Soul’s grasp.

The Nascent Soul gazed at Han Li with a resentful expression before silently blurring out of sight. Not long after, it turned into a speck of light that flew towards the horizon. At that distance, it no longer used instant movement and simply tore through the skies, blue pearl in hand. A few seconds later, it could no longer be seen.

Han Li coldly glanced at the departing Nascent Soul and simply grabbed onto the old man’s corpse without moving.

Although his Thunderstorm Wings were also capable of instant movement, the delay between each movement made it so that he was still too slow to catch up to him. Since it escaped his first blow, he allowed it to go free as there was no immediate need to kill it.

At that moment, the old man’s Nascent Soul had already disappeared without a trace. Han Li expressionlessly shook his hand and caused the old man’s frozen corpse to shatter, filling the sky with glossy blue dust.

[1]. Given to him by Layman Qing Yi in Heavenvoid Hall(Chapter 468: Treasure Light Pavilion), this treasure talisman was only used once in his battle with Wen Tianren, the disciple of Archsaint Six Paths (Chapter 572: Bitter Battle).

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 695: Gathering Together

Although he hadn’t dealt with the opponent’s Nascent Soul, the old man’s body was destroyed. It should take decades before he could recover his vitality, let alone possess another body. Finding a suitable body should take quite some time. Even if he begrudgingly possessed an unsuitable corpse, his cultivation would greatly decrease.

As for the two ancient treasures and the storage pouch that were left behind, they were a great profit. Even if he didn’t find Master Cang Kun’s cave residence, this dangerous journey into the Moulan Plains would still turn a profit.

With that thought, he glanced at the faintly silver storage pouch that was left behind from the body.

Han Li calmly reached for the storage pouch and summoned it into his hand. He then immersed his spiritual sense into it and casually probed it, only to be filled with disappointment. Apart from a dozen mid grade spirit stones, there were only a few common tool refinement materials and a few bottles of medicine pills.

When Han Li opened the medicine pills, he found them to be of common quality. It seemed the Moulan Plains were truly lacking cultivation materials. Even a grand Nascent Soul spell warrior lacked decent items.

As for any jade slips, the storage pouch completely lacked them. Han Li was baffled by this and sighed in great disappointment. He originally wished to acquire a few spirit techniques and see if there were any techniques that would greatly increase his strength in a short amount of time. Unfortunately, there was no such luck.

After putting away the storage pouch, Han Li raised his head and glanced at the huge mountain with a fervant gaze. Although the treasure’s master had already fled as a manifested Nascent Soul, the black mountain still remained in its enlarged form, sparkling with black light.

Han Li narrowed his eyes and gently beckoned to the mountain. The masterless ancient treasure flickered with brilliance and quickly shrunk before shooting towards Han Li. By the time it arrived within his grasp, it had already turned back into a miniature mountain.

Han Li curiously weighted the small mountain in his hand. It wasn’t particularly heavy, and he examined it several times through only to find three faint gold character on the bottom of the mountain.

“Thousand Layer Mountain!” Han Li couldn’t help but utter its name. Satisfaction appeared from his eyes.

After putting away the mountain, Han Li glanced at the Wind Riding Chariot and put it away as well.

After glancing in the direction that the old man’s Nascent Soul had fled, Han Li lowered his head in thought before deciding to fly off in a different direction. Not long after, no trace of Han Li could be seen nearby.

...

Among a group of hills, there was no one to be found, only fields filled with straws as tall as men. But not long after, azure light flashed from the horizon.

A short moment later, the azure streak arrived above the hill. It flew around around and faded away to reveal Han Li.

After taking another glance beneath him, he frowned and suddenly flung his sleeve. Several streaks of azure light directly struck the hill like shooting stars.

As a result, the azure light bursted about a hundred meters in the air. A layer of extremely faint white light suddenly appeared in the air. There were four people underneath it that were looking at him, all wearing a faint smile. They were Marquis Nanlong, the white-haired old man, the old man, and the tan-skinned man.

Marquis Nanlong twirled his beard and chuckled, “It is truly fortunate for Han Li to have arrived safely!” He then waved his hand, causing the light barrier to disappear.

“Oh! The others still haven’t arrived?” Han Li replied with a smile and floated down before them.

The tan man shook his head and calmly said, “We fear the other Fellow Daoist may have had trouble fleeing. When we separately fled, Fellow Daoist Long and Fellow Daoist Wang were pursued by spell warriors. It is quite a difficult matter to break away from them.”

Marquis Nanlong excitedly said, “However, I feared for you most. If I saw correctly, that Wind Riding Chariot should’ve chased after you. Tch tch! Fellow Daoist managed to easily shake it off despite its amazing speed. It seems I’ve misjudged you.”

Han Li pursed his lips when he heard the Marquis. He could faintly make out a trace of bewilderment from his words.

Han Li wore a calm expression and casually replied, “It was nothing. I merely hold a bit of confidence in my movement techniques.”

Seeing that Han Li wasn’t eager to explain how he escaped, the Marquis tactfully changed the topic and began to talk about the Nine Nation Union’s upcoming war with the Moulan. It would shake the entire continent as a whole.

Excluding the white-clothed old man, the old woman and the tan man both interestedly included themselves in the conversation.

Marquis Nanlong mysteriously smiled and said, “I recall that the last war with the spell warriors lasted over ten years. Who knows how many years this war will last. However, the Heavenly South’s Devil Dao, Righteous Dao, and even Brother Han’s Heavenly Dao Alliance will have to send soldiers. And given the Drifting Cloud Sect’s position in the Heavenly Dao Alliance, a Nascent Soul elder will be required to participate in the battle. Perhaps Fellow Daoist Han will have another chance to visit the Moulan Plains!”

The old woman nodded her head and softly said, “In addition to the three superpowers sending assistance to the Nine Nations Union, there are also a few vagrant cultivators that volunteer to block the spell warriors with many an expert among them. The Moulan are incredibly difficult to hold off.”

The tan man frowned and mused, “However, I am quite baffled as to why Moulan would launch an attack despite knowing that the powers of our Heavenly South have united against them. From their current forces, they don’t have a chance of winning, considering what had happened in the last war. It isn’t wise for them to take the initiative to attack with just this. In the last war, they redoubled their attack because of an abrupt wave of reinforcements. Could it be that most of their tribes will be participating in this war?”

“That certainly is possible, but...”

As the conversation continued, much time had unknowingly passed by.

Suddenly, Marquis Nanlong suddenly paused in the middle of comment and he turned his head to the sky. The others unconsciously followed his gaze and their faces grew serious. It was possible that a spell warrior would arrive instead of one of their scattered cultivators. They were in the Moulan Plains after all.

They saw a flash of light from the horizon, revealing one black streak and two crimson spheres of light flying towards them. Marquis Nanlong attentively glanced at them for a moment before calming down.

Marquis Nanlong smiled and said, “It’s nothing. Just Fellow Daoist Wang and his two juniors.” When the others heard this, they also appeared happy.

A short moment later, the streaks of light grew closer. This time, Marquis Nanlong directly removed the restrictions, allowing Wang Tiangu and company to land next to the rest of the party.

When Wang Tiangu saw Han Li amongst the party, he revealed a trace of surprise and said, “Yi! Fellow Daoist Han arrived earlier than we did. That is truly surprising!” It seemed he also saw the Wind Riding Chariot pursue Han Li. It was likely he basked in schadenfreude at the time.

Han Li swept his gaze to Wang Chan and Yan Ruyan at his side and calmly replied, “It was merely a fluke! However, Fellow Daoist Wang was able to escape without injuries while looking after two juniors. You truly have my admiration.” His tone seemed to carry a deeper meaning.

Wang Tiangu indifferently replied, “Hehe, the spell warrior pursuing me wasn’t fast in the slightest. My two juniors and I joined hands to employ one of our sect’s movement techniques. We were able to easily shake them off. It isn’t comparable to escaping pursuit from the Wind Riding Chariot.”

Han Li inwardly sneered. Just as he thought to say something further, his expression suddenly changed and he swallowed his words.

Marquis Nanlong raised his head to the sky and yelped with a joyful expression, “Yi! Fellow Daoist Long is coming. It seems our luck is quite good. We can all hurry to our destination unharmed. I was actually pondering whether or not we’d be able to succeed in breaking the formation if we were missing a few members!”

When the party heard this, they all revealed joy. If they were were incapable of acquiring the treasure because of a missing member, it would be a rather depressing matter.

The white-clothed old man suddenly broke his silence and gravely said, “Not good! It seems Fellow Daoist Long is injured and is still being pursued!”

Once the others heard this, Han Li and the others hastily turned their eyes to the sky with shock. They saw that there was actually a green and red streak of light closely pursuing the stern-faced cultivator. In the blink of an eye, they had already arrived at the hill where the party was located.

Marquis Nanlong’s expression quickly turned sullen.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 697: Lightning Fire Spike

As the ground fiercely trembled, a fine crack spread from the top of the mountain down the base of the mountain. White light began to shine from the crack as if the mountain were split into two.

Han Li and company felt their breathes turn cold. Their hearts felt complete awe at the sight of Marquis Nanlong and Fellow Daoist Yun splitting open the mountain. Despite their shock, they still managed to appear calm as they observed what was happening.

The two with the lowest cultivation, Wang Chan and Yan Ruyan, stood behind Wang Tiangu in complete silence.

After Han Li coldly glanced at the two, he turned his sights back on the mountain. It seemed he wouldn’t have an opportunity to slay Wang Chan before they acquired the treasure.

As Marquis Nanlong and the white-clothed old man continued their incantations for a moment more, the mountain eventually split into two, creating a huge crevice that was over thirty meters wide. A limestone stairway laid within.

“Let’s go.” With a trace of excitement on the old man’s face, he led the way. As for the other founder of the party, Marquis Nanlong remained behind with a smile.

Han Li felt his heart stir. It seems that this white-clothed old man was quite the character to have Marquis Nanlong actually guard the rear.

The others saw this and glanced at each other, but they all tactfully kept silent on the matter. Instead, they calmly walked inside.

The stairs lasted for quite a while. White moonstones were embedded in each side, but the further they descended, the colder it became. Not long after, they were already three hundred meters deep into the mountain, and the moonlight stone’s faint white light had soon turned into a faint green for some unknown reason. This caused the descending passage to appear ominous.

When Han Li saw this, he frowned and unconsciously pulled away from the tan cultivator ahead of it. If anything happened, the distance would give him enough time to react. Han Li wasn’t the only one to do this. Apart from Marquis Nanlong and the white-clothed old man, the other cultivators began to keep a distance of about thirty meters from each other.

Marquis Nanlong and the old man surnamed Yun clearly knew that the other cultivators were actually taking precautions against them. However, they deliberately ignored this and continued forward without a trace of dissatisfaction.

After the time it took to finish a meal, Han Li and company had arrived in a large mysterious hall. The reason why it was mysterious was because it appeared as if the entire hall appeared was created from a giant hollowed boulder of jade. Its sparkling and translucent blue light appeared extremely beautiful.

Now that they stood within the hundred meter wide hall, everyone wore a face of amazement. This material obviously couldn’t have been true jade. Once they swept their spiritual sense past the walls, they were promptly repelled. It was incapable of seeing past them.

Han Li wasn’t alarmed by this. He used his spiritual sense to probe the other parts of the hall only to find that they were all the same.

Han Li inwardly pondered with a sense of apprehension and turned his gaze to the other cultivators in the room. Wang Tiangu and the others also frowned. It was clear that they also found this to be troublesome.

Could this be where the Wondrous Soul Restriction was located? It seemed Marquis Nanlong wasn’t exaggerating. Just as Han Li’s mind began to wonder, the entire hall began to violently shake and they heard a series of huge tremors from behind them.

The old woman and the others hastily turned their heads in alarm. They discovered the the stairway had unknowingly disappeared and was replaced with walls of sparkling blue light.

A moment later, the entire hall became deathly quiet.

“Fellow Daoist Nanlong, what is the meaning of this?” The tan cultivator asked with a sullen expression. The other cultivators also became vigilant as they glanced at Marquis Nanlong and the white-clothed old man; their eyes flickering around the room.

Marquis Nanlong didn’t display the slightest surprise and calmly said, “Be at ease, Fellow Daoists! The outside restrictions were merely reactivated, causing the mountain to close once more. The last time we came here, this also happened. We merely had to wait three days until the restrictions’ strength was at its weakest before leaving the mountain. We won’t be trapped here. Moreover, with the outer restrictions shut, we have no fear of spell warriors discovering us.”

While the others were somewhat skeptical of that explanation, they appeared visibly relieved. So long as Marquis Nanlong and the white-clothed old man were in the hall with them, they had no fear of any trap being set or any malicious planning.

The tan cultivator saluted and said, “So it was like that! It seems I was being rash.”

Fellow Daoist Nanlong chuckled and casually said, “It’s nothing! Let’s hurry to break the restriction. Last time, Fellow Daoist Yun and I returned dejected from failure. This Wondrous Soul Formation isn’t easy to break.”

The old woman’s wrinkly face broke into a smile and she said, “Is the formation truly that difficult to break? I’ve acquired a treasure in the past that was specialized in breaking many restrictions and barriers. Perhaps we can save ourselves the trouble and simply use this treasure to break the restriction?”

A trace of joy flickered from the white-clothed old man’s expression and he immediately replied, “Yi? If Lady Tai possesses such an exceptional treasure, please give it a try. Our method of using spiritual sense to dissolve the restriction isn’t guaranteed to be successful.”

Revealing a trace of delight, Marquis Nanlong said, “That’s right. Fellow Daoist Tai, please go ahead.”

The old woman chuckled and a trace of spirit flickered from her dull eyes, “Since you Fellow Daoists have both agreed, I’ll be blunt. If this somehow manages to luckily break the restrictions, will I have first pick alongside you two as well?”

The other cultivators had slightly changed expressions after hearing this.

Marquis Nanlong revealed slight surprise, but after glancing at the white-clothed old man, he suddenly said to the others, “Regardless of whether it be Lady Tai or anyone else, so long as you succeed in breaking the formation, they will have priority selection for a treasure after us two. What does everyone think?” Once that was said, Marquis Nanlong swept his gaze past the party.

Han Li and Wang Tiangu both appeared indifferent to this, but the tan man and the stern-faced cultivator appeared displeased. Regardless, no objections were raised.

Marquis Nanlong smiled and decisively said, “The others have no objections. Lady Tai, you may take action.”

“Since that’s the case, I will be making an attempt.” The old woman was inwardly delighted. She held quite some confidence in her treasure. So long as it wasn’t an intangible formation like an illusion formation, she had a large chance of success. Why else would she take the risk of angering the rest of the party?

Lady Tai flung out her sleeve and took out an object that was only several inches long. This fire-red object was narrow at the front and thick at the back, resembling something like a spike.

The old woman paid no attention to the others and spat a mist of blinding light onto the spike. A short moment later, the spike flickered with red light and began to emit waves of heat that quickly spread throughout the hall.

As experienced as they were, the Marquis and the white-clothed old man immediately knew that this object was unordinary and unconsciously took a few steps away from the woman as they glanced at her spike.

Wang Chan and Yan Ruyan revealed shock upon contacting the heat wave and hastily enveloped themselves in a crimson barrier. They felt their bodies scorch. As late Core Formation cultivators, they were unable to endure such temperatures.

With a flash of white light, the spike began to crackle.

Han Li and the others began to keenly gaze at the spike, discovering that the spike’s flames faintly pulsed with white lightning.

This was an ancient treasure with the dual attributes of lightning and fire! The cultivators looked upon the old woman with varied emotions.

The woman ignored this and deeply glanced at the blue wall in front of her. Her wrist shook and she thrust the Lightning Fire Spike into it. Fiery light flourished and muffled booms sounded out. The spike began to swiftly revolve above her head and soon its speed increased to the point where it became a blur.

The faint red-white blur quickly flew throughout the hall, barely able to be seen. The cultivators in the hall all watched with amazement.

Han Li was particularly alarmed at the sight. This was the first time he had seen such a swift ancient treasure. Even Nascent Soul cultivators would find it difficult to defend against it. If he were to fight against such a treasure, he would have no way of dealing with it apart from the Thunderstorm Wings.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Warning, I am jetlagged from the WW Retreat. I will also spend most of the next day on a plane.

Chapter 703: The First to Act

The meager wisp of blue flame was able to pass through the light barrier unobstructed, much to the surprise of the stern-faced cultivator. Lacking any time to dodge, the wisp of flame struck his neck. With a crackle, the stern-faced cultivator was entirely consumed by blue ice, forming a glistening ice sculpture.

Much to the stern-faced cultivator’s misfortune, Han Li had particularly directed the Celestial Ice Flames to strike at his neck as a result of his experience from fighting the spell warrior. With his head frozen over, he had no opportunity to cast any techniques and change the outcome.

In the same moment Han Li turned the stern-faced man into an ice sculpture, the blue lightning from the gourd struck Han Li before its thunder could sound out. But before it could strike Han Li’s body, a net of faint gold lightning suddenly appeared on Han Li’s body. In a flicker of golden light, the blue lightning was absorbed and disappeared from sight.

Han Li then hesitantly reached forward and quickly snatched away the blue gourd.

Han Li’s use of the thunderstorm wings, the icing of the stern-faced cultivator surnamed Long, and the acquisition of the treasure took place in a mere instant. Just as Wang Chan had thought to step forward and assist the stern-faced cultivator, he witnessed his instantaneous defeat. Wang Chan could hardly believe what he just saw.

When Han Li coldly glanced in his direction, Wang Chan responded without a thought. With fear in his voice, he yelled, “Cast together! Use the Blood Spirit Arts to restrain him!” Once that was said, he grabbed onto Yan Ruyan’s hand and hurriedly uttered an incantation. Crimson mist suddenly spread through the air.

Yan Ruyan didn’t resist, merely displaying a trace of disgust deep within her eyes. After a moment of hesitation, she followed suit and uttered an incantation. The blood mist from both of their bodies combined as one and condensed into a mist of violet blood light.

After Wang Chan and Yan Ruyan disappeared into the violet mist, it began to release ghostly howls as if monsters truly laid within.

When Han Li saw this, he faintly smirked.

Marquis Nanlong suddenly sent Han Li a voice transmission, “Good! I didn’t expect for Fellow Daoist Han to possess such heaven-defying abilities. If we join hands, we may be able to match them.”

When Han Li heard this, he swept his gaze to the other side.

Marquis Nanlong and the others had yet to fight, but the others were staring at him with absolute shock. Marquis Nanlong appeared delighted by Han Li’s recent display and his hopes of escaping grew stronger.

Marquis Nanlong immediately said, “So long as you join hands with me, I am willing to give you another jade box!”

‘Join hands? Haha...’ Han Li coldly laughed and said nothing. He carried no such desire.

He clearly understood that he was able to easily dispatch of the stern-faced cultivator because he was unaware of the deadly Celestial Ice Flames. Else, the battle would’ve taken far longer, even if he ended up victorious.

There were still three early and one mid Nascent Soul cultivators on the opposing side. If Marquis Nanlong was uninjured, they might’ve stood a chance, but as gravely wounded as he was now, Han Li would only be dragged down alongside him. Regardless of whatever it may contain, the jade box’s contents wasn’t worth his life.

Before he fled, he needed to have them start fighting and have their focus be on the Marquis. Otherwise, their attentions would be focused on him, and it would be difficult for him to escape. With that thought, Han Li paid them no further heed and flapped his wings, leaving only thunder behind.

When the white-clothed old man saw this, he immediately shouted, “Not good! He’s about to run! Block him! Don’t let him escape with the jade box!”

With the scene of Han Li instantly killing a similar grade cultivator still fresh in their minds, the old woman and the tan man ignored his words entirely. Even Wang Tiangu appeared hesitant. He couldn’t decide whether to take action.

After all, if Han Li truly left, they would be able to deal with the Marquis with complete certainty. The two jade boxes may as well be theirs. But if they were to forcefully detain Han Li, with his strange abilities, even the mid Nascent Soul old man might not be able to prevail over him. It was far too risky.

However, the jade box in Han Li’s grasp might contain the secrets of Devilfall Valley that they all so deeply desired. As shrewd and cunning as Wang Tiangu was, he found himself wavering between two extremely difficult choices.

When the white-clothed old man saw their hesitation, he understood them perfectly. He also felt some fear towards Han Li’s Celestial Ice Flames. Moreover, if he were to leave this place to deal with Han Li, the Marquis may escape. Although Marquis Nanlong’s injuries were severe, three early Nascent Soul cultivators didn’t have much hope of remaining steadfast against his formidable secret techniques.

He also found himself hesitant as to what to do.

In a flash of lightning, Han Li appeared at the top of the stairs. He strangely smiled at Wang Tiangu and company before pointing to the black mountain. The black mountain trembled and disappeared in an instant, only to appear above them and dropping down with all its might.

None had expected that Han Li would launch such a sudden attack, to their fury.

However, even the white-clothed old man didn’t dare to take on the mountain’s might alone. They could only helplessly dodge out of the way as the mountain fell down.

This was finally the moment Marquis Nanlong chose to strike. His eyes brightened and he transformed into a blinding streak of golden light, charging directly towards the old woman. In her fright, the old woman’s body flashed with yellow light, summoning a small yellow shield to block the Marquis’ approach. In an instant, gold and yellow light intertwined, but eventually the golden light engulfed the old woman.

When the others saw this, they instantly struck without any further thought and attempted to restrain the Marquis.

But through some unknown secret technique, the golden light on his body became increasingly dense. At that same moment, he released several powerful ancient treasures to enter the fray. He didn’t appear to be at the slightest disadvantage in this chaotic battle.

The others were completely occupied in their alarm and couldn’t pay any attention to Han Li’s actions.

When Han Li saw this, he was satisfied and pointed once more to the black mountain. It shrunk to several inches in a gust of wind and shot back into his hand. He then turned his gaze towards the violet blood mist with a stern expression on his face.

With pupils glowing with blue light, Han Li gazed at a certain portion of the mist. He raised his hand without any hesitation and black light began to surge through it. A dense mass of black-red light shot out from his palm towards the mist, discharging the Yin Devil Execution.

A wretched scream came from the blood mist, but Han Li had already disappeared with a flash of lightning.

Even if Wang Chan somehow managed to survive the strike, his injuries would be grave. While he did wish to take advantage of this opportunity to ensure Wang Chan’s death, he was certain that Wang Tiangu would come to Wang Chan’s aid. When that moment came, he would be tied down in a battle against Wang Tiangu, attracting much danger onto himself.

In any case, Han Li would always have the ability to kill a trifling late Core Formation cultivator like Wang Chang, so he had no need to risk his safety now. As such, he immediately fled after making his attack.

Han Li’s figure appeared at the exit of the building in a blur, and he flew straight towards the hall’s entrance. Along the way, a white streak of light flew into Han Li’s sleeve from the corner of the hall. It appeared to be a small white fox.

“Master, I — ” Silvermoon spoke with an excited tone.

Han Li flew straight out the hall and gloomily interrupted, “Now is not the time to talk. Leave it for when we’re out of danger.”

When Han Li broke through the Wondrous Soul Restriction, he deliberately used a flash of dazzling light to hide a gap in the restriction that he created. In that instant, he had Silvermoon go through. Afterwards, he deliberately stalled for time as he dissolved the formation. It was for this reason that Han Li had taken such efforts to break through the Wondrous Soul restriction, not on the mere basis of priority selection.

From how excited Silvermoon appeared, it seemed she had reaped quite a bit of profit from the pavilion.

Having taken the initiative to seize the treasures, Han Li had refused Marquis Nanlong’s proposal to fight together and simply chose to prioritize his own escape.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare & V-anon

Chapters may have delays over the next three days. Apologies in advance.

Chapter 709: Lei Wanhe’s Shock

“Senior!” Han Li stroked his chin and wore an odd expression on his face.

The fat old man was the “Senior Martial Uncle Lei” who had exchanged medicinal herbs for pill formulas. Although he was merely observing the common customs of the cultivation world, Han Li couldn’t help but find this action odd.

As for the gorgeous woman named Nie Yan, he had only met her once as “Senior Martial Sister Nie” before when she had protected the Murong Brothers from “Senior Martial Brother Lu” back during his time at Yellow Maple Valley [1] . Although Han Li didn’t have much of a relationship with her, he had heard much of her aptitude and her beauty both external and within. Back in the past, there had been countless male disciples that had admired her. He didn’t expect that after so many years, she would form a golden core.

Han Li remained silent and examined both Lei Wanhe and Nie Yan with a complicated expression. As this occurred, Lei Wanhe felt puzzled.

Not only did this “Senior” appear excessively young, for some unknown reason, Lei Wanhe found his face somewhat familiar as if he had saw him before. This had come as a shock to him and he began to feel apprehensive.

As Nie Yan looked at Han Li, bewilderment suddenly appeared from deep within her eyes.

Han Li was disinclined from wasting any more time with this silent display and eventually said, “It seems Martial Uncle Lei truly doesn’t remember me. However, the pill formulas Martial Uncle gave to me during that year had been of great help to me.”

When Lei Wanhe heard Han Li call him Martial Uncle, his jaw dropped and found himself at a loss for words. But after he heard him mention pill formulas, he suddenly recalled something and began to astonishedly stutter, “Martial Uncle? Pill formulas! You... You’re...” [2]

When the others heard this, they were also dumbstruck. This Nascent Soul Senior had actually called Lei Wanhe “Martial Uncle”. This had truly sent their minds spiralling into confusion.

But when Nie Yan heard him, she amazedly examined Han Li once more before saying, “You’re Martial Uncle Li’s disciple, Han Li... Junior Martial Brother Han?” The woman’s voice was filled with disbelief.

Han Li felt genuine surprise, “I didn’t expect that Fellow Daoist Nie would remember me.”

While Han Li was unknown during Qi Condensation stage due to his low profile and meager cultivation, truly few knew of him. But ever since he survived the [trial by blood and fire] and successfully became Li Huayuan’s disciple after entering Foundation Establishment, many shrewd individuals had taken notice of him. This “Senior Martial Sister Nie” was one of them.

Once the Six Devilish Dao Sects invaded the State of Yue, his reputation surged throughout lower grade disciples from his achievements in killing so many similar grade Devil Dao cultivators. Although she hadn’t seen his face since then, he had left a deep impression on her. With Han Li’s appearance exactly the same as before, she recalled the famous Junior martial brother Han from the past and unconsciously shouted out his name in shock.

“You truly are Martial Nephew Han!” Lei Wanhe felt his throat turn dry and his mind grew blank.

It was said that any strange events could happen in the cultivation world. Outstanding disciples rising to the same status as a senior was a common occurrence, but for a Foundation Establishment Junior to suddenly reappear at Nascent Soul stage was something that brought an individual as experienced as Lei Wanhe into a stupor.

Han Li glanced around and calmly said, “Martial Uncle Lei, there is no need to be so surprised. However, this isn’t the place to talk. Let’s have a chat as we travel instead.”

Lei Wanhe’s expression wavered several times before bitterly chuckling, “I don’t dare to accept the title as Martial Uncle. Since Senior Han has already entered Nascent Soul sage, I am your Junior.” His words still preserved the same respect from the very start.

Regardless of Han Li’s identity in the past, his current cultivation was far beyond his own. He didn’t dare to be addressed with such an inappropriate title.

The other three cultivators finally realized the relationship between Han Li and Wan Tianhe. After glancing at each other in dismay, weird expressions appeared on each of their faces.

Han Li didn’t pay this much heed. After a moment of silence, he nodded his head, “Since Fellow Daoist Lei says this, I won’t be polite. Let us immediately depart from here. Your speed is all rather slow, so I will be bringing you.

Once that was said, Han Li slapped his storage pouch and a small, exquisite item appeared in his hand. Once he flung it into the air, a squarish item appeared before them in a flash of red light.

Under control of spell seals, the Wind Riding Chariot quickly grew larger and appeared over thirty meters wide.

“Get in the chariot!” Han Li bluntly ordered them. Lei Wanhe and the others naturally didn’t have any objections and they all flew into the chariot with a blur.

Once Han Li stepped onto the Wind Riding Chariot, he began to infuse the chariot with his spiritual power. After gently trembling for a moment, it tore through the skies as a streak of white light. With its exceeding speed, it disappeared from sight in the blink of an eye.

The speed of the Wind Riding Chariot delighted the others. At this speed, the spell warriors wouldn’t be able to pursue them, relieving them of worry that was on their minds.

As Han Li drove the Wind Riding Chariot, he casually asked, “Fellow Daoists, the State of Fengyuan should’ve already fallen into the grasp of the spell warriors. Why were you there and how did you come to be blocked by a Nascent Soul spell warrior? If that area weren’t so remote, it wouldn’t have been easy to escape even if I took action.”

When the five heard this, they glanced at each other with various expression. The clear leader of their party, Lei Wanhe, hesitated for a moment before answering, “Senior might not know this, but we didn’t act out of our free will. We were under orders from the Nine Nations Union to carry-out an important task. As a result, we were occupied for several days and were present during the Moulan invasion.

Helpless, we could only choose a remote route and fly back, however, we encountered a few low grade spell warriors along the way and had no choice but to kill them. But who could’ve possibly known that there was a Nascent Soul spell warrior that was located nearby. Just as we finished killing the last low grade spell warrior, we were discovered by the old eccentric and were chased down.

Although we knew we weren’t a match, if we scattered, we would’ve only met our end sooner, so we could only do our utmost. It was only by a fluke that Senior Han came our way, else we would’ve met our end.”

As Lei Wanhe spoke with gratitude, he examined this “Martial Nephew Han”. To tell the truth, he still felt as if all that happened was a dream.

When Han Li heard this, he lost interest and indifferently grunted. A short moment later, he then asked, “Fellow Daoist Lei, is my master Li Huayuan still doing well?”

As there was no point in concealing the matter, Lei Wanhe honestly answered, “Senior Han, Junior martial brother Li died a hundred years ago in the war with the Moulan spell warriors. As for his wife, she wasn’t able to form a golden core and reached the end of her lifespan.”

Han Li was slightly shaken by his words and revealed a trace of sadness. He then asked, “Were my Fellow Martial Brothers and Sisters able to form a golden core?”

Lei Wanhe sighed and said, “No, although three of Junior martial brother Li’s disciples had exceptional aptitude and entered false core stage, they weren’t fated to form a golden core.”

Han Li grew silent for a moment. The appearances of Yu Kun, Song Meng, Zhong Weiniang, and the others appeared through his mind. Past events slowly began to appear.

A moment later, he took a deep breath. Since his Martial Brothers and Sisters were unable to form a golden core, he didn’t further ask about them. It was likely that they died during meditation. His time spent at Yellow Maple Valley seemed as if it had all happened in an old dream.

At that moment, Nie Yan suddenly said, “Senior Han, would you happen to be interested in rejoining Yellow Maple Valley?”

Han Li raised his brow and immediately answered, “Return to Yellow Maple Valley? I have no such interest. I’ve already become an elder of the Heavenly Dao Alliance’s Drifting Cloud Sect, and I am satisfied there.”

Disappointment appeared from Nie Yan’s expression and Lei Wanhe’s expression wavered.

As for the other three, they didn’t dare to speak as they were unfamiliar with Han Li.

After a moment of hesitation, Nie Yan then asked, “Would Senior happen to recognize Xiao Cui’er?”

Han Li was stunned for a moment. He asked with an odd expression, “Xiao Cui’er [3] ? Of course I do, you know that little girl?” At that same moment, the appearance of that young, strange-spirited girl came to mind.

[1]. Chapter 158: Blue-clothed Woman

[Back]

[2]. In Chapter 236: Ancient Formula, Han Li traded medicine herbs for Lei Wanhe’s pill formulas. Prior to this, Le Wanhe had assisted Han Li in getting rid of a few Thousand Bamboo Sect cultivators.

[Back]

[3]. Introduced in Chapter 291: Xiao Clan while Han Li was guarding the mortal Qin Clan. At the time, Xiao Ciu and her grandfather were Qi Condensation cultivators. For payment of the nameless qi restraining incantation, he had introduced her to his Senior Martial Brother Ma at Yellow Maple Valley as a disciple.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 712: Entering Disguised

Not long after Yuan Kun began shopping in the village, he smoothly gathered all the items he needed and flew back to the Gemcut Mountains with his two assistants. But when the three only traveled fifteen kilometers away from the city, silver light suddenly flashed ahead of them, revealing a gorgeous young woman. She looked at the three with a captivating smile.

“We are Masked Moon Sect disciples. Senior...” Although Yuan Kun’s cultivation was low, the strange scene that appeared before him indicated that the woman was beyond ordinary. He immediately fell back on his identity as a sect member to protect them.

However, it seemed as if the woman didn’t hear him. She chuckled and blew out a pink mist from her mouth. The mist appeared to be slow, but it enveloped the three in an instant.

Yuan Kun and company were unable to resist due to their meager cultivation. After smelling a trace of the scent, they felt their minds fade away as they fell unconscious, promptly collapsing onto the ground.

Without any hesitation, the young woman waved her sleeve and released a white mist from her cuff. The mist immediately grabbed the three and brought them to her side. After glancing at their faces, the young woman giggled and glowed with silver light, immediately taking to the skies with her captives.

The white light traveled over five kilometers away before dropping down at a desolate forest. There was an azure-robed youth that was sitting down cross-legged beneath a large tree and peacefully resting.

Right after the white light suddenly appeared before them, it disappeared. Yuan Kun and company were silently laid down in front of the youth, and the young woman gracefully floated down from the sky. The woman stood in front of the youth and respectfully said, “Master, I’ve brought people. They called themselves Masked Moon Sect cultivators. They should be what you’re looking for.”

The youth opened his eyes and indifferently asked, “You didn’t alarm any others?”

Of course, the youth was Han Li who had spent most of the last month rushing to the State of Beiliang.

Since he planned on stealthily finding Nangong Wan, he couldn’t brazenly pay her a visit on her doorstep. It would better to avoid any unnecessary trouble. As such, he needed to understand a few details about the Masked Moon Sect and he decided to stay at a small town nearby.

As one who had once tread the path of cultivation since he was a low grade cultivator, Han Li understood that a sect’s low grade disciples were incapable of completely separating themselves from the mortal world. The town closest to the sect should be a place well frequented by low grade disciples.

With Han Li’s immense spiritual sense, regardless of how many cultivators entered the city, they would be incapable of escaping his notice.

Originally, Han Li was eyeing another Masked Moon Sect Qi Condensation disciple, but when a Qi Condensation disciple wearing steward robes arrived in town, Han Li’s target had changed to him. A disciple of higher rank would naturally know of the sect far better.

With a thread of spiritual sense tied around him, he ordered Silvermoon to capture him and his associates. Afterwards, they were brought to the forest where he was waiting.

Knowing that Han Li was currently in a poor mood, she abandoned any intent to jest and tactfully replied in an earnest manner, “Master, be at ease. It was an easy task to capture three Qi Condensation cultivators. It definitely didn’t catch anyone’s attention.”

Han Li expressionlessly glanced at Yuan Kun’s body and coldly grunted, “Well done. With your demon fox illusion techniques and my Dreamtear Technique, we will have him tell us everything.”

Silvermoon immediately answered, “As you command, Master.”

Afterwards, she turned around and blew several breaths of pink mist onto the three on the ground, filling the entire surrounding area.

Han Li stood up and slowly entered the mist. Not long after, faint azure light faintly pulsed from within it.

Although the Gemcut Mountains had a notable name, the first time anyone that came to its mountain wouldn’t know why it had the name “Gemcut”. It didn’t appear exquisite as its name had implied. Rather, it appeared strange and oversized.

The Gemcut Mountains didn’t have many branching mountain, but the main mountain spanned tens of kilometers in length. Moreover, the bottom half the mountain appeared quite smooth and flat without any cliffs as if it were a huge slope.

But the center of the mountains suddenly grew steep. Not only was the mountain stones frighteningly steep but the spiritual Qi was far more plentiful. It was where the Core Formation cultivators placed their own cave residences.

But in order to prevent any attacks from the sky, ferocious spell restrictions were placed down around the top of the Gemcut Mountains. Low grade disciples have no method of climbing the mountain apart from a few set pathways.

Han Li currently stood at the center of the Gemcut Mountains on a simple stone road. He looked up to the top of the Gemcut Mountains with a soft expression.

His current appearance had greatly changed through the use of the Appearance Exchange Arts. His entire body and stature had precisely changed to that of Yuan Kun. Of course, he had also restrained his cultivation to Qi Condensation stage.

After acquiring the information that he wanted from Yuan Kun and his subordinates, he imprisoned the three in a dry tree hollow and boldly entered the Gemcut Mountains. With Yuan Kun’s steward command medallion along with the information he had acquired from the Dreamtear technique, he was able to easily enter the Masked Moon Sect.

He currently stood at a market city that was constructed at a corner of the Gemcut Mountains where thousands of disciples traded for wanted items. Among them were a few stores that sold mortal goods which were specifically managed by this Steward Yuan.

Han Li didn’t directly head to the top of the mountain. Instead, he patiently brought the items that Yuan Kun purchased at the mortal town and delivered them to these stores. He left each of these stores under the respective gazes of the shopkeepers and glanced up the mountain.

From these three disciples’ memories, although Nangong Wan was on the verge of getting married, she wasn’t freely accepting visitors despite not being in secluded cultivation. Even the high grade disciples of the sect found it difficult to meet their Martial Ancestor Nangong.

As for why Nangong Wan would agree to become the pair cultivation companion of the Flowing Mind Sect’s Wei Lichen, it was still unknown to Han Li. The three he had captured were lowly ranked and didn’t know anything of the matter, much to Han Li’s disappointment.

But from their memories, Han Li was able to clearly see, as the youngest Nascent Soul cultivator in the Masked Moon Sect and an amazing, world-shaking beauty, Nangong Wan held the vast adoration of many of the low grade disciples in the sect. There were even vast amounts of male disciples that secretly held romantic feelings for her, Yuan Kun being one of them.

Although he had only seen Nangong Wan a couple of times in the many years that he spent there, he was infatuated. When he heard that Nangong Wan was to be married, Steward Yuan felt depressed for a long while. When Han Li saw these memories, he was speechless.

Now that Han Li had finished delivering the mortal goods, he casually dealt with other matters in accordance to Yuan Kun’s memories. Fortunately, Steward Yuan didn’t have any particularly deep relationships in the sect and none were able to see through any gaps in behavior.

A while later, Han Li saw that the sky was dimming and felt that it was about time. According to the Yuan Kun’s ordinary behavior, he calmly climbed the mountain.

Although Yuan Kun was only a Qi Condensation cultivator, he was still a sect steward, and possessed a small, unremarkable residence on the second level of the Gemcut Mountains.

Han Li was able to make it into the second level of the Gemcut Mountains without any problems, but he came across a few Foundation Establishment cultivators along the way. When they spotted Han Li disguised as Steward Yuan, they each glanced at him with disdain. There were a few that ignored him.

When Han Li was alone, he bitterly chuckled as he stroked his chin. It seems that apart from Steward Yuan’s subordinates, this person didn’t get along well with others.

After entering the second level, Han Li didn’t go to Yuan Kun’s small residence. Instead, he flew towards the top of the mountain along the path on a low altitude flying tool. Although the other areas appeared empty, Han Li knew that formidable restrictions had been placed there. He naturally didn’t dare to touch them.

Eventually, Han Li arrived at the border entrance between the second and third level of the mountain. There were two Foundation Establishment cultivators that had bluntly blocked his way.

The pale-skinned cultivator frowned and loudly shouted, “Yuan Kun! What did you come here for! You should know that you have no business here.”

After a long while of hesitation, “Martial Uncles, this Martial Nephew wishes... wishes to see Martial Ancestor Nangong. Would Martial Uncles be able to report this?”

Once the two cultivators recovered from their shock, they harshly rebuked him without further thought, “What are you saying? Yuan Kun, are you awake? You must be daydreaming to think you can see Martial Ancestor Nangong!”

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 713: Nangong Wan

Han Li wore a miserable expression and said, “When this Martial Nephew went out to purchase a few items, I encountered a Senior with an unfathomable cultivation, he wanted to me to give something to Martial Ancestor Nangong. He even placed a restriction on my body, saying that only Martial Ancestor Nangong would be able to dispel it.”

The pale-skinned cultivator asked bewilderedly, “Senior!? Was he a Core Formation cultivator?”

Continuing his dejected expression, he helplessly said, “This... Martial Nephew isn’t sure. But this cultivator stated that he was an old friend of Martial Ancestor Nangong and wished to send her a congratulatory gift, having heard that he grand celebration was drawing near. There are still some things that I have to personally say to her.”

“An old friend of Martial Ancestor? Could he also be a Nascent Soul Senior?” This time, the burly cultivator had spoken with alarm.

After the pale-skinned cultivator recovered from his surprise, he doubtfully said, “It is possible, but since Senior was already there, why didn’t he personally arrive at the mountain and present the gift?”

“Who knows! Maybe this Senior has some of other matters to attend to, or maybe he finds it inconvenient,” after a few of his musings, the burly cultivate bluntly said, “Martial Nephew Yuan, extend your hand and let us see the restriction on your body!”

Having expected this, Han Li calmly extended his arm towards him and surged spiritual power throughout his power, simulating a bizarre magic power restriction on his body.

The burly cultivator grabbed onto Han Li’s arm and revealed astonishment after sensing it for a short moment. The pale-skinned cultivator also curiously placed two of his fingers on Han Li’s arm. Not long after, he wore a similar expression on his face.

The pale-skinned cultivator eased his expression and his tone grew less harsh, “That’s right, a fearsome restriction has been placed on your body. From the degree of its complexity, it appears to have been laid down by a Nascent Soul cultivator. However, we cannot allow you to easily climb the mountain on this alone. First, take out the congratulatory gift. One of us will take it to Martial Ancestor Nangong and see whether or not this person is truly an old friend of hers.

If Martial Ancestor is willing to see you, you can climb the mountain. Do you understand, Martial Nephew Yuan?”

When Han Li heard this, he wore a bitter expression, but after some thought, he nodded his head.

Han Li took out a long wooden box from his storage pouch and handed it over to him. He anxiously added, “This is fine. However, Martial Uncle must clearly explain the matter of the restriction placed down on my body!”

The lid of the wooden box had a faint silver restriction talisman placed on top of it. From its spiritual Qi fluctuations, it appeared to be quite importantly. It was clear to see this was to prevent anybody from opening the box as it was delivered.

“I understand. Properly wait here for the time being. Junior Martial Brother Ma, I am going!” The pale-skinned cultivator spoke impatiently to Han Li and gave a word of warning to the burly cultivator before flying off on his magic tool with the wooden box in hand.

Han Li could only calmly stand in place.

Although he was confident that Nangong Wan would see him once she opened the box, he still felt somewhat apprehensive.

He answered the intermittent questions from the guard that was left behind. However, when he asked of the appearance of the Senior who had delivered this gift, Han Li answered that this Senior was wearing a cloak and that he couldn’t tell whether or not they were a man or a woman.

After the time it took to finish a meal, the pale-skinned cultivator returned with empty hands.

“Martial Ancestor Nanlong said that this person is truly an old friend of hers, and that I am able to bring you to see her to dissolve the restriction.” After curtly speaking, the pale-faced cultivator had Han Li follow him up the mountain.

Han Li was overjoyed by this and wore an excited expression as he followed the pale-skinned cultivator.

“Be careful. There are paths that you cannot take no matter what. These restrictions are far more formidable than the restrictions on the center level. Even I wouldn’t survive if I fell into them.”

Of course, Han Li answered with acknowledgement.

At that moment, a streak of blue light shot forwards to meet them. The pale-skinned cultivator seemed to recognize the owner of this light and stopped in place with a respectful expression.

Soon, the light arrived before the two and faded away to reveal a middle-aged, embroidered-robed cultivator with an imposing appearance.

The embroidered-robed cultivator glanced at Han Li and said with a cold tone, “Martial Nephew Sun, why have you brought a Qi Condensation cultivator to the top of the mountain. Do you not understand the rules here?

The pale-skinned cultivator seemed to hold much reverence towards the embroidered-robed cultivator and hastily explained, “Martial Senior Lan, this Martial Nephew is only following Martial Ancestor Nangong’s orders. I wouldn’t have the courage otherwise to dare to do this.”

At that moment, Han Li swept his gaze past the embroidered-robed man to discover that he was merely an early Core Formation cultivator, and that he need not pay him much heed. Although these were his thoughts, he also assumed a respectful expression and didn’t dare to rashly speak.

When the embroidered-robed cultivator heard this, he was stunned for a moment before astonishedly asking, “Martial Aunt Nangong wishes to see this person? Tell me how this came to be.”

“It’s like this. Martial Nephew Yuan...” Unknown whether the pale-skinned cultivator didn’t dare to conceal this matter from his Martial Senior or that he was indifferent about the matter, he narrated the events that had occurred.

“An old friend of Martial Aunt Nangong placed a restriction on his body?” The embroidered-robed cultivator frowned and suddenly looked at Han Li with a penetrating gaze.

The embroidered-robed cultivator bluntly ordered, “Let me have a look at the restriction on your body!”

Han Li cursed at this person’s nosy meddling and could only helplessly obey.

The embroidered-robed cultivator grabbed Han Li’s wrist and deeply examined it for a moment before nodding his head, “Yi! This is truly odd. However, although this restriction is complex, it isn’t malicious. It seems this person didn’t have any ill intent. Go ahead and see Martial Aunt Nangong!”

Afterwards, he paid the two no further heed and shot down the mountain in a flash of faint blue light. A short moment later, the light dimmed and grew indistinct, disappearing soon after.

The pale-skinned cultivator waited until the embroidered-robed cultivated departed before taking a deep breath and gazing in the direction that the light disappeared. He muttered, “Martial Uncle Lan’s Incorporeal Evasion Technique can be said to be as blue as his name [1] . Although he is only at early Core Formation stage, even late Core Formation cultivators would find it difficult to deal with him!”

‘The Incorporeal Evasion Technique!’ When Han Li heard this, his heart stirred. Could this person have something to do with the Old Eccentric Qiong [2] that he saw during the Trial by Blood and Fire? Perhaps he was a descendant or disciple.

At that moment, the pale-skinned cultivator had relaxed and continued to lead the way. Soon after, Han Li tossed the matter of the embroidered-robed cultivator to the back of his mind.

Because the top level of the Gemcut Mountains didn’t house many cultivators to begin with, the two didn’t encounter anybody else as they traveled to a cave residence close to the peak of the mountain.

The pale-skinned cultivator spoke with a tone of admiration, “This is Martial Ancestor Nanlong’s meditation area! Speak carefully when you reply to the Martial Ancestor, and don’t say anything unrelated to the restriction placed on your body. Perhaps she may have some benefits in store for you!”

After he said that, he turned towards the gate and respectfully said, “Reporting to Martial Ancestor. The disciple is already here.”

“En! I understand. Have the disciple enter alone. You may take your leave!” The voice faintly carried a trace of familiarity and strangeness. Once those words were said, the door to the cave residence flickered with yellow light and the stone opened.

Han Li walked forward without any hesitation.

To Han Li’s surprise, there was a beautiful female cultivator wearing yellow short-sleeved robes that stood behind the door. She appeared to be the age of eighteen and possessed early Foundation Establishment cultivation.

The woman examined Han Li’s transformed figure of Yuan Kun and found nothing to be wrong. She coldly said, “Follow me. Martial Ancestor is waiting for you in the main hall!”

The woman turned around and entered the cave residence. Han Li lightly sighed and closely followed after her.

Nangong Wan’s cave residence couldn’t be considered large. The Foundation Establishment woman brought Han Li down a short corridor and through several small side rooms before arriving at the main hall.

The hall was elegantly decorated and there was some unknown essence being burned at an unknown corner of the room. There were two interesting small flower pots, each with a precious herb flourishing in them.

There was an exquisite square wooden table at the center of the hall. Each side had a light green straw chair. One of the chairs was occupied with a black-haired, white-clothed young woman. She was looking down at the huge sparkling silver sword in her hand.

The wood box on the table was open now laid empty.

[1]. His Surname “Lan” 蓝 is the same character for blue.

[Back]

[2]. First mentioned in Chapter 176: Making a Bet, Elder Qiong was a formidable Core Formation cultivator from the Masked Moon Sect.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare

Chapter 715: Heart Restraint Technique

“There isn’t much to be said after we parted. I returned to the Masked Moon Sect. Once my sect gained footing in the State of Beiliang, I snuck into the State of Yue to find you. However, the information I acquired was rather terrible. I only knew that you had been hunted down by the Ghost Spirit Sect. The concrete details of the matter were unknown. Not long after, I was discovered by the Devil Dao and was forced to return to the Nine Nations Alliance.

“Afterwards, I never acquired information on you. I believed you dead and my inner demons with regards to you had gradually disappeared. Along the way, I managed to condense a Nascent Soul and smoothly became an elder of the Masked Moon Sect. And here we are now.” Nangong Wan spoke with a calm tone.

Han Li’s expression changed several times as he listened to Nangong Wan’s unhurried explanation. In the past, she had done many things he was completely ignorant of, causing him to look upon her with even greater warmth.

A moment later, Han Li couldn’t help but ask, “What’s this about Wei Lichen?”

Nangong Wan coldly smiled. “Wei Lichen! I unintentionally encountered him as he was travelling several years prior. I am not fond of him. He appears to be elegant and noble, but he is a thieving hypocrite and a philanderer.

“I heard that he secretly performs Yin Drawing Techniques on each of his eight female disciples. He most likely harbors ill intentions towards marrying me. That was why I refused his first request to marry me.”

“Refuse? What changed?” Han Li curiously asked.

Nangong Wan didn’t directly answer and suddenly asked, “Do you know of the three great Nascent Soul cultivators in the Heavenly South?”

Han Li’s expression turned grim and faintly felt that something was amiss. “Naturally. There is a late Nascent Soul cultivator in the Righteous Dao, the Devilish Dao, and the Nine Nations Alliance, each only a step away from entering Deity Transformation stage. This is how each of the three superpowers remain on equal footing. As for our Heavenly Dao Alliance, we have two mid Nascent Soul-stage Dao Companions that are proficient in cooperative techniques. Together, they are capable of restraining a late Nascent soul cultivator, albeit with difficulty. What? Does Wei Lichen have anything to do with one of them?”

“Exactly. Wei Lichen’s great uncle is Wei Wuya, one of the three great cultivators. As the highest ranking elder of the Nine Nations Alliance, this Wei Wuya cultivates a rarely seen venomous cultivation art. With a sweep of his hand, he is able to take another life without any contact. His immense abilities are beyond imagination.” Nangong Wan folded her fingers together and bitterly smiled.

Han Li scowled and a malicious light surfaced in his eyes. “Could it be that this Wei Wuya personally made things difficult for you?”

Nangong Wan wore an indignant expression. “No, but Wei Wuya is personally involved. You may not know this, but our sect’s previous great elder passed away and was replaced with an old senior martial sister. Although her cultivation isn’t weak, she is of shrewd mind and is normally at odds with me. Although we get along with our other elder, the relationship between us is awful!”

Han Li’s expression grew sullen as Nangong Wan moved on to the heart of the matter.

After Nangong Wan gritted her teeth, she said, “After refusing Wei Lichen’s marriage request several times, Wei Lichen personally caused Wei Wuya to pay a visit to this senior martial sister of mine.

“Although I didn’t know what the two spoke about, half a year later during an incarnation period of my Female Essence Incarnation Technique, she suddenly restrained and forced me into wedding Wei Lichen.”

After a moment of shock, Han Li incredulously said, “Is your senior martial sister not sick in the head? Using such a method to deal with a Nascent Soul cultivator of the same sect?”

Nangong Wan smirked and mockingly said, “Isn’t that the truth? I hadn’t expected her to be crazed to this degree. However, it seems Wei Wuya’s conditions were truly difficult to refuse. I later found out that so long as the Masked Moon Sect agreed to this marriage, not only would the Six Sects expand out of the State of Beiliang, but Wei LIchen would be willing to leave the Flowing Mind Sect after marrying me and join the Masked Moon Sect. For these two benefits at the price of one, she acted without any hesitation. Regardless of my intentions, she released information that I was to be wed with Wei Lichen and prepared to hold a celebration, wishing to forcefully conclude the matter before it can be changed. If I wished to later back out, I would have no method of doing so.”

Han Li delightedly said, “So it turned out you hadn’t agreed to this matter. These words of you deliberately wishing to marry came as a shock to me!”

Nangong Wan looked at Han Li and unhappily said, “I still have something I wish to ask you! Even after condensing a Nascent Soul for so many years, why is it that you didn’t seek me out sooner? If you came a year earlier, this troublesome matter could’ve been avoided.

“It isn’t that I didn’t wish to see you, but rather...” Han Li attempted to give an explanation, but after a moment, he found this truly strange as well.

Although Han Li faintly felt that Nangong Wan should’ve been someone that he truly cherished, for some unknown reason, he never thought to touch upon this feeling. If it weren’t for news of Nangong Wan suddenly marrying, he feared that he still would’ve hesitated on this matter rather than directly confront these feelings.

As Han Li’s expression remained calm, Nangong Wan gracefully stood up and took several steps toward Han Li. She directly looked into his eyes and said, “In fruth, my own circumstances are about the same as yours. Although our own experiences and abilities are far beyond that of mortals, we are fearful and unfamiliar towards our first venture of our emotions. Even if we have a deep impression of each other, we aren’t a mortal pair after all. We cannot release all of our passion in an instant and have our emotions blaze like a star. For an optimal attitude for cultivation, cultivators have no option but to weaken our emotions and bury a majority of them. What is left behind is only an ordinary and flat relationship that is enduring. But when I heard that you were still alive, I felt more than happy and spent two days in careful consideration before eventually deciding to accept you in accordance to my feelings.”

After she said this with a soft tone, Nangong Wan extended her slender hand and grabbed Han Li’s palm.

After a moment of silence, Han Li placed his other hand on top. The soft sensation of her hand caused him to feel a trace of comfort.

Nangong Wan blushed and she quickly pulled her hand away, bashfully glaring at Han Li in the process. Han Li didn’t mind this and simply smiled. “Wan’er, although you are trapped here, from how calm you are, you should already have a plan for escape. Why else would you appear so worry free?”

When Nangong Wan heard this, she smiled and sly intent was betrayed from her eyes. “You’re a quick thinker! Yes, although I am under house arrest, only a sparse few in the upper echelons are aware of this matter. Ordinary disciples are completely ignorant. Else, I wouldn’t have been able to directly receive a sound transmission talisman from Martial Nephew Tang. However, many restrictions have been placed on my body in fear that I would flee.

“The other restrictions are of no matter to me as they were placed without knowledge of what amazing abilities I was capable of once I entered Nascent Soul stage. These common restrictions can be removed at any time, restoring my original cultivation. But there is one restriction that isn’t easily dissolved: the Heart Restraint Technique was personally placed on my body by that senior martial sister. This technique was something that she prepared from a record. If I were unwilling to agree to the marriage, she’d be able to use this technique to temporarily control me. She even used her own blood essence to place down the restriction, creating a restriction talisman that serves as the crucial point of the restriction. Through the use of this restriction medallion, I will not be able to escape her control within fifty kilometers of her, unless it is destroyed. Fortunately, there isn’t too great a gap between our cultivation and she is only able to control me to perform a few simple movements. She will have no control over my body’s magic power.”

Han Li curiously asked, “Then your plan was to...”

Nangong Wan softly smiled and chuckled. She said with a worryless tone, “I originally thought to restore my magic power when security was the lightest, several days before the ceremony was about to take place. Afterwards, I would immediately flee far away. So long as I am outside of the restriction talisman’s range, she cannot control me. But since you’re here now, I’ll leave this matter to you. After all, you are the man that wishes to marry me. From what I’ve heard, you were able to easily defeat a cultivator of a similar grade. You should be quite skilled.”

Han Li frowned and muttered, “Heart Restraint Technique? That restriction is truly troublesome. Are there other methods of dissolving it apart from destroying the medallion?”

Nangong Wan’s bright eyes flickered and she carelessly said, “Even if there isn’t, leave it be. We’ll be far away from the Masked Moon Sect anyhow.”

Han Li’s eyes narrowed and a cold glint flickered from his eyes. He imposingly said, “It’s fine! Isn’t it just a restriction talisman? It should be in your Senior Martial Sister’s grasp. I can simply go and fetch it. I’ll be able to vent some anger on your behalf as well!”

Nangong Wan shook her head and pursed her lips in a smile, revealing a trace of mischievousness. “I was merely saying it to test your intentions. I truly had no intention of having you go and seize the restriction talisman. My senior martial sister is a mid Nascent Soul cultivator and possesses abilities beyond that of early Nascent Soul cultivators like us. Let us sneak away stealthily. At worst, I’ll just spend another ten years whittling away at the formation.”

Han Li grew silent. The time for him to be united with this otherworldly woman was soon to come!

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Vish

PR: Vare

Chapter 724: Linghu's Request

After Lady Qi pondered for a moment, she said, “Although Fellow Daoist Han’s words are very likely, they are still only a guess. I hope you Fellow Daoists will discuss these matters only among other Nascent Soul cultivators in order to prevent an unnecessary chaos. However, if the Moulan truly wishes to have a grand confrontation, their Divine Sages will be certain to take action. These late Nascent Soul stage spell warriors aren’t something we are able to contend against. I will be informing Elder Wei Wuya of this, and see whether or not the three great cultivators can gather together and deal with this matter.”

A shriveled old man worriedly nodded his head, “Lady Qi makes sense. This matter is urgent. When we return, we will immediately inform our sect of this matter.”

The other cultivators also agreed, all knowing that the matter was grave.

Afterwards, the cultivators began to discuss about a few particulars and decided to first send some reinforcements to slow down the Moulan, buying the various powers the time they needed to prepare.

Han Li, Senior Martial Brother Lu, and the Child Fire Dragon walked out of the hall side by side. When they arrived outside, Han Li frowned.

Elder Lu caught sight of Han LI’s expression and asked with surprise, “Is there something wrong Junior Martial Brother?”

“It’s nothing. There is just an old acquaintance that wishes to see me. I’m afraid that it will take a moment. Senior Martial Brother Lu, Brother Lan, please go ahead. I’ll quickly return!”

Elder Lu nodded his head and smiled, “Yes, of course. We’ll first head back to have a discussion amongst the cultivators of the Heavenly Dao Alliance and then send information back to our Senior Martial Brother. We’ll see how each of our alliance’s sects will handle the matter.”

The Child Fire Dragon also responded with a smile.

Han Li saluted in response before slowly walking away.

Elder Lu stood at the hall’s entrance and glanced in the direction that Han Li had taken.

“Is there something that Brother Lu is worried about?” The Child Fire Dragon asked with a mysterious smile.

Although Elder Lu’s heart was uneasy, he maintained a calm exterior, “Worried? What is there to be worried about?”

The Child Fire Dragon smiled and said, “Brother Lu should have already guessed. Fellow Daoist Han was originally from Yellow Maple Valley and that Eccentric Linghu is nearing the end of his lifespan like your Senior Martial Brother. As Eccentric Linghu is the only Nascent Soul cultivator in Yellow Maple Valley, he may already be burning with anxiousness. While this might not matter to a smaller sect, to a sect as large as Yellow Maple Valley, the absence of the protection of a Nascent Soul cultivator could likely lead to a sect’s extermination. It would be odd if Eccentric Linghu wasn’t the one who had given Han Li the voice transmission.”

Brother Lu didn’t immediately respond. Instead, he pondered to himself for a moment before asking, “How does Brother Lan know of Junior Martial Brother Han’s origins? I do not recall mentioning them.”

The Child Fire Dragon bluntly explained, “There was no need for Brother Lu to speak of it. Since your sect suddenly acquired a young newly ascended elder, our Ancient Sword Sect naturally felt the need to investigate.”

Elder Lu had nothing to say in response. But after a moment, he shook his head and said, “Junior Martial Brother Han simply said that he was going to see an old acquaintance. If he originally intended to go back to Yellow Maple Valley, he would’ve already done so. He wouldn’t have waited until now!”

The Child Fire Dragon shook his head, “That may be true, but Eccentric Linghu is a cunning old fox. Since he invited Han Li over, he should have some confidence of convincing him.”

Elder Lu grew silent for a moment. Eventually, a troubled expression appeared on his face and he sighed, “Let’s leave it to fate. If Junior Martial Brother Han truly wishes to return to Yellow Maple Valley, what can my Senior Martial Brother or I do to stop him?”

...

Han Li stood in a small remote street and began to continuously observe his surroundings. He then caught sight of a two story pavilion. It was only about twenty meters wide with a small banner at its entrance that wrote ‘Tea’ on it. There were two yellow-robed Foundation Establishment cultivators standing there.

Han Li smiled for a moment before approaching it.

When the two saw Han Li walk over, they respectfully saluted him, “Greetings Senior Han! Martial Ancestor is respectfully waiting for you!”

Han Li nodded his head and wordlessly entered.

The entire building was extremely quiet as if there were no one there. Han Li hesitated before climbing up to the second floor. As a result, he found someone calmly waiting for him. He was wearing yellow robes and had a sallow complexion — he was Ancestor Linghu who he has just seen previously in the hall.

He was currently sitting at the octogonal table in the center of the room, and was currently sipping on a cup of tea.

Han Li’s gaze flickered and he walked forward without hesitation. He silently took a seat across from Ancestor Lingu, noticing that there was a teacup that had already been prepared for him.

Ancestor Linghu said nothing. He simply waved his and caused the teapot on the table to float. It poured some tea in the cup in front of him before floating back down.

Eccentric Linghu narrowed his eyes and glanced at Han Li. He slowly said, “The spirit tea here is good. Will you not give it a taste?”

Han Li smiled and brought the cup up his eyes, glancing at the clear green liquid within.

Han Li then took a sip and said, “It is quite decent. It is truly a grade higher than common spirit teas.”

Eccentric Linghu put down the tea and chuckled. He unhurriedly said, “It seems Fellow Daoist Han is also one fond of tea. It seems I was right to meet you here.”

Holding no intention to speak in circles, Han Li bluntly said, “Surely you didn’t invite me here only to sample this spirit tea! If you have something to say, then say it.”

This Ancestor Linghu clearly recognized him. Han Li could already guess why he was invited here.

“Since Fellow Daoist is so impatient, I won’t speak in circles. Would Fellow Dan be willing to return to Yellow Maple Valley as an elder?” Ancestor Linghu calmly spoke as if he were speaking of a minor issue.

“Return to Yellow Maple Valley?” Han Li didn’t reveal the slightest change in expression and simply looked down at the tea cup in his hand.

A bright glint shined from Ancestor Linghu’s eyes and he slowly said, “Needless to mention how you were treated wrongly in the past, I must tell you that my lifespan is running short. I only have twenty years more at best before I expire. So long as you return, Yellow Maple Valley will be yours. Surely you wouldn’t have held onto some minor grudge for so long!”

Han Li raised his head and stared at Ancestor Linghu. He shook his head, “I no longer care about the matters of the past. If I found myself in your position, I would perhaps do the same. However, I am currently an elder of the Drifting Cloud Sect. I have no intention of joining your sect. Fellow Daoist Linghu, you had best find another cultivator.”

Ancestor Linghu coldly smiled, “Of course I know you’ve joined the Drifting Cloud Sect. However, the Drifting Cloud Sect still has two other elders. Do you not have to share control? Wouldn’t you be happy to be the sole holder of power?

Han Li pursed his lips, forming a faint sneer. “I believe you misunderstand. I didn’t enter a sect for authority. I merely wished to find a suitable place for cultivation. I have no interest in control over a sect.”

Ancestor Linghu frowned, but he soon regained his calm.

“Fellow Daoist Han doesn’t realize how beneficial is it towards your cultivation to be the sole power over a sect. Not only will you not have to trouble yourself to find rare medicines and materials, you will gain an incomparable status in the cultivation world. Moreover, don’t you have the slightest interest in your past sect members? Many cultivators of your generation are still within Yellow Maple Valley. If there isn’t a Nascent Soul cultivator to protect them, they may as well be extinguished in a single night by a coalition of other sects. Who knows what will happen to them?” Ancestor Linghu had finally begun to appeal to emotion.

Han Li smiled and carelessly said, “I have no lack of spirit medicines and materials as a Drifting Cloud Sect Elder. And how could I care for something as hollow as status and reputation in the cultivation world? As for the death of the sect, it had always been a common occurrence. No matter how long the sect existed, they eventually disappear with their legacy lost. As for my old sect members, I will not be involved with them. May fate treat them kindly.”

Chapter 732: Fire Spirit Flood Dragon

The two high grade spell warriors at the black figure’s side whispered something as if discussing how to destroy the grand formation ahead of them. Once the two finished their discussion, the oddly tall, shriveled cultivator blurred out of side and reappeared at the side of the black-robed figure while wrapped in azure light.

“Sir Heavenweep, shall we start? The grand formation here should prove to be more powerful than the last. I’ve also heard that there should be a few Nascent Soul cultivators there. I fear that it will take quite some time.”

“There is no need for us to attack first.” tThe black-robed spell warrior shook his head. “They have already decided to emerge. Let’s first see how powerful these cultivators are before we decide what to do.” He spoke hoarsely and unclear almost as if he didn’t have a tongue, much to the unease of those who heard him.

When the lanky spell warrior heard this, he blinked in surprise and glanced down towards the green mist. As expected, a previously still area of the green mist suddenly began to roil and split into two with flickers of light that could be seen from within.

Soon after, seven streaks of light shot out from within. They circled once around in the sky before revealing themselves — they were the party of five Nascent Soul stage and two Core Formation stage cultivators.

Under the bald man’s command, there would be no low grade cultivators following them with the exception of the Core Formation cultivators from Sky Terrace Valley and Chong Xuzi.

Han Li stopped in the air and glanced across the army of spell warriors. Of course, the ten spell warriors leading them had attracted his attention, particularly the sinister black-robed figure. He wasn’t able to stare for long as he unconsciously averted his gaze.

When he saw this black-robed figure, he was immediately reminded of the Bone Sage, Xiao Cha.

‘Could it be this person was also a ghost Dao cultivator?’ Han Li’s heart trembled and he grew vastly more diligent.

Before the Bone Sage seized Crooked Soul’s body, his material form was dense with Yin and ghostly Qi. However, there was something slightly different with the black-robed figure’s aura that Han Li couldn’t describe for the time being.

As Han Li and company arrived, the spell warriors above began to stir. The spell warrior with the python wrapped around him suddenly transformed into a huge ball of light as it shot down towards the cultivators. When Han Li and company saw this, they coldly watched in silence, revealing not a single trace of panic.

So long as that spell warrior wasn’t seeking his own death, he wouldn’t dare to take the initiative to attack alone. As a result, the group of cultivators simply watched with hostile gazes as the huge fireball arrived twenty meters away from them. The flames emitted a scorching heat even from a distance, to the alarm of the many cultivators before them.

A silhouette leaked through the flames, followed by a thunderous voice that shook the very air nearby, “I am the Fire Rite Tribe’s Great Sage Ku Yao. Since you’ve arrived, you must be planning to first test our skills. How do you intend to have a competition? One on one? Or a melee?”

The bald man glared at the fireball and icily replied, “One on one. May the Heavens decide who survives.”

Ku Yao wildly laughed from within the fireball, “Good, that’s just what I wanted. I will be the first of your opponents. Prepare someone to come forward.”

The cultivators were furious by this, but Old Man Ma was particularly sullen. With an expression filled with killing intent, his body transformed into a streak of white light and he flew forward. The bald man hesitated for a moment, but he didn’t stop the old man and silently allowed him to be the first to battle.

From his point of view, he had no idea who amongst them possessed the greatest strength. Of course, he hadn’t considered Han Li, who had just recently entered Nascent Soul stage.

When Ku Yao saw the streak of white light fly forward, he silently flew back and Old Man Ma followed until they were at the center between the spell warrior army and the green mist. In this manner, both of them would be able to act without any need to hold back or fear of a sudden ambush from either side.

The bald man turned to look at the horse-faced cultivator and solemnly asked, “What are the abilities of this Moulan Sage? Does he have any particular techniques?”

A trace of resentment appeared on his face as he answered, “His fire attribute techniques are incredibly powerful. The flame python on his body is particularly nimble as well — it is difficult to defend against. A fellow Core Formation guard of Sky Terrace Valley had been turned to ashes by that python after being caught.”

“Oh, it was like that!” The bald man then turned to the side and doubtfully said, “Brother Gu, if I remember correctly, the Grand Pavilion’s Grand Righteousness Arts is impervious to heat and flame, not to mention ghosts and wickedness. He should have an advantage against this spell warrior.”

With a hesitant expression in his eyes, Gu Shuangpu slowly said, “It’s hard to say. If they’re common fire attribute techniques, the Grand Righteousness Arts would be able to deal with them without a problem. But if it’s against a spell warrior’s techniques that display the three essences of worldly spirit flames, I fear it would be beyond the scope of the Grand Righteousness Arts.

Regardless, Fellow Daoist Ma is still the most suitable among us to fight this person. Even if his Grand Righteous Arts are unable to suppress the flames, they should be able to withstand the devilish influence of the flames. There won’t be any worry of inner demon backlash.”

When the bald man heard this, he felt his thoughts were certain and he relaxed for a moment before breathing out a long sigh.

Han Li glanced at the fire python that laid within the huge fireball and he felt his heart stir. With blue light flickering from his eyes, an odd expression was momentarily betrayed from his face.

At that moment, Old Man Ma held his hands together in an incantation gesture and a layer of soft white light began to glow from his body. At that same moment, he opened his mouth and spat out a silver speck of light the size of a walnut. In a large gust of wind, the silver light transformed into a ruler. It trembled for a moment before flickering with a thousand silver lights and releasing a cry similar to the holiest phoenix of the highest heavens.

Rather than act, Ku Yao remained still and indifferently glanced at the old man with folded arms with a sneer on his face. This display had inspired fury in Old Man Ma, and he coldly snorted before deciding to take the initiative to attack.

At that moment, he suddenly heard a faint voice transmission in his ear, so faint it was nearly inaudible but clear nonetheless. Old Man Ma was alarmed by what he heard, and he bewilderedly glanced around before his gaze fell onto Han Li.

Han Li gently smiled at the old man in response. With both amazement and doubt in mind, he turned his gaze back to Ku Yao and his expression sank.

Old Man Ma’s gaze flickered several times and he sullenly said, “That fire python of yours isn’t an ordinary spirit beast!”

Ku Yao paused for a moment before sneering, “Oh? So you have some judgement after all. My fire python is formed from a worldly fire spirit. It isn’t comparable to a spirit beast in the slightest.”

His body trembled for a moment and the fire python on his body brightly shined with red light before taking to the skies. A horn suddenly emerged from the python’s head and fierce claws grew from its body, revealing its form to be a fire flood dragon with sparkling red scales. It roiled in a fierce display as it flew above Ku Yao’s head.

“Transformed fire spirit!” The bald man couldn’t help but shout from his alarm. As for Gu Shuangpu, his expression grew unsightly.

Old Man Ma felt his heart drop. His opponent’s flame techniques had reached a stage where he could refine and transform fire spirits. This wasn’t something an ordinary Nascent Soul stage spell warrior was capable of. There was going to be a fierce battle ahead of him.

With that thought, Old Man Ma erased his original plan of only using seventy percent of his strength to fight the enemy. He took a deep breath and widely swept his sleeve, summoning an item that was wrapped in a rainbow glow. It circled once around his head and stopped a meter above it.

At that moment, the cultivators below and the spell warriors in the distance both watched with curiosity. A treasure that was able to flicker with rainbow light was likely something of exceptional quality.

Han Li also glanced at this item. The item was round and slim, a meter-long faintly yellow scroll. The scroll faced Ku Yao and slowly unrolled itself as Old Man Ma began to gravely chant a incantation. As a result, the scroll revealed a drawing of an ordinary eight trigram diagram.

Old Man Ma then struck the scroll with a seemingly basic spell seal and had the scroll shine brightly, suddenly releasing astonishing fluctuations from the diagram.

When Ku Yao saw these fluctuations, he knew things were far from good and immediately pointed at the old man. The fire flood dragon floating above his head suddenly opened its mouth and spouted an unending stream of scarlet flames, instantly engulfing Old Man Ma and the eight trigram diagram in a sea of flames.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare, Lannis

Chapter 734: Heavenflash Devil Arts

When the old man saw that the scroll was in tatters, his face greatly paled. It was clearly ruined beyond use.

“What a pity!” The black-robed figure spoke with a trace of regret, “If Fellow Daoist Ku Yao hadn’t been in such a rush to break free and used his fire spirit’s vitality to stall of time, that cultivator’s magic power would’ve been exhausted and he would’ve taken the initiative to dispel the formation diagram regardless.”

The shriveled cultivator pondered for a moment before he found himself agreeing.

With the spell warrior broken free, Old Man Ma’s complexion turned sickly pale as he grasped onto the scroll. He quickly placed it away in his storage pouch, and viciously gazed at Ku Yao. Ku Yao snorted in response and had the flood dragon beneath him surge once more with flames and red light.

The shriveled spell warrior suddenly shouted from above, “Sage Ku Yao, cease!” He then turned to the Heavenly South cultivators and said, “How about ending this battle in a draw? Both of their magic power is nearly exhausted. Nothing will result from having this battle continue.”

The bald man was somewhat surprised to hear this. After exchanging a look with Gu Shuangpu, he nodded his head, “That is fine. Let’s have this battle end.”

Although Old Man Ma felt somewhat opposed this decision, he knew that it would be futile to continue the battle and flew back without any better option. Ku Yao also felt gloomy at this decision and begrudgingly recalled his flood dragon before flying back into the spell warrior ranks.

Old Man Ma returned down below and received a few consoling words from the bald man, easing the tension from the old man’s face.

But at that moment, the black-robed spell warrior and the shriveled old man was muttering something to each other. As a result, the black-robed figure gently floated in the air and arrived at the location of the previous battle.

He gloomily swept his gaze past the other cultivators and a trace of contempt was revealed from his eyes. In his hoarse voice, he said, “This time, you will be fighting me, but I will say this first. This battle will last until someone is dead. Don’t have any delusions of stopping this battle while it is in progress.”

The black-robed figure’s arrogant words infuriated Gu Shuangpu and the bald man. However, the two didn’t dare to rise up to the challenge. They both knew that two Nascent Soul cultivators have already perished at the hands of this strange spell warrior. As they still greatly valued their lives, they were hesitant.

“Let me try him on.” Han Li indifferently said.

The bald man blinked in surprise upon seeing Han Li take the initiative to fight, but soon, he inwardly sighed with relief. “Ah! Fellow Daoist Han wishes to go? You must take care. If there is something amiss, we will naturally go to rescue you.”

Han Li smiled and said little else. Azure light glowed from from his body before he streaked across the skies. In the blink of an eye, he arrived before the black-robed figure, and expressionlessly stood in the air with his hands held behind his back.

The black-robed figure appraised Han Li for a moment before his eyes began to turn from black to green in what appeared to be a monstrous display.

Han Li narrowed his eyes and asked, “Are you demon or ghost?”

“You don’t think this old man is human?” The black-figure coldly chuckled. At that same moment, inky threads of black Qi began to wrap around his body. Ghostly wails soon began to howl, followed by gusts of Yin wind.

Han Li took a short breath and calmly said, “So you were originally a man, but it seems that you’ve cultivated the Dao of a demon or ghost.”

“Humph! Junior, you speak too much rubbish. There is no need to examine me any further as you will soon die by my hand. Don’t waste your effort.” With that said, black Qi suddenly surged around his body, nearly hiding him entirely from sight.

“As I don’t have the patience to play with you, I’ll be taking your life now.” The black-robed old man sinisterly laughed and formed an incantation gesture with his hands. Suddenly, he grew to giant about six meters in height.

Although the vortex of Yin Qi surrounding him mostly blocked him out of sight, one could faintly make out two horns poking out from the robes and two fangs as well. It was no wonder so many cultivators believed this unfamiliar spell warrior was a transformed oddity.

Han Li’s eyes shined with blue light, revealing the huge man’s ferocious appearance.

“What?” Han Li was shocked by the demonic appearance of the huge man. His current appearance was exactly the same as the one of the phantoms of the Six Apex Devils he encountered when he fought the disciple of Archsaint Six Paths.

[1]

“What relation does your esteemed self have with Archsaint Six Paths?”

The huge man evilly grinned after a moment of surprise. “Who is this Archsaint Six Paths? Don’t think that your nonsense will allow you to stall for time. Accept your death!” He then raised his hand and scattered some of the black Qi, suddenly shooting a black object towards Han Li. However, the object flashed with black light as soon as it left the cover of the black Qi and disappeared from sight.

Han Li’s expression sank and suddenly shot back ten meters. At that same moment, a huge ghost claw appeared where he was originally standing. The attack was so sudden, it seemed to have materialized out of thin air.

“Yi!” The huge demonic figure yelped in surprise at seeing his attack miss.

Han Li stared at the ghost hand and indifferently said, “Not bad at all. Although you aren’t a ghost Dao cultivator — as you cultivate Devil Dao techniques — your methods of attack are quite similar to ghost cultivators. If one were to truly regard you as a ghost cultivator, they would definitely suffer.”

The large demonic man stayed still as it coldly glanced at Han Li.

At that same moment, Han Li frowned and he moved about ten meters to the side in a blur. As a result, yet another green ghost claw had silently struck where he once stood.

The huge man was no longer able to keep his calm after missing a second time and asked, “Since you’ve already dodged two of my attacks, could it be that you’d seen other ghost cultivators in the past?”

“Of course I have. How else could I have so easily dodged your attacks?” Han Li replied smilingly with a half-truth.

“Humph! Your esteemed self is actually a vastly experienced individual. Regardless, even if you know that I use Devil Dao techniques, what will come of it? With the might of the Heavenflash Devil Arts, you will be dead in only a moment.” The huge man spoke sinisterly. He then abruptly released an intense, ear-piercing whistle that was capable of even splitting stone.

When Han Li saw this, his calm expression turned stern.

The black Qi enveloping the huge man began to rapidly revolve in place. Soon after, an astonishingly powerful wave of devilish Qi suddenly erupted out of thin air, and the huge man shot out from the black Qi, instantly arriving before Han Li as he left afterimages in his wake.

With a slight movement of his arms, an impenetrable flurry of black-green claws immediately surrounded him. It seemed that he intended to use his claws to cut Han Li into countless pieces.

Han Li took a deep breath and wore an odd expression as he remained in place. He slapped his hands together before spreading them out, summoning a net of golden lightning around him. With thunder ringing in the air, Han Li glanced at the claws around him with complete fearlessness.

Without any further thought, the huge black figure then ordered the claws to strike Han Li without mercy.

From the huge black figure’s point of view, common devilish arts might be subdued by lightning attribute techniques, but the Heavenflash Devil Arts is by no measure common. It wouldn’t be stopped by some trifling lightning. However, the cultivator he faced seemed to know quite a bit, much to his unease; he felt it best to immediately dispose of him.

But before the black figure finished his thoughts, he suddenly felt his own claws grow hot, soon followed by an unimaginable pain. Golden light then brightly chined from before him. The golden lightning net had actually broken through the claw phantoms and was making its way to envelop him.

Unable to protect himself from behind and trapped by the net of golden lightning, a legend he once heard suddenly appeared in his mind. In the past when he was learning of this devilish art, his master had repeated warned him of the greatest nemeses of the Heavenflash Devil Arts. But because he had never encountered any equal opponents after cultivating this devilish art, he had forgotten about this matter!

“Golden lightning? It can’t be! It’s so similar. Don’t tell me —” The black figure’s expression grew completely tense and he felt his heart drop. Unwilling to remain idle in the oncoming danger, he immediately howled and had his tall stature suddenly shrink in size, becoming a dwarf that was only a meter tall, buying him more time before the golden net struck him.

In that time that he bought, his shrunken body suddenly fluctuated in size before hastily erupting into countless threads of black light — scattering in every direction.

[1]. The Six Apex devils appeared in Chapter 573: Yin Devil Execution vs the Six Apex Devils.

[Back]

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Lannis

Chapter 740: Battle to Break the Formation (2)

The bald man sighed. “I didn’t think the Moulan would be so careful. Although we killed a few of their spell warriors, we didn’t do much to harm their strength. We now can only use force against force. Brother Ma, how is your magic power holding up? You used the Concealing Heaven Flags to cover half of the mountaintop.”

Old Man Ma twirled his beard and casually said, “With the magic power I have left, I won’t be able to defeat the enemy, but I should have no problem distracting a Moulan Sage.”

The bald man solemnly said, “That’s fine. Leave the rest of the enemies for me and Fellow Daoist Han to deal with. Fellow Daoist Bu has also restored a bit of his strength. I’ve already instructed his subordinates to call for him if the situation turns dire.”

Old Man Ma used his spiritual sense to view the tremendous beast outside of the formation and wore a worried expression. “That is also fine. However, I fear that huge beast will be troublesome to deal with. We cannot afford to be distracted and I suspect our Core Formation cultivators will not be able to deal with it.”

The bald man sighed. “There is nothing we can do about the matter. We are truly lacking people. But with the Murong Brothers watching over the formation, they will be able to provide further assistance. As Core Formation cultivators that cultivate lightning techniques, they’re considerably hard to kill and should prove somewhat effective even against the beast’s rough hide.” His tone lacked confidence, having heard of the beast’s fearsomeness from a few of the defeated cultivators.

Old Man Ma nodded with a worried appearance. “That is all we’ll be able to do in advance.”

At that moment, azure light flashed from the green mist and flew around the two.

The light faded away to reveal Han Li. He smiled at the two and asked, “Fellow Daoists, it seems the Moulan are about to attack. Do you have any good plans to withstand them?”

The bald man smiled. “It is good that Brother Han has come. We were just discussing this. Preparations...” He repeated his previous plan to Han Li.

Han Li frowned for a moment before relaxing his brow, “That gigantic beast will be troublesome. This strange breed should’ve only existed during ancient times. Just how did the Moulan acquire them? Anyhow, let us do as Fellow Daoist Lu says.”

The bald man chuckled and respectfully said, “For this coming battle, we will be relying much on Brother Han’s abilities.”

Han Li stroked his nose and calmly said, “Since this matter concerns the safety of the entire Heavenly South, I naturally must strive my hardest. However, the enemy forces are truly powerful. My spirit may be willing, but my body might be too weak!”

Old Man Ma smiled and respectfully said, “If even Brother Han cannot match them, let alone us, the same could be said about the others in the alliance.”

Han Li glanced at Old Man Ma and mysteriously smiled. “Brother Ma truly overestimates me. My abilities aren’t nearly as great as you two think they are. Please don’t set your expectations too highly.”

Wishing also to deepen his friendship, the bald man chuckled and said, “Regardless of how it is said, Brother Han is by no means a common early Nascent Soul cultivator. Your abilities are far beyond ours. For this coming battle— Yi! The Moulan have begun their assault.” He quickly turned his gaze towards the instant.

Han Li and Old Man Ma quickly glanced around in alarm.

Red lights suddenly glowed in the direction of the spell warriors army. A cloud of red flame suddenly filled the sky with several tens of scorching miniature suns gathering within it.

Being the first time he had seen such a thing, Old Man Ma shouted in alarm, “What’s this?!”

The bald man sullenly explained, “This is a spell warrior spirit technique formation. With a large number of spell warriors taking the place of formation flags and plates, they are able to quickly form a spell formation spirit technique. However, a high grade spell warrior is needed to oversee the formation. From the huge fireballs, it is likely being controlled by the fire attribute spell warrior from yesterday.”

“Spirit technique formation?” Old Man Ma muttered to himself in astonishment. Although he wished to further ask about the details, he knew now was not the appropriate time and kept silent.

Han Li withdrew his gaze and calmly said, “Let us all enter the formation and act with discretion. Before we fight with the Nascent Soul-stage spell warriors, let us kill as many low grade spell warriors as possible.”

“Good!” Neither of the two offered any objections.

The bald man called for several of the other Core Formation cultivators and gave them each their instructions, all of them entering the green mist one after another, with Yingning among them. Of course, Han Li gave her a few words of warning via voice transmission before promptly disappearing from the mist.

At that moment, a portion of the spell warriors were organized into groups of several tens, each of them arranged in a profound and wondrous spell formation. They all raised a sparkling fire-red magic tool over their heads as they gathered around the fire Qi and conducted the formation.

Several tens of huge fireballs floated hundreds of meters above them, as they surged with broiling heat. The spell warriors underneath were roasting — each of their mouths parched, their vision blurry, their bodies trembling as they bitterly supported the spirit technique formation.

At the very center of the formation of tens of fireballs, Ku Yao was sitting cross-legged with disheveled hair as six huge red banners slowly revolved around him. He remained completely motionless while his hands formed a strange incantation gesture. As for the three-meter-long fire python, it spiralled around his head while its body shined with brilliant red light, stirring clouds of fire around it.

Not far away, the green robed woman had dismounted from the huge beast and was coldly staring at Ku Yao’s actions. As for the shriveled spell warrior, he was further behind them and was glancing at them with concern.

Ku Yao suddenly opened his eyes and shouted, “Go!” The six banners around him simultaneously erupted into pillars of scarlet light. At that same moment, six fireballs that spanned over forty meters in length appeared in the air.

Suddenly, the pillars of scarlet light were completely absorbed by the six fireballs, and they began to tremble for a moment before spurting out flames that were three meters tall. Then as the war drums continued to beat, the fireballs shot towards the sea of green mist like huge meteors in a single line as if wishing to forcefully open a passage through the mist.

The combined casting of these many spell warriors had condensed fireballs of extraordinary might.

As meticulously placed as the green mist grand formation may have been by the Nine Nations Union formation experts, these meteors of flame caused an earth-shattering explosion as soon as they touched the green mist. With several successive bursts of hundred meter tall flames accompanying each explosion, the green mist was scattered by the wild flaming winds that soon followed, wiping them entirely away in an instant.

Although green and yellow formation lights still shined, they were clearly outmatched and weren’t able to withstand the assault in the slightest. In the blink of an eye, six huge areas were completely devoid of mist from within the formation.

A cold glint flickered from the green-robed woman’s eyes and she flipped her hand, summoning a golden circle in her hand. She then raised it in the air and it flew down to the Giant Rhino, which was already positioned at the edge of the sea of green mist.

With a loud ring, the golden circle fell onto the blue horn of the Giant Rhino and tightened in an instant. The huge horn was then sheathed and began to sparkled with dazzling light.

Perhaps spurred by the blinding golden light or some action by the green-robed woman, the Giant Rhino’s eyes quickly turned blood red and it released thunderous roars. As it treaded on the blue clouds underneath it, it wildly rushed down towards the green mist.

A short moment later, the beast’s roars filled the air as yellow and green light brightly glowed.

“Let’s go in. Sage Ku Yao will continue to use fire spirit techniques and destroy the restrictions. We will bring this formation down.” The green-robed woman’s clear voice spread throughout the sky. The spell warriors on standby cheered upon receiving their orders and they began to enter the green mist while in groups ranging from five to ten.

The green-robed woman indifferently said, “Let’s also head in. Once Sage Ku Yao finishes casting the technique, he will follow after us.” She then glowed with white light and flew down in a streak of light. The shriveled spell warrior hastily agreed before following after her in a trail of black light.

A short moment later, there were only several hundred spell warriors that had yet to enter the restriction.

At that moment, the remaining fireballs were being absorbed by the six banner of flames surrounding Ku Yao. They then fell onto the sea of mist in an arrangement of lines at the same location as the previous six meteors, causing several tens of pillars of flames to erupt, nearly breaking apart the entirety of the restriction.

With wild roars of laughter, Ku Yao suddenly stood up and waved to the spell warriors around him. Then he wordlessly flew down towards the mist of sea in a ball of scorching flame. When the other spell warriors in the formation saw this, they flocked after him.

At that moment, there were over a thousand spell warriors in total inside the formation, not to mention the several hundred hidden spell warriors that were controlling the formation’s restrictions from within.

Han Li floated motionlessly inside the mist with his eyes closed. His body was already enveloped in armor composed of the black-tainted Gold Devouring Beetles, and he was standing on a huge azure sword. Above him floated silent, three-meter-long swarms of sparkling golden beetles.They each appeared extremely malicious and blood-thirsty as if just waiting for their first opportunity to kill.

Han Li blinked several times and he slowly opened his eyes; his face wearing a trace of astonishment.

“As expected, there was a mid Nascent Soul-stage Sage amongst them, but to think that it’d be a female spell warrior.” Han Li muttered to himself. After a moment more of thought, he slapped his storage pouch and summoned a set of formation tools in his hands.

Han Li’s figure blurred as he quickly placed down the mightiest spell formation he could place on such short notice.

Han Li swept his sleeve and commanded, “Silvermoon, come out.”

A small fox then flew out of his sleeve and landed in front of him. Han Li continued, “I will be giving you the Purple Cloudlace, and the flower basket as well. The opponent this time seems to be even more troublesome than Wan’er’s senior martial sister. Be careful! If her abilities are truly too fearsome, we won’t need to strain ourselves. Let’s lure her here and use the green mist restrictions as well as my spell formation to even the odds. If that won’t do, then we will simply escape. There is no need for us to stake it all.”

He then summoned the Purple Cloudlace and the flower basket into his hand before tossing it to the small white fox.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Lannis, Vare

Chapter 741: Battle to Break the Formation(3)

“Yes, Master. In that case, I will act the same as last time and stay hidden as I bide my time for an appropriate time to act.”

Han Li nodded. “That will do. Last time you acted at a very decisive moment, to much effect.”

“Many thanks for Master’s praise. This servant shall strive her hardest.” After placing away the two treasures, she smiled and disappeared from sight in a flash of silver light.

Han Li then turned to look at the distance, a stern expression appearing on his face. In a burst of azure light, he flew deep into the mist.

Not long after the spell warriors entered the mist, the remnant restrictions within it began to stir, repeatedly endangering them. Fortunately for a majority of the spell warriors, the giant rhino was clearing a path, brushing aside the restrictions without care.

Regardless whether they be fireballs, lightning, ice spikes, or boulders of earth, they didn’t harm the huge beast in the slightest. Its jet-black armor easily brushed off any of the attacks.

Paying no heed to any of the attacks, the huge rhino straightforwardly lowered its head and rushed forward. Any restrictions or obstructions that barred its path were struck through as if the beast’s body carried the momentum of a shooting star. Its destructive force cleared the mist of an area of over a hundred meters around it. As for the many spell warriors following after it, not a single one of them were harmed.

However, it was quite baffling that within the group of spell warriors, those with the greatest cultivation were the four at Core Formation stage. There wasn’t a single Nascent Soul-stage sage amongst them. It was unknown where the three Nascent Soul sages went after they entered the green mist, nor what strange plot they had in store.

When these spell warriors saw that the area was clear of the mist, they sighed with relief. The Core Formation-stage spell warriors even gathered together to discuss their next course of action. But at that moment, two sparkling silver halberds suddenly shot out of the mist, leaving thunder in their wake as they arced with lightning.

Shocked with alarm, two of the Core Formation-stage spell warriors acted first. They immediately raised their hands and released a blue and red streak of light directly towards the halberds in an attempt to block them. But who could’ve thought that instead of directly confronting the spell warrior’s magic treasures, they changed direction and quickly shot towards the giant rhino’s head.

Although this had greatly surprised the Core Formation spell warriors, they soon grew relieved. The giant rhino’s defenses weren’t something that could be penetrated with ordinary magic treasures.

But soon, an astonishing scene had occurred before them. The two silver halberds didn’t directly strike at the giant rhino, but instead, they flew above the beast and began to strike each other without warning. Then a huge roll of thunder sounded out as a dense bolt of lightning shot from the two halberds towards the head of the huge beast.

A blue light barrier shined from the beast’s body, but it was completely scattered by the bolt of silver lightning and directly struck the jet-black armor. With a loud rumble and a flash of lightning, the giant rhino stood in place unscathed. However, the beast was enraged by the attack and loudly roared to the skies before opening its mouth and shooting out a three-meter-long spike of ice towards the silver halberds above it.

Making no attempt to stand their ground, the halberds dodged away from the ice spike before releasing another silver bolt of lightning and flying back into the mist. When the huge beast saw this, its eyes grew crimson and it chased them down without a further thought.

The Core Formation spell warriors were alarmed and hastily called out to the other spell warriors behind them, each of them intending to give chase to the huge rhino. But before they took action, various colored lights appeared from the mist, revealing over a hundred cultivators that had emerged from concealment. Then, they launched a massive assault against the Moulan spell warriors as they released their magic tools into the air.

In furious alarm, the Moulan spell warriors also sent out their magic tools and unleashed their spirit techniques, sowing chaos amongst the cultivators. With that delay, the giant rhino had already disappeared into the mist.

The Core Formation-stage spell warriors were unable to deal with this as they were locked into battle against many cultivators at a similar cultivation.

In their rage, they thought to call to the spell warriors behind them to assist them and completely wipe out the cultivations, but suddenly, the cultivators had recalled their magic tools and flew back into the mist. When the spell warriors saw this, they glanced at each other with dismay and hesitation, not knowing what they should do next.

A late Core Formation-stage old man, the leader of the bunch, pondered for a moment before calmly commanding, “We will split our vast numbers and take action separately. A majority of the restrictions nearby should’ve already been destroyed. So long as we are careful, it shouldn’t pose much of a problem. Since they’re using guerilla tactics, they shouldn’t be able to withstand a full fledge pursuit and will be smoothly exterminated.”

As for the giant rhino, the Core Formation cultivators shouldn’t be able to harm it. We will find the beast after we kill them.”

Then taking the lead, the old man flew into the mist pursuing a Core Formation cultivator that had fled in that direction. Soon, the other spell warriors obeyed and chaotically scattered into the mist in their own groups.

The thick mist roiled for a moment before soon growing calm, with not a single person in sight. But a short moment later, a silhouette walked out of the green mist with a calm expression and with his hands held behind his back. He was Old Man Ma. Though his complexion was somewhat pale, his eyes shined spiritedly as if he were in peak condition.

He walked out to the center of the empty area and he glanced around before suddenly revealing an odd expression. He then stared at an empty location and calmly said, “Since I’ve already come out, there is no need for Fellow Daoist to continue hiding. Your techniques won’t be able to hide you from me.”

With a cold snort, the black light flashed to reveal the tall shriveled spell warrior. “I didn’t expect that your spiritual sense would still be so strong. I originally planned on giving you a pleasant surprise, but it seems things don’t always go as planned.”

As soon as he appeared, he twisted his hands and raised them towards Old Man Ma. In the following instant, several tens of thumb-thick black streaks shot out in a barrage towards the old man.

...

About a kilometer away from Old Man Ma and the shriveled spell warrior, the bald man was expressionlessly staring at a man across from him, Ku Yao, who was enveloped in a ball of roasting flame.

The blaze emitting from his body was so fierce that it turned the nearby mist to ash, creating clear air for a hundred meters around him.

Ku Yao originally planned on ambushing Old Man Ma from behind and attacking him together with the shriveled spell warrior. However, he didn’t expect that he would be blocked by the bald man along the way, much to his fury. He snorted and said, “You think that you’ll be able to save your companion by blocking me? Sage Wen’s spirit techniques are ferocious beyond your imagination.”

The bald man remained still as he narrowed his eyes, “Rather than paying attention on others, wouldn’t it be better if you were focusing on preserving your own life? While Fellow Daoist Ma didn’t recover his strength from yesterday’s battle, you must’ve exhausted much of your power as well. And with the addition of the great amount of strength needed to direct the spirit technique formation, you are in rather poor shape. Unless you have a heaven-defying treasure to assist you...”

He then opened his mouth and spat out a short white rod. It circled once around his body before suddenly emitting a blinding white light with a tremble. When Ku Yao saw this, his face revealed disdain. But just as he thought to launch his own attack, his expression vastly changed.

The color of the light had suddenly changed, and the white light gradually turned golden. At that same moment, a huge golden ape began to form above the short rod.

Although its stature wasn’t as excessive as the giant rhino, it was twenty meters tall. Under closer inspection, the ape had four hairy ears and appeared extremely ugly and fiendish. As soon as it had appeared it thumped its chest and howled to the sky before glaring at Ku Yao across from it.

“Artifact spirit! Your magic treasure has an artifact spirit!” When Ku Yao saw this, he cried out in alarm.

Killing intent leaking from his face, the bald man formed an incantation gesture with his hand. “Hehe! You are the first to witness my Four-Eared Golden Ape artifact spirit. You shouldn’t feel too wronged to meet your end by this.”

The huge ape’s body became more distinct and soon, the short rod grew to a hundred meters in length. Now appearing as a true demon bast, it grabbed onto the extended rod and fiercely pouched towards Ku Yao with golden light emitting from its body.

...

The green-robed woman was neither together with the shriveled spell warrior or Ku Yao. Her objective was quite simple. Using her own abilities, she would directly approach the heart of the grand formation and shatter it. With the crux of the formation shattered, the rest would soon follow. Of course, she planned to dispose of a certain cultivator along the way.

Ever since she entered the mist, she clearly sensed a faint sliver of spiritual sense coil around her. Even with her vastly powerful spiritual sense, she was unable to block it. While this did cause the woman’s heart to tremble, her desire to slay the Nascent Soul youth only grew stronger.

If she didn’t eliminate this vastly skilled cultivator, it was quite possible that he could cause great mishaps in the future. Fortunately, this cultivator seemed rather confident of his abilities and didn’t conceal himself in the slightest, wishing to draw her in, a mid Nascent Soul-stage spell warrior. She met the challenge with a sneer and directly flew towards him.

When she sensed the youth was only three hundred meters within range, the green-robed woman’s body ceased emitting white light and her flight speed slowed before coming to a full stop. Although she was confident in her own abilities, she wasn’t clear whether or not she was walking into a trap. She then slapped her storage pouch and summoned a fist-sized azure pearl into her hand.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare, Lannis

Chapter 747: Reputation Rising

Silvermoon worriedly muttered, “Then how about Master use Bloodshadow Evasion? In a single use, you’ll be able to traverse over fifty kilometers. Surely you’ll be able to break free of his spiritual sense tracking.” Although Silvermoon hadn’t mentioned anything about Han Li saving her life, she was touched by it nonetheless, causing her tone to feel particularly concerned.

Having already considered the matter, Han Li wryly smiled and said, “A single use won’t be enough. I’ll have to use the Bloodshadow Evasion at least two times in succession — perhaps even three — and exhaust all my remaining Divine Devilbane Lightning for a good chance at escaping. Although my magic power is slightly greater than ordinary early Nascent Soul-stage cultivators, it is still quite dangerous. Even if I come out unscathed, I will be weakened for quite a long while. Now that no other methods will work, this is the only option left.”

“Master, you—”

Han Li’s expression suddenly changed and he turned his head to look behind him and gloomily snorted. “That person is growing closer by the second. I can no longer continue like this. I can only take the risk!”

When Silvermoon heard this, she chose to keep silent.

Soon after, Han Li deeply sighed and his hands quickly blurred as they formed a series of strange incantation gestures. At the same time, his body began to pulse with azure light and an astonishing spiritual pressure was suddenly released from his body. He then spat a mist of scarlet blood essence from his mouth that scattered in the air and seeped into the azure light surrounding his body, transforming it into a demonic fusion of crimson and azure light.

Soon, Han Li’s hands and face became dark-red, and countless threads of crimson blood began to spurt from all over his skin, making for a frightful sight. Han Li didn’t seem to mind this in the least and continued forming hand incantations at great speed. Spitting out another two mouthfuls of blood essence, Han Li became completely enveloped in a mist of blood and could hardly be seen.

At that moment, a bright light began to shine from the distant sky and three silver balls of light were slowly moving towards him. Silhouettes could be seen moving from within the light balls. They were Divine Sage Zhong and his two incarnations. Their scholar robes fluttered as they calmly flew in Han Li’s direction, however, they moved at an incredible speed in spite of their appearances. In an instant, they had already traversed a distance of over four hundred meters and could see Han Li with the naked eye.

“Yi!” One of the men wore a surprised expression, but he soon frowned.

The azure-crimson blood mist suddenly burst with a dazzling crimson light. As Han Li stood in place, he coldly glanced at the incoming Moulan Divine Sage before unfolding the Thunderstorm Wings behind his back. In the following moment, space itself warped around him, and Han Li’s figure blurred from sight.

A sharp ear-piercing shriek faded into the distance as suddenly as it had appeared.

The three scholarly men simultaneously wore a face of astonishment and the three glanced at one another before the outer two joined together with the man at the center. With a flash of silver light, the three men then returned into one. He immediately shut his eyes and released his spiritual sense in the direction the shriek had traveled in.

The scholarly man glanced where Han Li had disappeared and revealed a trace of surprise. “What kind of movement technique can travel fifty kilometers in an instant? It seems similar to the Devil Dao’s blood movement, but the distance is astonishing.”

Having chased Han Li for several days, the Divine Sage had experienced quite a bit of surprise at having continuously pursued him for several days without rest.

Even if an early Nascent Soul cultivator was capable of lightning movement, their magic power should’ve long been exhausted, leaving them helpless to their fates — unless one possessed a heavenly treasure capable of instantly restoring one’s magic power, or a secret technique that drained from one’s vitality. Now that Han Li had employed a strange movement technique, it appeared he hadn’t shown his full strength before this.

But this was no matter, although he had already traveled fifty kilometers, Divine Sage Zhong was still tracking him with his spiritual sense. It would only be some more time before he caught up.

Just as the scholarly man thought through this, he narrowed his eyes and his spiritual sense targeted Han Li once more. With a cold smirk, his body glowed with white light before setting off once more to give chase. But at that moment, the scholarly man suddenly felt Han Li’s aura mysteriously disappear once more. He ceased his movements in shock.

He suddenly thought of something and hastily expanded the perimeter of his spiritual sense by twofold before spotting Han Li once more. Yet before he could set off once more, Han Li’s aura disappeared yet again. This time, the scholarly man simply stood in place with a face of amazement.

Although his spiritual sense was vastly powerful, it could only reach a distance of a little over a hundred kilometers. He could forcibly stretch his spiritual sense to acquire an approximate understanding of the environment, but it was beyond him to track someone at that distance. Of course, unless something impossible occurred — like Han Li waiting in place for him to sweep his spiritual sense past him — he had now lost Han Li’s trail.

Han Li was a truly cunning opponent. The moment he felt the Divine Sage’s spiritual sense speed past him, he employed that strange movement technique several times in succession and slipped away. This was perhaps the first time in many years since the scholarly man had ever been played around with in this manner.

He was a magnificent Moulan Divine Sage. Once it became known that an early Nascent Soul cultivator was able to escape him, his reputation would be greatly tarnished. However, he didn’t have any intention to immediately continue the chase. Without any spiritual sense tracking along with Han Li’s strange techniques, it would be difficult to track Han Li down again — even with the use of secret techniques. Not to mention that he had already wasted several days chasing Han Li down. He couldn’t continue the pursuit, especially given the uncertainty of success.

After all, since he — a Divine Sage — had made an appearance, the other late Nascent Soul-stage cultivators in the Heavenly South could no longer remain idle. He needed to return and join with the other Moulan Divine Sages in preparation. If they were jointly attacked by enemy late Nascent Soul-stage cultivators, it would be extremely dangerous.

After pondering for a long while with a restless state of mind, his face grew sullen and he flew back in the direction from whence he came. In a blink of silver light, he disappeared from sight.

In an area a hundred-fifty kilometers away, Han Li was flying through the sky in a streak of azure light in a different direction from before. He was continuously taking out medicine bottles from all over his body and pouring whatever vitality healing medicine he had down his throat. His complexion was deathly pale and his eyes were listless.

Silvermoon’s voice echoed through Han Li’s mind, “Master, are you alright? Using the Bloodshadow Evasion three times in succession was truly dangerous. Were it not for the many medicine pills master had taken along the way, the third use of the technique would’ve...”

“It’s nothing. Although I’ve lost a large amount of blood essence, fortunately, I refined a few medicine pills in the past. So long as I consume them and properly rest for a few months, my cultivation should be fully restored.” Han Li slowly replied with an exhausted voice.

Having heard this, Silvermoon sighed and hesitantly asked, “Will you be returning to Soaring Heavens City?”

With a tone of helplessness, Han Li said, “Of course not. With a situation this dire, I must at least restore my cultivation before heading back to the Nine Nations Union. Otherwise, the Ghost Spirit Sect and whatever other enemies I have will be able to easily plot against me. I cannot brave such risks. Fortunately, I don’t need to seek out an area with spirit veins, given the efficacy of the medicine pills alone. I simply need to find an uninhabited area and rest for a while. Furthermore, the Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords are still tainted by the azure lantern flames. Although I’ve used the Purple Apex Flames to forcibly restrain them, I must think of a method to remove the azure flames entirely or there will be consequences later.”

Silvermoon smiled and said, “That bronze lantern was a lineage treasure belonging to the Moulan Tribes, so it should have some closeness to the Ghost Dao. This servant is confident that so long as Master spends some time, he will be able to refine those flames entirely. Regardless of what is said, the Purple Apex Flames possess truly remarkable abilities.”

Han Li bitterly smiled and calmly replied, “With how things played out in the end, these problems can only be solved slowly.” Afterwards, Han Li spoke no more and used the remaining spiritual power in his body to urge the light around him to fly faster.

After flying for a day, Han Li ceased his flight and dropped down into an unremarkable valley. The Moulan Divine Sage should be unwilling to search this far away.

He glanced around several times and found two suitable barren hills. Not only were they completely lacking any spiritual power, but they were also completely bare and inseparable from the other hills in the area.

Han Li cautiously swept his spiritual sense past a fifty kilometer radius. Finding that there were no cultivators or spell warriors nearby, he felt safe and released Silvermoon.

The small silver fox then obeyed Han Li’s orders without any objections and twirled around, sweeping a yellow light around her and enveloping Han Li within it. In a flash of light, she brought Han Li directly with her into the side of the hill.

The valley became desolate once more.

With Han Li brought to the center of the mountain through Silvermoon’s earth movement technique, azure sword Qi was shot out in a dense barrage, quickly carving out a crude, ten-meter-wide room. In a blur, Han Li entered it and promptly sat down cross-legged.

Not long after, Han Li opened his eyes and azure light began to revolve around him. Over ten medicine bottles of various sizes lay before him. He needed to first refine the medicine pills he had taken before he dared to take any more medicine. As such, he calmly secluded himself as he restored his vitality.

However, Han Li didn’t anticipate that the damage to his vitality would be far greater than he had predicted and the amount of time he would need to recover would be much longer. As time dryly passed by, he meditated and focused on recovering with the aid of medicine pills. After around half a year slowly passed by, Han Li still remained within the center of the mountain. However, countless changes began to surge around the world with battle to the death between cultivators and spell warriors just over the horizon.

And beyond Han Li’s knowledge, his fame as the Drifting Cloud Sect’s Elder Han had spread widely not only throughout the cultivators of the Heavenly South, but also through the ranks of the spell warriors. Whenever they heard of his name, none dared to hold him in contempt. His repute of matching a mid Nascent Soul-stage cultivator was already well known.

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Boring

PR: Vare & Lannis

Chapter 748: Return

Ever since the battle at the Yellow Dragon Mountains, the three Moulan Sages had taken the initiative to lead the war effort. In only half a month, they had already managed to push all the way towards Soaring Heavens City.

Caught unprepared, the Nine Nations Union could only stand alone against the incoming enemies.

Fortunately, the grand elder of the Nine Nations Union, Wei Wuya — one of the three great cultivators in the Heavenly South — had recently received word to hurry to the city. Relying on the city’s grand formation, he was able to support it for an entire month against the spell warriors armies.

However, the city faced the combined might of three Divine Sages, a few black-robed cultivators, and eight giant beasts. As such, it didn’t take long for the grand formation to be destroyed and for Soaring Heavens City to fall to the hands of spell warriors. But fortunately for the Nine Nations Union, a majority of their forces in the city had already withdrew to the neighboring countries of Yu and Beiliang.

At that time, reinforcements from the Righteous and Devil Dao as well as those from the Heavenly Dao Alliance had arrived.

With the four united superpowers of the Heavenly South, they managed to temporarily hold back the Moulan vanguard after a few small scale battles. However, it was clear that none of these battles were a true battle to the death.

Once Soaring Heavens City was seized by the Moulan, it immediately became the first stronghold in the Heavenly South for the spell warriors. An unending stream of Moulan spell warriors began to stream in from the Moulan Plains in great number.

Each of the Moulan tribes sent their elite to the other tribes in hopes they would be able to occupy the Heavenly South, apart from the greatest Moulan Tribe — the Golden Sun Tribe who were occupied with monitoring the movements of the Soaring Tribes in the Moulan Plains.

Once the Moulan finished gathering together, they would begin conducting battles to the death.

Of course, the Heavenly South wasn’t about to accept this occupation without resistance.

In addition to the forces of the four superpowers, unaffiliated sects also sent men and even a few vagrant cultivators participated in the war effort, all knowing just how important the coming battle was. Even the various clans in the Heavenly South took the initiative to send their own forces to support the war.

With these forces taking in, the four superpowers immediately moved towards the border of the the State of Beiliang and the State of Yu. Through the use of grand techniques, they were able to construct a huge stone city overnight, treating it as a fortress to resist the spell warriors advance.

During that time, they also made arrangements for the various sect and vagrant cultivators in their armies so that they may drive away the Moulan from the Heavenly South in a single move.

Like the calm before the storm, battles between both sides ceased, and they made use of this opportunity for further preparations.

And during this time, Han Li’s feats during his time at the Yellow Dragon Mountains had already begun to spread.

Of course, he couldn’t have known that in addition to himself, Old Man Ma had also survived from the battle that day. However, in the face of the green-robed woman’s wind movement techniques, he could only abandon his mortal body and flee back to the Nine Nations Union only with his Nascent Soul.

As for Core Formation cultivators, Yingning and the Murong Brothers had both survived. Once they saw the battle was lost, they all took the initiative to flee.

With these survivors, Han Li’s feat of killing the black-robed Nascent Soul cultivator in an instant became known by others, and his reputation soared!

As for the Controlling Spirit Sect spy— Gu Shuangpu — his true identity was only known by a select few high grade cultivators amongst the superpowers. It was not widely spread.

Of course, what truly made Han Li’s reputation soar was the news that he managed to escape from the grasp of a Moulan Divine Sage. When Divine Sage Zhong had returned to the spell warrior army, his failure to kill Han Li had caused quite a commotion amongst the spell warriors.

The scholarly man as a result had given Han Li a very high assessment in order to save face and avoid embarrassment, rating his abilities slightly beyond that of a mid Nascent Soul-stage cultivator.

Naturally, none doubted the assessment of a Divine Sage.

With the addition of the many abilities Han Li displayed in his battle with the green-robed woman surnamed Le, and his earlier victory over the Heavenly Wind Tribe’s Sage Mu — resulting in the destruction of his physical body, his repute amongst the spell warrior armies were even greater than those of the Heavenly South cultivators.

Of course, this information eventually made its way to the Heavenly South and had caused quite a ruckus as well.

Needless to say, many other obscure Nascent Soul cultivators had also made a name for themselves in that way. After all, a cultivator’s true abilities could only be truly measured in battle.

Eventually, over half a year had passed, and Han Li had finally emerged from his seclusion in a valley in the State of Yu.

...

Feng Tuo was a Foundation Establishment-stage spell warrior from a small Moulan Tribe. Although he was worshiped as an Immortal master amongst his people, he was now merely a common foot soldier in Soaring Heavens City.

He was currently stationed on a fortress on the border of the State of Beiliang. He had to patrol an area of over a hundred of kilometers with a party of Qi Condensation spell warriors in between the fortress and the city to warn of any sudden attacks by the Heavenly South cultivators.

After patrolling for about half a day, it was about time for him to be relieved by another spell warrior. Once he patrolled a few tens more kilometers, he would be able to return.

Feng Tuo pondered for a moment, thinking about the tens of spirit stones he had received in the past two days. With those spirit stones, he felt confident he would be able to breakthrough the bottleneck to mid Foundation Establishment stage. He couldn’t help but feel an impatience to return to cultivating and become stronger before the next battle. If he would be able to acquire a few merits in the upcoming battle, he would surely be rewarded with an appropriate number of spirit stones.

This spell warrior was indulging in fantasy as he slowly flew on his magic tool, guiding a party of Qi Condensation-stage spell warriors.

At that moment, he happened to fly across an ordinary cliff that few ever visited. When he thought to brush through the area, he suddenly saw a flash of azure light emerge from the rock, revealing an azure-robed youth that appeared to be in his early twenties.

The youth glanced at the party of spell warriors with a cold, emotionless expression.

When Feng Tuo clearly saw this youth, he swept his spiritual sense past him and felt his breath turn cold. “Heavenly South cultivator! He’s at least Core Formation stage. I cannot see the depth of his cultivation.”

“Quickly, withdraw! This person isn’t someone we can handle!”

Feng Tuo acted rather keenly and hastily called for his six low grade party members to retreat. He then tossed an exquisite spirit beast pouch through the air.

At that same moment, a streak of red light shot out of the pouch and spun in the air before shooting in the direction of the fortress.

At that moment, a beautiful white-clothed woman appeared in a flash of white light. Red light suddenly appeared near her and she chuckled before spitting out a fragrant pink mist and forming a barrier around the streak of red light.

With a clear cry, the red light faded away to reveal a small red bird floating in the air.

The young woman extended her hand and had the small bird fly into it.

Having seen this, Feng Tuo felt his heart drop. Unable to look after the others, he quickly formed a hand incantation and had his body glow with yellow light and instantly shot several kilometers away by using a life saving technique.

But at that moment, the youth narrowed his eyes and snorted.

The sound was ordinary as it could be, but when Feng Tuo heard this, he felt his ears ring and his mind grow dark as he felt the very earth twirl around him.

The other Qi Condensation-stage cultivators didn’t fare any better either. In the instant the youth infused magic power with his snort, the spell warriors dropped to the ground in succession.

As for Feng Tuo, the young woman arrived by his side in a blur and lifted him into the air by his neck.

Once she landed in front of him, she sweetly smiled at the youth and said, “Master, this person is their leader. He should know a bit more.”

Needless to say, these two were Han Li and Silvermoon who had discovered that the State of Yu had fallen during their time in seclusion. They already had a rough understanding of what had happened. He already had Silvermoon sneak into the nearby area and gather some information.

Just as he was passing through this area, he discovered Feng Tuo’s party patrolling nearby.

Han Li felt his heart stir and decided to capture the party of spell warriors, questioning them about the surrounding affairs and saving him the hassle of treading into any areas that may be guarded by a Divine Sage.

Combined with Silvermoon’s bewitchment techniques, Han Li’s Dreamtear Technique allowed him to easily acquire what he wanted.

Han Li greatly sighed with relief. The three Divine Sages took alternative turns guarding the border, but this span of the border was far from the fortress the Divine Sage was guarding and was being guarded by only a Moulan Sage.

With Han Li’s cultivation, he should have no problem sneaking past him.

Han Li then looked down at the captives with a frown.

In order to acquire the information as quickly as possible, Han Li had used a forceful method to extract information, resulting in a near total annihilation of their minds. Even if they woke up, they would empty husks.

With a light sigh, he turned each of the spell warriors into ash with a fireball. He then took to the skies in an azure streak of light and took Silvermoon in tow.

...

On the border of the State of Beiliang, in a remote building in the newly constructed city of Skyfirst, Han Li’s Senior Martial Brother Lu was currently talking with a few other high grade cultivators of the Heavenly South cultivators. However, he appeared absent-minded as if he were worrying about something.

Since he had already battled against the spell warrior vanguard, he could already return to the Drifting Cloud Sect. However, the sect currently only had two Nascent Soul cultivators. He couldn’t allow the silver-haired old man, his senior martial brother, to lead the Drifting Cloud Sect disciples into battle, so he took the initiative to remain and look after his sect disciples.

Of course, the other reason he was unwilling to depart was because of the recently famous Drifting Cloud Sect’s Elder Han. His whereabouts were still unknown. He was worried that Han Li either met mishap or perhaps found himself incapable of returning.

Nevertheless, Han Li had already proven himself capable of killing other Nascent Soul cultivators and even escaping the pursuit of a Moulan Divine Sage. Elder Lu could hardly believe Han Li was such a capable individual.

After all, others might not know this, but he personally knew that Han Li had just condensed a Nascent Soul several years ago. How was it possible that he had developed such heaven-defying abilities in such a short amount of time? Even a Moulan Divine Sage had appraised him to be a level slightly above that of a mid Nascent Soul cultivator.

Could it be that the Drifting Cloud Sect had truly collected a treasure? Was Junior Martial Brother Han a cultivation genius that appeared once in ten thousand years?

As of current, Lu Luo was sitting in the hall as he pondered about this matter, oblivious to what the others were saying.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare, Lannis

Chapter 749: An Adopted Sister

A white-haired old man sitting across from Lu Luo in the meeting politely asked, “Brother Lu, did you receive any information about Elder Han?” He was an early Nascent Soul cultivator by the name of Xu Changjing, an elder of the Heavenly Dao Alliance’s Water Mirage Sect, and a longtime acquaintance of Lu Luo. He had arrived at Skyfirst City the day before.

After a moment of pause, Lu Luo smiled and answered, “There is no news for the time being. But it seems that Brother Xu is showing quite a bit of interest in Brother Han.”

Xu Changjing chuckled. “It is only natural. From your tone, it seems that others have also asked you the same question. This should come as no surprise. Before I arrived at Skyfirst City, I had already heard many rumors with regard to Fellow Daoist Han. Tch tch! An early Nascent Soul cultivator was actually able to escape a Moulan Divine Sage’s pursuit. This isn’t something that the likes of us are capable of. Furthermore, I’ve also heard that Fellow Daoist Han condensed a Nascent Soul only recently. If that’s true, then it’d be all the more shocking.”

As the old man spoke, the other cultivators nearby glanced at each other and then turned their eyes towards Lu Luo with interest. They were all interested in whatever rumors were related to Han Li, not to mention the hearsay that Han Li was only a newly ascended Nascent Soul cultivator — that was something they had yet to hear anyone confirm.

“That...” Lu Luo hesitated for a moment. Then after he recalled that this was already a fact known to quite a few people, he honestly replied, “Junior Martial Brother Han is truly a newly ascended Nascent Soul cultivator.”

The entire hall began to stir. There were even a few people that gasped in surprise.

Amazed, Xu Changjing spoke with even greater admiration, “Since Elder Han possesses vast abilities at such a young age, surely he has a great chance to reach the late Nascent Soul stage. I must congratulate Brother Lu. The Drifting Cloud Sect will soon experience an era of prosperity, and in the future a great cultivator will be joining the ranks of our Heavenly Dao Alliance!”

The others mostly felt the same and began to speak words of praise. Lu Luo felt somewhat pleased by this, but he uttered humble remarks nonetheless.

A middle-aged man with thick straight eyebrows frowned and said, “However Brother Lu, although Elder Han managed to escape the hands of a Divine Sage, I fear that his injuries must be severe. Why else hasn’t he appeared until now? Brother Lu should probably send some men to find him. If you are lacking hands, I am able to send some of my sect disciples to assist you.” His tone came off as emotionless.

Lu Luo couldn’t help but grow tense upon hearing those words. But he soon calmly replied, “I am not too sure about his circumstances, but I am sure that he is merely recovering from his injuries in concealment.”

As someone who had lived for several hundred years, Lu Luo was able to clearly see the middle-aged man’s envy. He was an elder of the number one sect in the Heavenly Dao Alliance — the Phoenix’s Cry Sect. They were the sect that had the Dao Companion cultivators capable of rivalling the three great cultivators of the Heavenly South. There was no other reason for why they stood at the top of the alliance.

Now that the man heard that a Drifting Cloud Sect would later be able to enter the late Nascent Soul stage, his mood turned for the worse. But from his expression, it appeared as if he were truly concerned, so none could say much about it.

Just as the atmosphere turned awkward, a streak of red light suddenly entered the room, much to the surprise of those present. It circled once around before flying towards Lu Luo. With a faceful of surprise, Lu Luo waved at the red light and it burst into a ball of flames before dropping into his hand. After he immersed his spiritual sense into it, delight appeared on his face.

“Junior Martial Brother Han just entered the city and is currently at my sect’s camp. I must take my leave.” Forcefully suppressing his excitement, he gave a brief explanation before hurriedly departing.

The others were left dumbstruck for a time after seeing him leave in a blur, each of them wearing all sorts of expressions. They didn’t expect that the legendary Elder Han would appear right when they were speaking of him.

Xu Changjing twirled his beard as he wore a pensive expression. As for the middle-aged man, he appeared calm but if one looked closely, one could spot a trace of gloominess on his face.

Although Skyfirst City was a newly constructed city, it was where the various sects of the four superpowers stationed their forces, with each faction taking up a different section of the city. As for the middle portion of the city, it was public grounds where a few famous vagrant cultivators lived.

The Heavenly Dao Alliance were situated in the west section of the city, with the Drifting Cloud Sect occupying an area of about five acres in the southmost portion. Over two hundred Drifting Cloud Sect disciples occupied it, consisting of seven Core Formation cultivators and the rest being at Foundation Establishment stage — making up a majority of the Drifting Cloud Sect’s forces.

Han Li was currently sitting in a wooden chair at the center of the main hall in the Drifting Cloud Sect’s camp. He was holding his chin in his hand while wearing a calm expression. At his side stood two Core Formation cultivators — the Fire Cloud Mountain Lord, a red-clothed old man, and the White Phoenix Mountain Lord, the woman surnamed Song. They were both waiting at his side in a solemn and respectful manner, but complicated expressions occasionally surfaced on their faces.

At that moment, Lu Luo hurriedly rushed into the hall and spotted Han Li. He promptly beamed with joy as he approached and said, “Junior Martial Brother Han, you’ve finally returned. It’s been over half a year since I’ve seen you. You had me worried.”

Han Li stood up and returned the smile. “Sorry to worry you, but my vitality was injured at the time. I had no choice to but to recover for a while. However, I heard news that Soaring Heavens City is no longer under our control. I was quite worried for you as well.”

“It is good that nothing bad has happened.” Lu Luo wore a relieved expression, but he then swept his gaze across the hall and his expression grew sullen. “Huh? Where are the other Martial Nephews? Why haven’t they greeted you?”

The red-clothed old man respectfully answered, “Reporting to Martial Uncle, the others are on rotation today.”

Lu Luo’s expression then relaxed as he said, “Oh! Then it can’t be helped.”

At that moment, Han Li said with a smile, “When I returned, I discovered that I have become quite famous. Could you tell me something of the rumors? There seem to be many of them.” On his return, he was quite surprised to hear many of the rumors about him.

Lu Luo chuckled. “I was just thinking of talking to you about this...” As he was about to continue, he suddenly glanced at the red-clothed old man and the woman standing at the side. “You two may leave. I am going to have a discussion with your Martial Uncle Han alone.”

The two didn’t dare to disobey and hastily withdrew. However, when the woman surnamed Song walked out, she glanced once more at Han Li before departing. Han Li felt somewhat puzzled by this, but he turned a blind eye to it.

Ever since the woman surnamed Song saw him, her expression had been odd as if she had something she wanted to say to him. However, she was always hesitant to do so. While this baffled Han Li, he had no intention of taking the initiative to ask about it.

Seeing that the two Martial Nephews had withdrawn, Lu Luo bitterly smiled and complained, “Junior Martial Brother, you’ve spent quite a bit of effort hiding your vast abilities from Senior Martial Brother Cheng and me. Why didn’t you tell us about them earlier?”

Han Li shook his head and helplessly said, “Senior Martial Brother Lu should know perfectly well that I condensed a Nascent Soul only a few years ago. Wouldn’t I seem boastful speaking of my vast abilities ?”

Lu Luo chuckled and wore a strange smile. “That’s enough. There is no need for Junior Martial Brother to be so modest. Although it was our enemies who evaluated your abilities, their assessment shouldn’t be too far off. However, what truly surprised my Senior Martial Brother and I was how you managed to steal away that female Nascent Soul cultivator from the Masked Moon Sect. You truly have our admiration.”

Han Li’s expression stirred and he worriedly asked, “What? You’ve already seen Wan’er?”

Before Han Li and Nangong Wan departed, he had given her a jade slip providing an ambiguous description of her identity. But when he heard Lu Luo, it seemed he already knew everything.

Seeing the worry on Han Li’s face, Lu Luo beamed and said, “That’s right! Fairy Nangong already explained everything to Senior Martial Brother Cheng. There is no need to worry about anything.”

Puzzled, Han Li frowned and asked,“Senior Martial Brother Lu means to say...?”

Lu Luo blinked before happily saying, “Ah, so Junior Martial Brother still doesn’t know. Several months ago, the Masked Moon Sect suddenly spread information that Fairy Nangong had suffered an inner demon backlash during cultivation and had lost her life, and that her engagement to the Flowing Mind Sect’s Wei Lichen was dissolved. Also, Senior Martial Brother Cheng has recognized Wan’er as his sworn sister, and intends for the two of you to become Dao companions. What does Junior Martial Brother Han think?”

Han Li was dumbfounded by what he heard. “Wan’er has become a sworn sister of Senior Martial Brother Cheng?”

“That’s right. It is as I said. Once we repel the spell warriors, we will openly conduct the Dao Ceremony for you two. Even if any doubts later surface, the matter will already be done. Who would dare to seek trouble from the entire Heavenly Dao Alliance? Even if Wei Wuya were to personally know of this matter, he would only be able to forcibly ignore the matter as we were war allies. Besides, you’ve also made quite the name for yourself so the Flowing Mind Sect and the Masked Moon Sect will likely ignore the matter.”

Having heard this, Han Li grew silent and a complicated expression appeared on his face. Then with a light sigh, he slowly said, “For my matters, I have troubled my two Senior Martial Brothers greatly. I will take it to heart.”

Han Li’s simple words were much to the delight of Lu Luo. He and his Senior Martial Brother had spent no small amount of effort to win over Han Li’s feelings. With the words he had just spoken, it was most likely impossible for Han Li to be roped in by Yellow Maple Valley.

In a display of complete intimacy, Lu Luo continued, “Hehe! We consider Junior Martial Brother Han to be one of our own, not some outsider. Ah yes, Lady Nangong was somewhat worried when she heard you went missing, and felt the need to rush here herself. It was only through immense effort that Senior Martial Brother Cheng was able to hold her back. After all, there are may cultivators from the Flowing Mind Sect and the Masked Moon Sect here, and you’ve yet to officially become Dao companions. It’d be best if Fairy Nangong isn’t recognized at this point. As for Junior Martial Brother Han’s concubine, I’ve had her escorted back to the sect, as it will be dangerous in the upcoming battle.”

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Boring

PR: Vare, Lannis

Chapter 750: Conditions

Han Li felt somewhat apprehensive at the thought of Mu Peiling and Nangong Wan meeting each other. However, he merely uttered a few words of thanks to Lu Luo.

“What does Junior Martial Brother Han plan on doing now? According to the arrangements, you no longer need to participate in any upcoming battles due to your previous service. However a few days ago, the Righteous and Devilish Dao, the Nine Nations Union, and our Heavenly Dao alliance held a meeting with regards to war countermeasures, and Junior Martial brother Han was mentioned. Since you were able to slay the black-robed spell warrior in an instant, your techniques will certainly be capable of restraining the other black-robed spell warriors. As such, they hoped Junior Martial brother would be able to participate in the battle soon to come.”

Lu Luo then revealed a hesitant expression before continuing, “The representative of the Heavenly Dao Alliance also believes that Junior Martial Brother will be a great military asset, and that it would be inexcusable if he doesn’t fight. That is...”

Somewhat to Lu Luo’s surprise, Han Li didn’t reveal any anger. Instead, he coldly smiled and said, “I find it acceptable to continue fighting. If the Heavenly South was to be truly occupied by the Moulan, nothing good would happen for our Drifting Cloud Sect. However, how will the previous agreement be dealt with? Surely it won’t just be waved away with mere words!”

Lu Luo bitterly smiled and said, “Of course not. With the addition of Junior Martial Brother’s merits of slaying the black-robed cultivator and ferreting out the Moulan spy, the alliance promises that it will adhere to any conditions Junior Martial Brother will raise, given that he continues to fight in the war. So long as your conditions are fulfillable, they will attempt to satisfy you as much as they can as compensation.”

Han Li’s expression stirred for a moment, but he remained calm while he said, “They are willing to compensate me? That is easy to say, but I’ll need to have a discussion about these specific conditions with the person in charge.”

Lu Luo smiled and said, “That is also good. I was just about to bring Junior Martial Brother to go see the acting leaders of the Heavenly Dao Alliance. So long as your conditions aren’t excessive, they should be willing to agree.”

Han Li smiled and slowly said, “Be at ease, Senior Martial Brother Lu. I will not attempt to overreach myself and make it difficult for you.”

Seeing that Han Li understood to act within reason, Lu Luo felt relieved and said, “Junior Martial Brother must be joking. There is no need to give consideration for my sake. This is a rare display of generosity from those old folks so you shouldn’t hold back.”

When Han Li heard this, he wore a mysterious smile and said nothing further. Afterwards, Lu Luo promptly led Han Li out of the Drifting Cloud Sect’s encampment and directly headed to the Heavenly Dao Alliance’s official hall.

“Our Heavenly Dao Alliance’s acting leaders are a coalition of ten or so elders from various large sects. They are replaced in ten year intervals. Of course, this doesn’t apply to the three founding sects of the Heavenly Dao Alliance — the Ancient Sword Sect, the Phoenix Cry Sect, and the Sailing Boundaries Study. In truth, these three sects have the most sway within the alliance.

“And amongst them, the Phoenix Cry Sect is a cut above the Ancient Sword Sect and the Sailing Boundaries Study in terms of power. Surely you should know of Fellow Daoists Feng Bing and Long Han of the Phoenix Cry Sect? They are the Dao companions that are capable of contending with a late Nascent Soul cultivator. It is because of these two that we are capable of rivalling the other three factions. However, only Fellow Daoist Long Han has revealed himself as Elder Feng Bing immediately entered into seclusion upon arriving at Skyfirst City. It appears she was at a crucial period of cultivating some secret technique. So long as Junior Martial Brother Han has a proper discussion with the acting leaders of the alliance that are currently in the city, they should be agreeable. I also have to mention that Elder Long Han is currently amongst the three acting leaders in the city.” As Lu Luo walked by Han Li’s side, he gave him an explanation of the inner workings of the Heavenly Dao Alliance.

Some of this information was new to Han Li. As such, he simply nodded as he listened.

The Heavenly Dao Alliance’s official hall was located in the center of the west part of the city. After a calm walk, Han Li and Lu Luo soon arrived at an imposing stone hall surrounded by many towers.

Clearly recognizing Lu Luo, the Foundation Establishment cultivators guarding the hall respectfully saluted him. One of them stepped forward said, “Greetings Senior Lu. Which elders have you come to see? And who might this Senior be?” Their expressions grew hesitant when they saw Han Li’s unfamiliar face.

Lu Luo’s expression remained tranquil as he calmly said, “This is my fellow Sect Elder Han, and I’ve come to see Elder Long and the others.”

“Ah, so it was Senior Han. Please wait a moment. The elders are currently discussing something in the hall. I will report to them immediately.” The cultivator was shocked and glanced at Han Li with astonishment, his expression growing more respectful. It was clear he knew of Han Li’s reputation.

The cultivator soon took out a sound transmission talisman and whispered something into it before tossing it into the air.

A short moment after it shot inside as a streak of red light, three melodious rings sounded out from the hall. When the guards heard this, they immediately bowed and said, “Please enter, Seniors. The elders know that you’ve arrived.”

Lu Luo nodded and boldly walked into the hall as Han Li calmly followed after him.

After passing through several corridors, Lu Luo brought Han Li into a side chamber where six Nascent Soul cultivators were currently seated. When the two walked in, all six of them glanced over. However, most of their gazes were focused on Han Li, each wearing an interested expression.

Each of their cultivations was unordinary, but when Han Li looked at them, his attention was caught by the middle-aged man that was sitting at the center of the room. His clothes were grey, his appearance odd, and his stature wide. His cultivation was also at the peak of mid Nascent stage, a considerable distance above ordinary mid Nascent Soul cultivators; he was just a step away from entering the late Nascent Soul stage.

Han Li’s heart trembled, immediately realizing that this person was the Phoenix Cry Sect’s Long Han. With such profound cultivation, it was no wonder he was able to contend against late Nascent Soul cultivators with his wife. He had originally believed the rumors were over-exaggerated, not the other way around.

As the others remained silent, the middle-aged man beamed and stood up. With a salute, he said, “Brother Lu, this must be your sect’s Elder Han. In the past few days, we’ve heard much of his thunderous repute.”

After giving the middle-aged man an appraising look, Han Li returned the salute and said with a smile, “You must be Long Han. I too have long heard of your famous name.”

Sitting at Long Han’s side, an old man with a pale complexion half-jokingly said, “If we’re speaking of reputation, recently Fellow Daoist Han is much more famous. You’ve earned our Heavenly Dao Alliance much repute.”

“This Fellow Daoist is quite humorous. May I know your name?” Han Li had already taken note of the old man as he was the only other mid Nascent Soul cultivator in the room apart from Long Han. He didn’t dare to slight him.

Before the old man could reply, Lu Luo rushed to introduce him, “Junior Martial Brother Han, this is Brother Kuang of the Sailing Boundaries Study. His Heavenly Earth Arts have repeatedly shaken the continent for several hundreds of years.”

Astonished, Han Li said, “So it turned out to be Brother Kuang. I’ve also held you in much esteem for a long time.”

Han Li’s words weren’t lies. This old man was truly renowned, and in the Heavenly Dao Union he was ranked below only to Long Han and his Dao companion. Of course, the Drifting Cloud Sect Elder Cheng had repeatedly mentioned them in the past, but Han Li didn’t think he would actually meet them.

Afterwards, Lu Luo introduced the other cultivators to Han Li. They weren’t particularly noteworthy apart from the Ancient Sword Sect Elder, an ugly man surnamed Tian, who Han Li particularly took notice of. With the introductions over, they all took a seat.

Long Han smiled and calmly said, “Since Fellow Daoist Han has come to visit the official hall, he should know of our wishes for him to continue fighting in the war. In truth, we did break our previous promise. But with war approaching, your abilities will prove to be of great help for the cultivators of the Heavenly South. We have no other choice. But as compensation, we will provide you with materials, medicine pills and such for your trouble. Fellow Daoist Han, if you are still unwilling, we can further discuss this. So long as it is possible for our alliance, we will not refuse you.”

Long Han deserved his title as the cultivator who ruled the Heavenly Dao Alliance. Before Han Li could even mention why he had come, he had already taken the initiative to apologize to Han Li. He would be put in a bad position if he were to reveal any objections.

However, Han Li wasn’t angry to begin with. Having escaped from the hands of the Moulan Divine Sage, he had proved he should have strength to spare while still preserving his life if a battle took a turn for the worse. Since Han Li had no worries over his survival, he didn’t have much to be unhappy about. Rather, he felt that this was a rare opportunity!

As a result, Han Li pondered for a moment before bluntly speaking, “Since Brother Long said this, I will not object to continuing to fight. After all, I do understand this war is for the survival of the Heavenly South. However, there are some things that I will require from the Heavenly Dao Alliance. Therefore, I will bluntly take advantage of this opportunity.”

When Han Li said this, he appeared calm. He knew that these old eccentrics were extremely sharp, and felt that it would be easier to handle such matters directly.

As expected, his honest words left a positive impression on most of the cultivators in the room. The cultivator surnamed Kuang was particularly happy, and he honestly replied, “Fellow Daoist Han’s quick and direct words are very much to my liking. Please tell us of your conditions. I am quite curious about them!”

Long Han’s expression wavered several times before he silently smiled. As for the others, they all glanced at Han Li, wondering what it was that he wanted.

With an indifferent expression, Han Li calmly said, “It is quite simple. I hope to draw support from the alliance to help me find a certain type of tool refinement material. I won’t hide this from you; this item is extremely important to me. If you are able to gather together these items for me before the grand battle, I will have far more confidence in dealing with those black-robed cultivators.”

“Tool refinement material?” Those in the room glanced at each other, none revealing surprise. They all knew of materials that were certainly precious and difficult to find. Why wouldn’t Han Li want to use this opportunity to seek them out?

Translator's Thoughts

ED: Boring

PR: Lannis, Vare

Chapter 751: A Surprise Meeting

Lu Luo wore a pensive expression upon hearing Han Li and faintly recalled something.

Long Han slowly asked, “What is this material? Please tell us, Fellow Daoist Han.”

“I need Auric Essence to refine my magic treasure. The more, the better. But don't worry, I am willing to trade items of equal value for it. I will not take it for nothing. The alliance only needs to use their resources to help me collect the Auric Essence, or perhaps find its whereabouts.” Having been unable to acquire a large amount of Auric Essence and refine the Aureate Sword Formation, Han Li felt extremely frustrated by the matter. Now that this opportunity had presented itself to him, he wished to use it to its fullest.

“Auric Essence!” Those present all revealed unconcealable shock upon hearing Han Li. This illustrious treasure known as ‘Honed Gold’ was about what they had expected, but they were stunned by hearing such a heaven-defying material, nonetheless.

Old Man Kuang frowned and wore a puzzled expression as he said, “Fellow Daoist Han, the magic treasure you wish to temper requires such a vast amount of Auric Essence? Do you know how much a magic treasure’s power increase after only infusing a small quantity of it? And if you add too much, it won’t have any further effects.”

Han Li calmly said, “Don’t worry. I already know this. I merely wish to ask whether your alliance would be able to gather a certain quantity of this item.”

Long Han shook his head with a sigh and said, “Since Fellow Daoist Han is willing to evenly trade for it, we can certainly be on the lookout for any information to help you gather together the material if we can. However, when such items are acquired, they are normally consumed immediately. From your tone, it seems you require much of it. I fear this will be quite difficult to do. Even if information on Auric Essence exists, their masters may keep quiet on account of wishing to acquire it themselves. It will be difficult to find. That is why only such a small amount was found at the recent trade meet.”

When Han Li heard this, his heart sank. He had already considered the problems, but he had no methods of dealing with them; he was at a complete loss over the matter. If he truly couldn’t acquire a large amount of Auric Essence in the Heavenly South, he may have to travel to the rumored Jin Empire or other great continents in his search.

Since the Jin Empire was about ten times larger than the Heavenly South, perhaps he would be able to find a large amount of Auric Essence there. Not to mention that he still had the bone case he had received in the Umbra Realm that contained the refinement method for the Spirit Subjugation Talisman. If he returned to the Jin Empire, he would naturally want to return it to the Heavenly Talisman Sect.

Han Li felt a wave of gloominess upon hearing this. Seeing Han Li’s hesitant expression, Lu Luo couldn’t help but console him, “Junior Martial Brother Han, let’s change the condition. Auric Essence isn’t something that can be easily sought.”

Han Li unconsciously frowned when he heard him. After a moment of thought, he shook his head and said, “Regardless, Auric Essence is extremely important to me. Even if the chances are slim, I still want the alliance to agree to this matter.” Once this was said, he wore a resolute expression.

Seeing that Han Li had made up his mind, Long Han eventually nodded. “Since Fellow Daoist Han has decided, I will order the alliance’s disciples to spare no effort on this matter. However, please don’t regret this decision if we aren’t able to find even a single piece of Auric Essence.”

Despite how great of a superpower the Heavenly Dao Alliance may be, the most it could do was order its low grade disciples around, and pay particular attention to any news that may surface. Since this matter wouldn’t prove particularly draining, Old Man Kuang and the others raised no objections.

However, they also felt that this alone wasn’t enough compensation. They promptly took out a bag of over a hundred mid-grade spirit stones as well which Han Li took with a smile.

With this resolved, a friendly atmosphere appeared in the hall.

The Heavenly Dao Alliance cultivators then chatted for a time. Eventually, detailed questions about the battle at the Yellow Dragon Mountains were being asked, particularly about the black-robed man and the Moulan Divine Sage.

With no intent to conceal anything, Han Li answered their questions once through. Of course, he brushed past any mention of his techniques and treasures, and Long Han and the others didn’t press him.

However, they were doubtful when they heard that the black-robed men weren’t heretical demon or ghost cultivators. Long Han was particularly surprised to hear that they were merely Devil Dao cultivators.

When a half day had passed, Han Li and Lu Luo eventually took their leave.

Shortly after they departed, a voice transmission talisman suddenly shot towards Lu Luo’s hand.

Lu Luo gave Han Li a helpless smile and said, “I have urgent business to attend to so I’m afraid I can’t continue to keep you company. Junior Martial Brother Han should take a stroll around the city. Let us have a proper chat when night comes.”

Han Li kindly smiled in response, “Senior Martial Brother Lu, please don’t mind me. I also wished to take a look around the city alone!”

Feeling relieved, Lu Luo saluted Han Li and hastily flew off in a streak of light. The sudden matter seemed truly important.

As Han Li watched Lu Luo depart, he shook his head, but after some thought he smiled instead. He pondered for a moment as he looked at the sky before heading towards the city’s central district. But after taking a few steps, he stopped and slowly turned around to face Mountain Lord Song, who stood at the entrance of a nearby alley. She stood there with bit lips and a hesitant expression.

Han Li blinked and waved at the woman. With a moment more of hesitation, she walked over with lithe steps.

The beautiful woman respectfully shouted, “Junior pays her respects to Martial Uncle Han!”

“How long have you been waiting here?” Han Li looked at the woman’s face with his hands behind his back.

The woman lowered her head and softly replied, “It has been about an hour already.”

Han Li glanced around and calmly said, “It seems you have something you wish to say to me. However, this isn’t a good place to talk. Follow me.” Without waiting for her reply, he began walking. The woman’s expression wavered for a moment before she closely followed after him.

Once Han Li brought her to a secluded place, he turned around and said, “What is it that you wish to say?”

The woman kept silent for a moment before taking a jade slip from her robes and handing it over to Han Li, “Someone had this Martial Niece pass on a letter to Martial Uncle. They wish to see you.”

“A letter?” Han Li wore a face of surprise and swept his spiritual sense past the jade slip. However, he didn’t immediately sink his spiritual sense into it. He stared at the woman and asked, “Who gave this to you? You must know.”

With the jade slip no longer in her hands, she managed to regain her calm. “It is a good friend of mine. She says that she knows you and wishes to pass something on to you.”

“She knows me?” Han Li narrowed his eyes and his expression stirred. After pondering with a tilted head, he eventually pressed the jade slip against his head and looked into it. A short moment later, he was wearing an odd expression on his face as he said, “Where is she? Bring me to her.”

The woman blinked and astonishedly said, “Martial Uncle truly recognizes my friend!”

Han Li casually said, “That’s right. There is some friendship between us. I didn’t think that Martial Niece Song would know her.”

Spirits roused, she sweetly smiled and said, “I met her in only the last two years. I originally believed it to be a joke that she knew you and didn’t think that it would be true. I’ve arranged an empty place for her outside of the city. I’ll bring you to her right away.”

Afterwards, Han Li and the woman walked towards the city gate together. After they left Skyfirst City, the woman took to the skies and led Han Li south. They traveled tens of kilometers before arriving at a small, uninhabited valley.

The entrance of the valley was enveloped in a pure white mist, concealing its interior from sight. The woman surnamed Song silently waved her hand as she grabbed onto a command talisman. A streak of red light then shot into the mist and caused it to roil away and reveal a narrow green path.

The woman respectfully stood to the side and said, “Martial Uncle, please go first!”

With Han Li’s current spiritual sense, he clearly saw everything within the valley. He wore a slight smile and walked down the path.

The exquisite valley wasn’t large. It was a mere three hundred meters in area with nothing aside from several small buildings at its center, making it appear as a temporary residence. Yet, it was completely clean near the buildings with not a single weed to be found.

However, someone in the room was alarmed by the formation being broken. In a blur, a gorgeous, yellow-robed woman emerged from the building.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare, Lannis

ED: Boring

Chapter 752: Spirit Kindle Fruit and Nature Origin Pill

As the woman appeared before Han Li, her name appeared in his mind. She was Mei Ning, who had traveled with him from the Umbra Realm to the Heavenly South. Her beauty had become even more captivating over the few years since he had last seen her.

When Mei Ning spotted Han Li, a trace of resentment appeared on her face, but it was soon replaced with solemn respect. As Han LI was now a Nascent Soul cultivator, she couldn’t speak as freely as she once could. “This Junior was only able to reach her current cultivation because of the pills that Senior gave me in the past. Thank you for your kindness.”

At that moment, Cultivator Song walked up from behind Han Li and spoke in a familiar manner, “Little Sister Mei, is Fellow Daoist Violet Spirit inside?” This caused Han Li to look at her with slight surprise.

Not daring to neglect the two, Mei Ning wore an apologetic expression and said, “Senior Song! Elder Sister Violet Spirit is currently cultivating inside her room, but her cycle should be done soon. How about you two wait in my room for now?”

Han Li raised no objections. With his spiritual sense, he was able to see from Violet Spirit’s spiritual Qi fluctuations that she was on the verge of finishing a cultivation cycle. The two then entered one of the stone buildings under Mei Ning’s modest invitation and they both took a seat. Afterwards, Mei Ning quickly steeped a cup of tea for each of them.

Han Li took a sip of the tea and calmly asked, “Lady Mei, where have you and Violet Spirit been cultivating these past few years? Could it be that the two of you haven’t entered a sect yet?”

Standing at Han Li’s side, Mei Ning lowered her head and replied, “Big Sister Violet Spirit and I had a discussion about this. We will first observe the great sects of the Heavenly South and consolidate our cultivation before deciding on a sect. As such, we’ve been travelling over the last few years. After all, the circumstances in the Heavenly South are quite a bit different from our original home.”

Seeing that Mei Ning didn’t conceal that she was a foreign cultivator, Han Li came to the realization that his Martial Niece Song most likely knew that they came from the Scattered Star Seas. It seems her relationship with Violet Spirit was quite close.

But upon seeing Mei Ning’s gentle and sincere behavior, Han Li stroked his nose and felt it awkward to continue his questions. He simply turned to look at Cultivator Song at the side and smiled. “You didn’t bring me here on behalf of Violet Spirit just so that we could reminisce about old times, right? Otherwise, there should be no need to be so secretive and hesitant about delivering the letter.”

“Martial Uncle, I...” Cultivator Song’s complexion grew slightly red and she swallowed.

Mei Ning revealed a trace of embarrassment. Just as she thought to say something, a woman suddenly laughed from outside the room. “Brother Han, there is no need to make it so difficult for these two little sisters. In truth, it was mostly my idea to invite you here.” Just after she finished speaking, Fairy Violet Spirit walked in. Her appearance was more captivating and her eyes were more luminous than ever before.

“In truth, I should actually be calling Brother Han as Senior now. However, I feel that Brother Han is a more appropriate title as your age isn’t necessarily greater than mine. Brother Han certainly won’t mind.” Violet Spirit spoke with a smile. Having met her in Heavenvoid Hall and the Umbra Realm as well as the days he spent with her in the Endless Seas, Han Li felt her to be a close friend.

Han Li shot the woman an appraising glance. Despite his current cultivation at Nascent Soul stage, he felt his spirit shake upon seeing Violet Spirit’s true appearance. She was no doubt a country shattering beauty from legends.

Solely with regards to beauty, even his beloved was an entire level lower. Of course, Nangong Wan’s calm temperament and charm belonged to a completely different category. The two couldn’t be compared.

“It makes no difference to me. However, if Lady Violet Spirit were to walk out of this valley with her true appearance, she will bring about chaos in the Heavenly South. If any of those old eccentrics were to see you, I fear they would attempt to take you by force.” It was only in the presence of this old friend that Han Li was able to say a seldom heard joke.

Violet Spirit smiled and gave Han Li a glance before calling out towards Cultivator Song, “I’ve troubled you quite a bit Big Sister Song. Mei Ning and I found it difficult to travel into Skyfirst City.”

“It’s nothing! Since I am also involved in this matter, exerting a bit of effort is only natural.” The woman still appeared somewhat astonished. Although she knew Violet Spirit and Han Li were truly old friends, she was quite astonished to see them acting so casually with one another, and it greatly bolstered her confidence in the matter to come.

At that moment, Violet Spirit sweetly smiled at Han Li and casually said, “Every time I see Brother Han, it seems his cultivation has vastly increased. This unknown cultivation art of yours is truly astonishing and now, Brother Han’s resounding fame has left us at a loss for words. Rumors have spread everywhere that Brother Han’s strength is greater than even a mid Nascent Soul stage cultivator. Is this matter true?” Once that was said, Violet Spirit mysteriously smiled at Han Li, her eyes faintly revealing a trace of anticipation.

Han Li’s heart stirred, and he pondered for a moment. Rather than offering a direct response, he calmly asked, “Lady Violet Spirit, why is the first thing you ask me about is my strength? Isn’t that too impatient? Can you tell me why you sought me out first? I hope to understand this before we move onto other matters.”

When she heard Han Li, she blinked and wore an embarrassed expression. “You’re right, I was impatient. However, it should come as no surprise. This matter is truly important. If you have the abilities of a mid Nascent Soul stage cultivator or greater, our plan will have a chance to succeed.”

Han Li expression flickered and his smiled disappeared. He calmly asked, “What is so important? If you need my help, you may as well ask me clearly.”

Violet Spirit’s expression grew solemn. “It seems there is no need for me to say. Brother Han has already guessed. We truly sought Fellow Daoist Han for help. But before this, I want to ask you a question. Not longer before, did Fellow Daoist Han accompany a few Nascent Soul eccentrics to the Moulan Plains and acquire Master Cang Kun’s remains?”

With slight surprise, Han Li asked, “How do you know about that? This matter should only be known to a few people.”

Mei Ning sweetly smiled and said, “It was something we found out from a Ghost Spirit Sect cultivator. They are of direct lineage with a Ghost Spirit Sect Elder. He accidentally saw Big Sister Violet Spirit’s true appearance and became entirely captivated her. There is nothing he won’t tell her.”

“Stupid girl, what nonsense are you saying?” Violet Spirit snorted and her cheeks blushed. It seemed the two had grown quite close over the years.

Han Li nodded and suspicion appeared on his face. “If the Ghost Spirit Sect is involved, this matter can’t be ordinary.”

Violet Spirit’s bright eyes flickered and she said with a sweet voice, “I didn’t expect Brother to still be so cautious after entering the Nascent Soul stage.”

“I’ve only recently entered Nascent Soul stage. If I don’t want to die, I must be careful. Being careful is only natural. However, why does it matter that I headed to the Moulan Plains in search of treasures? Could it be that you acquired another connected secret from the Ghost Spirit Sect?” Han Li asked curiously.

Seeing that Han Li was truly familiar with Violet Spirit, Cultivator Song felt more at ease and interjected herself, “Martial Uncle is truly insightful. This matter involves a treasure inside Devilfall Valley. The Ghost Spirit Sect disciple unintentionally revealed this as we were talking about it.”

After a moment of surprise, Han Li wore an odd expression and said, “Devilfall Valley? I recall that only Master Cang Kun was able to leave there alive. How does the Ghost Spirit Sect know of a treasure inside it? Were you not deceived?”

Violet Spirit’s eyes shined and she said, “That isn’t the case. At the time, we were curious and joined hands to perform a charming technique on the man. Not only did we manage to acquire the treasure’s name, but we also found out the treasure’s approximate location. As for why the Ghost Spirit Sect knows of this matter, the person in question also didn’t know. However, this matter is most likely true.”

Han Li frowned. “If this matter is true, then this must be an unordinary ancient treasure. What is this treasure that you covet so greatly?”

The three woman quickly exchanged a glance. Cultivator Song then solemnly asked, “Has Martial Uncle Han ever heard of the Spirit Kindle Fruit?”

Han Li’s calm expression was now replaced with astonishment. “What? The Spirit Kindle Fruit? If I remember correctly, the fruit itself should be extinct. However, Devilfall Valley has been sealed since times of antiquity. Perhaps one is truly inside.”

“It seems Brother Han knows about the spirit fruit then he should also know of the Nature Origin Pill. In legend, so long as one uses this pill, they will be able to break through any bottleneck short of the Deity Transformation stage. It is also said that cultivators who take this pill had their spiritual senses undergo a transformation and ascend to an inconceivable level. Although these rumors are unclear to the point that recorded results differ between each individual, the legend of cultivators breaking through a bottleneck was always consistent. Despite the many records throughout the ages, they all mentioned the great name of this spirit pill. It is a pity that the main ingredient to refine it, the Spirit Kindle Fruit, was extremely difficult to find even in the age of antiquity. Although the pill formula was preserved, it has remained unused for eras.”

Despite their former knowledge of this matter, Cultivator Song and Mei Ning couldn’t help but reveal excitement upon hearing it once more. Mei Ning in particular was excited about the Nature Origin pill as it would vastly increase her chances of reaching the Core Formation stage.

But at that moment, Han Li’s excitement slowly faded as he pondered about the matter.

After some careful consideration, Han Li calmly replied, “If the spirit fruit is in Devilfall Valley, that explains why the Ghost Spirit Sect went through such lengths to hire those treasure seeking Nascent Soul cultivators and tried to kill Marquis Nanlong for Master Cang Kun’s treasure. Still, there are a few things I don’t understand that I need you to explain. I will not be braving this danger otherwise, despite how tempting the fruit may be.”

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Vare, Lannis

ED: Boring

Chapter 772: Battle at the Border (6)

Han Li waved at the huge mountain and it shrunk back to several inches in size in a flash of light before flying back into his sleeve. And in a display of tenacity, the blood barrier shortly returned to its original shape.

He turned around and extended his finger. With a crackle, a walnut-sized ball of faint blue flames appeared on his fingertip. Han Li then shouted, “Go!”, sending the fireball to strike the distant wall.

With a light bang, the blue flames ruptured and formed a blue icy layer that covered the inner layer of the barrier, turning its interior into a world of a severe winter. It had turned so cold that one’s breath would turn to frost as soon as they breathed out.

Sparkling blue covering the inner layer of the blood barrier, Han Li pressed his hand against it in a blur, striking at the dense layer of ice with azure sword Qi. As a result, the ice around his hand shattered into translucent fragments of ice drifting through the air.

Han Li’s expression grew sullen. The area where he struck at the ice was unscathed and still as crimson as blood. The barrier wasn’t truly frozen though, its surface was merely covered in a layer of frost. Blood Qi still roiled at the center of it.

Han Li pondered for a moment before sweeping his hand, covering it in purple devilflames. He pressed it directly against the blood barrier. The difference in strength between the Celestial Ice Flames and the Purple Apex Flames were clear to see. As soon as the purple flames touched the wall, the blood mist protruding from the barrier instantly solidified and began to glow with a brilliant purple light.

With a smile on his face, he carefully controlled the Purple Apex Flames and concentrated their power on a small portion of the barrier. He then opened his mouth and spat out a bolt of golden lightning, thunder ringing from his mouth.

Golden light flashed as the lightning struck the barrier, leaving behind fine cracks. But soon, the barrier violently shook and instantly mended itself.

Han Li was dumbstruck. The blood barrier greatly resembled Ghost Dao Techniques; it was even capable of restoring itself. It was no wonder why the Moulan was so confident in this restriction, even the Purple Apex Flames was incapable of damaging it. Truly, the restriction was more than capable of trapping Nascent Soul cultivators.

Although he felt somewhat alarmed, Han Li quickly slapped his storage pouch and took out an azure thumb-sized pearl into his hand. This was one of his newly refined lightning beads. Ever since he had refined it, he hadn’t had a chance to test it yet.

Having no other way of sensing how the battle was faring on the outside apart from the rolls of thunder, Han Li believed that there should be many obstructions waiting for him as the battle was still in its beginning phase. Additionally, if he were too slow in escaping the barrier, the cultivator army would have already been defeated, leaving him surrounded by the Moulan forces. No matter how exceptional he may be, he wouldn’t be able to escape from that.

With that in mind, the lightning bead began to glow as he willed the lightning bead to spin in his hand before shooting towards the blood barrier.

With a muffled roar of thunder, a head-sized ball of gold-azure light struck the ceiling of the barrier, violently shaking the entire dome as a result. A trace of astonishment appeared from Han Li’s expression. The might of these lightning beads were far beyond what he had expected.

Just as the thought surface in his mind, his expression made a sudden chance and azure light brightly shined from his body as he shot through the air. The strike from the lightning bead was able of easily ripping open a small hole in the blood barrier, causing Han Li to fly towards it without another thought.

The hole rapidly shrunk, but Han Li was able to escape just in time. He was overjoyed. The lightning bead created from purple flames and azure lantern flames could easily breakthrough such a durable barrier, much to his surprise. Had the lightning bead not worked, his only other options was to use the Gold Devouring Beetles or the Blood Devil Sword.

Although there was nothing the Gold Devouring Beetles couldn’t consume, devouring the barrier would’ve taken time. As for the Blood Devil Sword, the consequences of its use wasn’t something that Han Li could accept lightly.

The Nameless Lightning Bead’s ability to deal with the blood barrier came as a pleasant surprise. It seemed the Purple Apex Flames was incapable of breaking the restriction because it was inherently an ice-attribute flame, unlike the lantern flames which were a true fire-attribute flame.

But when Han Li flew out of the barrier, he heard many astonished cries of alarm before he could clearly see what was going on. Followed by that, there were various explosions, rumbles, and furious roars from all around him.

Han Li hastily looked at the scene in astonishment. At that moment, he was surrounded by ten spell warriors. Fortunately, he was able to quickly see that their cultivations wasn’t very high.

There were two Core Formation spell warriors with the rest of them being at Foundation Establishment stage. They were all holding onto formation flags and were about to prepare a spirit technique attack. But when Han Li emerged from the blood barrier, he appeared right in front of them.

Han Li ignored them and examined the surroundings instead. He felt his breath turn cold. The area surrounding him, be it sky or ground, were all densely filled with spiritual light and treasure aura, not to mention a rapid succession of explosions far and near.

The cultivators and spell warriors from both sides were engaged in a melee, with groups of varying numbers engaging one another. At that moment, Han Li wasn’t able to see which side was winning, and he turned his gaze to coldly examine the nearby spell warriors.

When these spell warriors saw Han Li emerge from the blood barrier, they were dumbstruck.

“Not good! He’s a Nascent Soul cultivator! Call for the great sages!” One of the Core Formation cultivators was the first to recover. After he shouted, he slapped the back of his head and spat a green saber towards Han Li before flying away in a streak of green light. When the others spell warriors heard him, they also recovered from their shock.

The other Core Formation cultivator released a fire-red trident and raised his hand, sending a voice transmission talisman through the sky. As for the Foundation Establishment-stage spell warriors, they all raised the formation flags in their hands and began to utter an incantation. Over ten streaks of light shot out from the tips of the flags and formed a sea of flames burning around Han Li.

“Yi!” Han Li felt greatly surprised that the spell warriors actually took the initiative to tie him down rather than flee. However, a trace of killing intent appeared on his face and azure light twinkled to release several tens of azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Sword from his sleeve. He struck them with a spell seal in a casual wave of his hand and had each of these flying swords lightly tremble before immediately splitting into several copies of themselves, instantly surrounding Han Li in a dense screen of swordlight. The sword QI surrounding him instantly soared with astonishing pressure.

When the two Core Formation cultivators saw this, they were greatly alarmed, but they ordered their magic treasures to continue the attack regardless.

Han Li coldly smiled and casually flicked two of his fingers, sending several streaks of swordlight to block the incoming saber and trident. In a bright flash of azure light, the two magic treasures were utterly suppressed by the swordlight and endlessly wailed as their spiritual light shrink. As for the sea of flame that roiled around him, the swordlights surrounding his body dispelled the flames whenever they grew near.

Since he didn’t have the time to further place with these spell warriors, Han Li had no intention of holding back. With a single command, the hundred streaks of swordlight brightly shined and simultaneously launched towards each of the spell warriors nearby.

Although the Foundation Establishment spell warriors raised the formation flags in attempt to block the attack, they were completely shredded without resistance. When the Core Formation spell warriors saw the swordlight fly towards them, blood drained from their faces. Their possessed neither the courage nor recklessness to receive such a powerful attack, and hastily fled in streaks of light.

When Han Li saw this, a cold glint appeared in his eyes. He formed an incantation gesture with his hands and two swordlights masses of swordlights chased after them. With a series of rings, they bonded together and increased in speed.

Just as the two Moulan spell warriors flew fifty meters away, swordlight had already enveloped them. Despite their greatest efforts to protect themselves and the various techniques they released, the azure light instantly shattered everything that protected them. Without even scream, the swordlight split their bodies into countless pieces, shattering apart even their primal souls.

As Han Li killed them with ease, a violent roar came from up above him. A blinding yellow light soon followed, pouncing towards him at great speed. With a change of expression, Han Li instantly unfolded the Thunderstorm Wings and disappeared in a flash of silver light.

When the silhouette in the yellow light saw this, he couldn’t help but slow down and come to a stop, revealing a beardless old man who wore yellow clothes. Although he wore an expression of fury, bewilderment also appeared on his face.

He was a Moulan sage who had been battling against a Heavenly South Nascent Soul cultivator when he suddenly received a voice transmission from a clan member. He immediately disengaged from the fight and quickly flew towards the sender only to see two of his relatives exterminated by azure swordlight. One of them had even been his succeeding disciple, his own nephew.

However, Han Li had quickly disappeared from sight. Alarmed by the sight, he quickly recalled a particularly fearsome Heavenly South cultivator and he restrained his hatred only to sweep his spiritual sense around him.

In the following moment, silver light flashed behind him and Han Li came into existence once more.

“Die!” The old man quickly turned around as soon as he sensed him and raised his hand, releasing a cubic magic treasure towards Han Li. As it flew, it brilliantly glowed in yellow light, instantly turning into a huge brick that was over forty meters large — carrying a fearful momentum as it screamed through the air.

Translator's Thoughts

PR: Lannis

Chapter 789: Ghost Sifting Banner

Han Li’s heart stirred at the sight of these pearls. They appeared to be the same as his own lightning beads. As the thought appeared in his head, he willed the Aureate Sword Formation to continue onward.

The sword threads were one of the abilities of the Aureate Formation, similar to the sword threads used by sword cultivators, but the formation was capable of summoning over a hundred astonishing threads of sword Qi. With the sword formation’s might coupled with the Auric Essence infused swords, these sword threads were far more formidable than those from common sword cultivators. Ordinary treasures were similarly incapable of blocking the swords’ incisive strikes.

As for items like the Lightning Bead, Han Li had no fear of them. So long as the true thirty-six swords were unharmed, the sword formation would easily reform itself even if the sword threads were scattered. The Aureate Sword Formation couldn’t be set back by any attacks.

Just as Han Li thought this, golden light flashed as the pearls contacted the sword formation, splitting the pearls into several pieces.

Surprisingly, the pearls weren’t explosives. Instead, they released a dense black-red mist of blood. The blood mist immediately dispersed and leaked through the air, spreading a pungent, sickly sweet scent.

The bead was known as a Blood Mine and it was said that they were refined from the most putrid materials found in the world. So long as one didn’t have particular Devil Dao treasures, the treasure’s spiritual nature and power would greatly decrease upon entering the blood mist. Even if a powerful magic treasure with a highly spiritual nature were to enter it, they would take days of purification with Nascent flames in order to recover from the damage.

Of course, these Blood Mines were incredibly rare. Not only were the materials used to refine them seldom seen, but the odds of a successful refinement were minuscule. These tensome beads were something the black-robed youth had spent over a hundred years accumulating.

This youth was an elder from one of the Ten Great Devil Sects of the Jin Empire. With his vast experience, he immediately thought to use the Blood Mines to corrupt the swords comprising Han Li’s sword formation.

A sword formation needed great coordination in order to display its might. If a few of the swords fell out of balance, the sword formation would collapse. Using Blood Mines was one of the most common methods used by Jin Empire devil cultivators to combat sword formations. And since the Blood Mines were incredibly rare items, the youth normally wouldn’t use them in solo battles. He would only deploy them in large-scale conflicts as sword formations usually couldn’t be activated by lone cultivators.

Although Han Li didn’t know what this blood mist was, he immediately sensed something strange about it. Just as he pondered about it, faint rolls of thunder could be heard coming from within it as flashes of golden light appeared from the blood mist, followed by arcs of golden lightning. When the golden lightning struck the blood mist, the mist scattered in an explosion. In the blink of an eye, the Divine Devilbane Lightning and the tensome pockets of blood mist had erupted in mutual destruction.

Han Li was astonished by the sight, as this was the first time he had ever seen the Divine Devilbane Lightning take action on its own. It had shot out of his flying swords without any orders! It appeared that the wicked nature of the blood mist had counteracted the Divine Devilbane Lightning, a truly astonishing discover indeed.

Han Li didn't know that the Blood Mines were specialized in dealing with the treasures of the Righteous Dao. When met by the Divine Devilbane Lightning, which specialized in subduing Devil Dao techniques, the two just so happened to counteract one another. However, the quantity of the lightning contained in the thirty-six swords was vastly greater than the amount of blood mist. As a result, the blood mist was cleanly eliminated in the blink of an eye.

The black-robed man’s complexion paled and he shouted with fright, “Divine Devilbane Lightning! The flying swords were treasures crafted from Golden Lightning Bamboo. Impossible! How did you acquire so much of it?”

“I’ll answer that after I send you to the underworld!” Han Li took a deep breath and ordered the sword formation to continue since the blood mist had temporarily stopped the golden threads. The swords threads then continued to closed in on the black-robed youth without a sound.

Although the Aureate Sword Formation was immensely powerful, it was difficult for Han Li to sustain with his current cultivation. It was a massive drain on his magic power and he wasn’t able to increase the speed at which the sword formation moved after activation. Otherwise, he would’ve had the sword threads close in on the black-robed youth in the blink of an eye and put an immediate end to him, preventing him from figuring out a way to resist.

Han Li reckoned that the optimal time to cultivate the Aureate Sword Formation would be during mid-Nascent Soul stage. If he wasn’t only using half of his flying swords, he simply wouldn’t be able to activate the sword formation due to his level of cultivation, despite how his magic power exceeded that of ordinary early Nascent Soul cultivators.

The black-robed youth surrounded himself in a layer of black Qi and snorted. With an imposing tone, he said, “You truly believe a trifling sword formation can truly trap me? Your sword formation may be incisive, but can it cut my sect’s protective treasure?” He glanced at the golden threads that were less than thirty meters away and silently raised his hand before striking at his chest.

Black blood sprayed out of his mouth, as a green, inch-long banner appeared from within the blood.

As soon as the banner appeared, it flickered with green light and completely absorbed the black blood that surrounded it, turning it dark green.

The black-robed youth gloomily waved at the banner and it shot into his hands as a streak of black light. The green banner brightly glowed and immediately grew until it was a meter tall. The banner now glistened with green light as if it was densely covered in Yin clouds, causing its surface to be concealed. However, one of the corners of the banner seemed to be missing as if it were damaged.

Han Li’s pupils shrank at the sight of the banner. “The Ghost Sifting Banner!”

Originally, the Yin Sifting Sect Master had wanted to use their sect protecting treasure to fight Devil Concord. While it hadn’t actually been used in battle, its name had stuck in Han Li’s mind. Now that the black-robed youth took out the small banner, Han Li managed to guess what it was.

The black-robed youth coldly smiled after hearing that Han Li recognized it. He said with absolute confidence, “Aren’t you clever? This is one of the main banners of the twenty Ghost Sifting Banners. I’ll have you experience its might.”

Soon after, the youth firmly grasped onto the banner and waved it towards one of the golden threads. With a gust, a dark-green Yin cloud flew out from the banner and surged, enveloping the body of the black-robed youth.

The bone-chilling Yin cloud expanded and the sky was suddenly turned pitch-black, as the cloud blotted out the sun from the sky. This incredible darkness had somehow spread from the green ghost mist with ghastly wails and screams echoing all around.

With a mere shake of the banner, the entire world around them had changed. It was no wonder why he was so confident in this treasure. Despite Han Li’s confidence in the Aureate Sword Formation, even he felt dumbfounded at the current situation.

At that moment, the sound of tearing wind suddenly arrived from the flag, and several black threads shot out from the mist surrounding the youth, directly attacking Han Li.

Golden light flashed as the sword formation’s restrictions were activated. Countless golden threads chopped the black threads into pieces. However, the threads immediately turned into green mist and returned back to the main body.

Before Han Li could react, the black-robed youth shouted in alarm from within the green mist. The Yin ghost threads were said to be incredibly durable, but they were easily struck down in a single blow, much to his surprise. After a moment of thought, he decided to unleash the full power of the ghost banner.

He suddenly tossed the green banner from the mist and it bore into the earth a meter in front of him.

Soon, he began to utter a cryptic incantation and a series of Yin winds swept up the dense fog around him, sweeping towards the banner at its center. In the blink of an eye, the banner grew to six meters in height and the mist that had been covering it scattered, revealing its true form. Its appearance vastly shocked Han Li.

Han Li fiercely shouted, “How many souls did you use to refine that banner!? How many people have you killed!?”

The green banner’s surface was densely filled by innumerable faces. They all continuously squirmed from the flag as if they were alive and wore expressions of agony.

The youth’s sinister voice spoke from within the fog, “How many? Who knows? It should be around a hundred thousand or so. There are also at least several hundred cultivator souls in there as they are required to refine a single main banner.”

Han Li grew silent and he coldly stared a the green mist. A moment later, he said, “You are all damned.”

The youth sneered and said, “Damned? There are many that have said this to me before, but here I am, alive and well. And all the people who said this to me had their souls seized by the banner, becoming a part of it. You will be no exception.” He then struck the banner with a red spell seal.

Green light magnificently flashed, summoning a meter-wide hole in the flag. Black Qi flowed out of it, releasing a series of Yin winds and piercing whistles. Soon, huge skulls flew out in a line from the hole, their eyes glowing with ghastly green flames and trailing green smoke.

The biggest of the skull had huge bull horns emerging from it, but the rest of it features appeared entirely human.

Han Li was alarmed. Could it be that the skulls were from metamorphosis stage demon beasts? But for the time being, he placed the thought at the back of his head.

Once the first wave of skulls emerged from the flag, various flaming ghost skulls followed. In the blink of an eye, over a hundred ghost skulls surrounded the black-robed youth.

Pointing at Han Li from within the mist, the youth shouted, “Go!”